<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Doxology on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/doxology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Doxology on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:35:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/doxology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Word Made Flesh</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-word-made-flesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-word-made-flesh/</guid>
      <description>We confess the mystery and wonder of God made flesh and rejoice in our great salvation through Jesus Christ our Lord. With the Father and the Holy Spirit, the Son created all things, sustains all things, and makes all things new. Truly God, He became truly man, two natures in one person. He was born of the Virgin Mary and lived among us. Crucified, dead, and buried, He rose on the third day, ascended to heaven, and will come again in glory and judgment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: What Else Can I Say? Psalm 16:11</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-what-else-can-i-say-psalm-1611/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 20:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-what-else-can-i-say-psalm-1611/</guid>
      <description>The God who alone is awesome.
This is Love, Election, Calling, Atonement, Justification, Propitiation, Expiation, Adoption, Sanctification, and Glorification rolled into one.
Even typing these words, meagerly and fumblingly, is drawing away from the sheer beauty, breath snatching, eye-rubbing gorgeousness, ever-swelling joy, tear-pouring grace and heart-bursting love that is this one verse.
Psalm 16:11
**You make known to me the path of life;
in your presence there is fullness of joy;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: What Shall I Pray? 1 Timothy 1:12-17</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/influences-what-shall-i-pray-1-timothy-112-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/influences-what-shall-i-pray-1-timothy-112-17/</guid>
      <description>So in all of this, what shall I pray?
What can I say?
I pray to worship You.
I pray to praise Your holy name forever.
I pray to sing to You.
I pray because I want You.
I pray because I need You near.
I pray because I have no life without You.
I pray because You are my Lord and God.
I pray because You are my Father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 1</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-1/</guid>
      <description>O Lord,  Like a child, I have fallen and all of my strength has left me.
As my precious Father, put me back up on my feet and hold my hands so I can learn to run to you.
Give me your strength and might.
Give me your word and your promises.
Oh, how you give to me. You give me your love and you see to it that I make it back to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/here-is-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/here-is-love/</guid>
      <description>Here is love, vast as the ocean, Lovingkindness as the flood, When the Prince of Life, our Ransom, Shed for us His precious blood. Who His love will not remember? Who can cease to sing His praise? He can never be forgotten, Throughout Heav’n’s eternal days. On the mount of crucifixion, Fountains opened deep and wide; Through the floodgates of God’s mercy Flowed a vast and gracious tide. Grace and love, like mighty rivers, Poured incessant from above, And Heav’n’s peace and perfect justice Kissed a guilty world in love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blessed Assurance</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/blessed-assurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/blessed-assurance/</guid>
      <description>Blessed assurance, Jesus is mine! O what a foretaste of glory divine! Heir of salvation, purchase of God, Born of His Spirit, washed in His blood. Perfect submission, perfect delight, Visions of rapture now burst on my sight; Angels descending bring from above Echoes of mercy, whispers of love. Perfect submission, all is at rest I in my Savior am happy and blest, Watching and waiting, looking above, Filled with His goodness, lost in His love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doxology</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/doxology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/doxology/</guid>
      <description>Awake, my soul, and with the sun Thy daily stage of duty run; Shake off dull sloth, and joyful rise, To pay thy morning sacrifice. Thy precious time misspent, redeem, Each present day thy last esteem, Improve thy talent with due care; For the great day thyself prepare. By influence of the Light divine Let thy own light to others shine. Reflect all Heaven’s propitious ways In ardent love, and cheerful praise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great is Thy Faithfulness</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/great-is-thy-faithfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/great-is-thy-faithfulness/</guid>
      <description>Great is Thy faithfulness, O God my Father; There is no shadow of turning with Thee; Thou changest not, Thy compassions, they fail not; As Thou hast been, Thou forever will be. Summer and winter and springtime and harvest, Sun, moon and stars in their courses above Join with all nature in manifold witness To Thy great faithfulness, mercy and love. Pardon for sin and a peace that endureth Thine own dear presence to cheer and to guide; Strength for today and bright hope for tomorrow, Blessings all mine, with ten thousand beside!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His Eye Is On The Sparrow</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/his-eye-is-on-the-sparrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/his-eye-is-on-the-sparrow/</guid>
      <description>Why should I feel discouraged, why should the shadows come, Why should my heart be lonely, and long for heaven and home, When Jesus is my portion? My constant friend is He: His eye is on the sparrow, and I know He watches me; His eye is on the sparrow, and I know He watches me. “Let not your heart be troubled,” His tender word I hear, And resting on His goodness, I lose my doubts and fears; Though by the path He leadeth, but one step I may see; His eye is on the sparrow, and I know He watches me; His eye is on the sparrow, and I know He watches me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Great Thou Art</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/how-great-thou-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/how-great-thou-art/</guid>
      <description>O Lord my God, When I in awesome wonder, Consider all the worlds Thy Hands have made; I see the stars, I hear the rolling thunder, Thy power throughout the universe displayed. When through the woods, and forest glades I wander, And hear the birds sing sweetly in the trees. When I look down, from lofty mountain grandeur And see the brook, and feel the gentle breeze. And when I think, that God, His Son not sparing; Sent Him to die, I scarce can take it in; That on the Cross, my burden gladly bearing, He bled and died to take away my sin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Is Well</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/it-is-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/it-is-well/</guid>
      <description>When peace, like a river, attendeth my way,
When sorrows like sea billows roll;
Whatever my lot, Thou has taught me to say,
It is well, it is well, with my soul.
Though Satan should buffet, though trials should come,
Let this blest assurance control,
That Christ has regarded my helpless estate,
And hath shed His own blood for my soul.
My sin, oh, the bliss of this glorious thought!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Led to the Slaughter</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/led-to-the-slaughter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/led-to-the-slaughter/</guid>
      <description>Expose our prideful motives, throw them away And clothe us with humility as You displayed We all have sought a savior in garbage heaps Lift us out from the wreckage, become our King Born into this world like us A humble human form Pouring Himself out as an offering God became just like a lamb led to the slaughter Expose our prideful motives, throw them away Present us in Your purity in these twisted days May we not seek false saviors in worthless things Collapse our knees beneath us, You are our King Every knee will bow, every tongue confess Every knee will bow, every tongue confess Every knee will bow, every tongue confess You’re the King and source of true righteousness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 10</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-10/</guid>
      <description>O Lord,  My sin wakes me up from my slumber.
At my weakest, my iniquities flood my mind. My mind is not sharp. My soul is asleep. In the pitch blackness of the night, I cannot see.
Sin is like a ravenous, rabid dog who sits upon my chest, waiting to devour me. I can smell it’s breath. I can taste the poison stench. My eardrums break from the deafening bark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 11</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-11/</guid>
      <description>Dear God,  I have seen the volley of artillery rain down all around me and You, O Lord, my precious shield, have absorbed their attacks.
Yet, the enemy’s sharpshooters have taken careful aim at my heart. Their fiery bullets have pierced my chest. Their lies have penetrated my mind. Their blasphemous words have laid weight upon my soul.
It hurts me so.
But You, O God, are endlessly faithful:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 12</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-12/</guid>
      <description>My Lord,  My legacy has already passed through my lips. I have nothing but strongest bitterness and the most potent venom to come out of my mouth.
I have lied. I have manipulated. I have cheated.
With my snake tongue, I have tried to get others to do my bidding, believing the lie that I am the one that needs to control them in order for my soul to be at peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 13</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-13/</guid>
      <description>O Lord,  You have not forgotten me.
You have not hidden your lovely face from me.
Your comfort and wisdom warm my soul.
Your joy and hope fill my heart all the day long.
You are mindful of me and when I call out your name, you answer me. You have answered me by saving me. You saved me by giving Yourself to me.
One day, I might stare down Death, but when I do, I will only see a crownless king with a broken scepter who has been stripped of power where there is little left to wield.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 14</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-14/</guid>
      <description>O Lord,  I would say to you, “I have not forgotten you.” But what about those times I succumb to the wickedness of my heart, to the depravity of the world, or to the lies of Satan? What about those times?
What about those times when I am devoid of strength and I do not turn to the one who has my infinite strength?
What about those times when I rely on my rational thought process, the very good gift that you have given me, instead being depended and led by that very Giver, the Spirit of God, by which I am declared to be your beloved son?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 15</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-15/</guid>
      <description>O Lord,  How could I possibly worship you? I am not worthy to commune with you and be with you. I sin even now. My heart strays. My soul wanders.
Yet, you, O God, are not far from me. When I am in the wilderness, you are closer than a whisper. When I have fallen, you set me back up on solid ground and you rejoice over me with singing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 16</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-16/</guid>
      <description>My Lord,  I have gone everywhere. I have not found any good apart from you.
When I turn away from you or try to find not You, my sorrow and grief run deep. It crushes my hearts and buries my soul.
When I try to give life to my idols, they give nothing back because there are no other gods. And I die.
When will I realize that you alone are my All-in-all?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 17</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-17/</guid>
      <description>O Father,  You are God of the Universe. Holy, righteous, just. High above my idols. High above my sins. High above my faults. High above the twisted wickedness of my own heart. In no way could I have ever approach you.
But you, O Lord, abundant in mercy and rich in grace, made the way. You sent your Son to come get me. Now I am yours.
I am your son.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 18, Pt 1</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>My Lord,  You are my All-in-all.
Beyond my Provider, it is by your very thought that you hold me together. By your will, I am pointed in your direction. By your great Spirit, I have strength.
You give unlimited might for this very weak man.
You put an immovable foundation beneath my weary feet.
You are my home where I can peacefully lay to rest.
You are my rescuer and it is in your arms, I know I am coming home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 18, Pt. 2</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>[][1]Red Tulips in the Snow by Lenore Ludlow My Lord,  My hands are not clean. My hands are washed in my own sin. They stink of feces and dung. If you judge me according to what I have done, then surely I am damned!
What hope do I have in myself and the works that I have done? I have nothing to give you, God.
But you knew. You knew and you came to be born as a man like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 18, Pt. 3</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-3/</guid>
      <description>You are my Way,
I am a man with little mercy. My life is filled with shame. My heart is ridden with cancerous sin. My will longs for the wide path well-traveled.
I cannot think I am better than a prideful man because I am that prideful man.
But you, O my Abba, have cleared one singular particular definite path to you and that is through your precious Son, my Christ my Savior and King.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 18, Pt. 4</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-4/</guid>
      <description>Who is like you, my Lord?
Who is like my God?
The one who has saved me and never abandoned me. The one who is my shield when fiery arrows have scorched the skies. The one who has called me righteous and equips me according to his own righteousness?
The one who has given me the speed to run to him in times of trouble? The one who has set me upon the mountaintop to see his awesome glory?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 18, Pt. 5</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-5/</guid>
      <description>I was once so far from you. I was once lost. I was once your sworn enemy. Instead of casting me out, you sought me out. Instead of leaving me lost, you found me. Instead of leaving me to die, you found me and gave me life. Instead being at war with me, you call me friend.
You are my only hope. You are my life. You are my salvation. You alone hold the words of eternal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 19</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-19/</guid>
      <description>My God,
I was deaf. I was mute. I was hungry. I was thirsty. I was blind. I was ignorant. I was violent. I cursed your name. I was a dumb brute. I was barbaric.
Yet, you transported from the spiritual to the material. You cut across space and time. You personally opened my eyes, gave words for my throat, opened my eyes, filled my heart, and gave me understanding so that I may know you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 2</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2/</guid>
      <description>My Lord,
I am set apart, this is true. But set apart by you to you.
I reach out to the world, plead to the world, and with the Spirit, invite the world to come into Your loving embrace.
Few do. Many do not.
How can I respond?
You are my Lord above. You are my King on high. All things, both spiritual and material, are yours. All truth and all philosophies are under your sovereign hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 20</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-20/</guid>
      <description>Lord, If I cry out for you, will you answer me? If you alone made the provisions and the sacrifices, will you save me? Even if I don’t understand you, will you reach for me? I need you, Lord. I don’t even have the wisdom to reach my hands up to you. I want you, God, and my heart is still filled with sin and wickedness. I have you, my Lord and my God, because I have your Spirit within me all because of what Your Son has done for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 3</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-3/</guid>
      <description>My God,  In my finite perception, my circumstances would seem to say I am in despair. I feel that. I feel that onslaught. I feel that pressure.
Many would say, ”Ah, your God has failed. Your God is not good. Your God does not deliver. Your God does not save.”
They would be wrong on all accounts.
When I turn away from all of my oppressors and turn towards you, I see the loveliness of your face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 4</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-4/</guid>
      <description>Dear God,  Help!
You have helped me in the past and this time I still need you.
I have dismissed all the lies around me.
I still need you.
I still need your love.
I still need your mercy.
I still need your grace.
Give me your hand.
I need to feel your embrace.
I need to feel your warmth.
I know you are always with me.
Right now, I will lay in peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 5</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-5/</guid>
      <description>My King and my God,  My heart grieves. My soul groans. I am in need of your Spirit.
My own pride has kept me far from you. My own arrogance has caused you to look away. Yet, I am in need of your holiness—the very thing that keeps me far is the very thing that keeps me close.
Clean my lips.
Give me your heart.
Remove this poison from my throat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 6</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-6/</guid>
      <description>My Holy Lord Above All,  My deeds have warranted not your affections but your attentions—attention to correct my path. However , it is not simply that, it is more serious, more deadly than that.
I continuously want death. I continuously want counterfeit. I continuously want less.
You, my Father, don’t want that for me.
You want life for me. You want truth for me. You want the most for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 7</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-7/</guid>
      <description>O Lord my God,  It might feel like the world is against me. I might feel like I am a being persecuted. But the real battle is not the world versus me but rather, my own sin and my own iniquities versus the spirit inside of me.
Dear God, my very best works and all of my good deeds before you are nothing more than used menstrual rags and bags of crap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 8</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-8/</guid>
      <description>My Lord, Our Lord,  Your name is known throughout all the earth.
Your fame knows no bounds.
Your glory will not be given to another.
Your love is simply unmatched.
And who you are and what you do is not determined and defined by the world around me. You are defined by your thoughts, your mind, your heart, and upon your revelation alone. I ask not for you to reveal more than what you have already reveal for my mind and soul and heart can barely comprehend your fullness now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 9</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-9/</guid>
      <description>Dear Lord,
I will not and cannot list what I think you have not done for me. That is preposterous! What you have done for me, in me, and through me is too great to even list. But I thank you so much. I thank you for you are absolutely good, absolutely merciful, absolutely gracious, and absolutely love. These I know of you and know you well.
God, you are high and exalted far above all creation, including any little thing I might create with my mind and my hands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take My Life</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/take-my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/take-my-life/</guid>
      <description>Take my life, and let it be Consecrated, Lord, to Thee; Take my moments and my days, Let them flow in ceaseless praise. Let them flow in ceaseless praise. Take my hands, and let them move At the impulse of Thy love; Take my feet, and let them be Swift and beautiful for Thee. Swift and beautiful for Thee. Take my voice, and let me sing Always, only, for my King; Take my lips, and let them be Filled with messages from Thee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving For Who You Are—You Are God Alone</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-who-you-are-you-are-god-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-who-you-are-you-are-god-alone/</guid>
      <description>I thank him who has given me strength, Christ Jesus our Lord, because he judged me faithful, appointing me to his service, though formerly I was a blasphemer, persecutor, and insolent opponent. But I received mercy because I had acted ignorantly in unbelief, and the grace of our Lord overflowed for me with the faith and love that are in Christ Jesus. The saying is trustworthy and deserving of full acceptance, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Adoption—Family</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-adoption-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-adoption-family/</guid>
      <description>John 14:18-21
“I will not leave you as orphans; I will come to you. Yet a little while and the world will see me no more, but you will see me. Because I live, you also will live. In that day you will know that I am in my Father, and you in me, and I in you. Whoever has my commandments and keeps them, he it is who loves me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Blood—Expiation</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-blood-expiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-blood-expiation/</guid>
      <description>Leviticus 6:28
And the earthenware vessel in which it is boiled shall be broken. But if it is boiled in a bronze vessel, that shall be scoured and rinsed in water.
Leviticus 16:21-22
And Aaron shall lay both his hands on the head of the live goat, and confess over it all the iniquities of the people of Israel, and all their transgressions, all their sins. And he shall put them on the head of the goat and send it away into the wilderness by the hand of a man who is in readiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Calling—Mission</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-calling-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-calling-mission/</guid>
      <description>Genesis 3:15
I will put enmity between you and the woman,
and between your offspring and her offspring;
he shall bruise your head,
and you shall bruise his heel.
Genesis 6:11-22
Now the earth was corrupt in God&amp;#8217;s sight, and the earth was filled with violence. And God saw the earth, and behold, it was corrupt, for all flesh had corrupted their way on the earth. And God said to Noah, “I have determined to make an end of all flesh, for the earth is filled with violence through them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Choice—Election</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-choice-election/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-choice-election/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 90:2
Before the mountains were brought forth,
or ever you had formed the earth and the world,
from everlasting to everlasting you are God.
Ephesians 1:3-10
Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Faith—Trustfulness</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-faith-trustfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-faith-trustfulness/</guid>
      <description>Genesis 24:27
and said, “Blessed be the LORD, the God of my master Abraham, who has not forsaken his steadfast love and his faithfulness toward my master. As for me, the LORD has led me in the way to the house of my master’s kinsmen.”
Genesis 32:10
I am not worthy of the least of all the deeds of steadfast love and all the faithfulness that you have shown to your servant, for with only my staff I crossed this Jordan, and now I have become two camps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Freedom—Redemption</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-freedom-redemption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-freedom-redemption/</guid>
      <description>Titus 3:3
For we ourselves were once foolish, disobedient, led astray, slaves to various passions and pleasures, passing our days in malice and envy, hated by others and hating one another.
Exodus 6:1-9
But the LORD said to Moses, “Now you shall see what I will do to Pharaoh; for with a strong hand he will send them out, and with a strong hand he will drive them out of his land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Friendship—Reconcilation</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-friendship-reconcilation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-friendship-reconcilation/</guid>
      <description>_Lord, you are more precious than silver.
Lord, you are more costly than gold.
Lord, you are more beautiful than diamonds, and
nothing I desire compares with you._
2 Chronicles 20:7
Did you not, our God, drive out the inhabitants of this land before your people Israel, and give it forever to the descendants of Abraham your friend?
Ruth 1:16-18
But Ruth said, “Do not urge me to leave you or to return from following you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Holiness—High and Lifted Up</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-holiness-high-and-lifted-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-holiness-high-and-lifted-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Leviticus 18:24-22:31&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do not make yourselves unclean by any of these things, for by all these the nations I am driving out before you have become unclean, and the land became unclean, so that I punished its iniquity, and the land vomited out its inhabitants. But you shall keep my statutes and my rules and do none of these abominations, either the native or the stranger who sojourns among you (for the people of the land, who were before you, did all of these abominations, so that the land became unclean), lest the land vomit you out when you make it unclean, as it vomited out the nation that was before you. For everyone who does any of these abominations, the persons who do them shall be cut off from among their people. So keep my charge never to practice any of these abominable customs that were practiced before you, and never to make yourselves unclean by them: I am the Lord your God.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Justification—Exoneration</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-justification-exoneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-justification-exoneration/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 51:4
Against you, you only, have I sinned
and done what is evil in your sight,
so that you may be justified in your words
and blameless in your judgment.
Titus 3:4-7 But when the goodness and loving kindness of God our Savior appeared, he saved us, not because of works done by us in righteousness, but according to his own mercy, by the washing of regeneration and renewal of the Holy Spirit, whom he poured out on us richly through Jesus Christ our Savior, so that being justified by his grace we might become heirs according to the hope of eternal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Love—Affections</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-love-affections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-love-affections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, God created the heavens and the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Chronicles 16:34&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh give thanks to the Lord, for he is good;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for his steadfast love endures forever!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew 5:45 For he makes his sun rise on the evil and on the good, and sends rain on the just and on the unjust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Titus 3:4-7&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when the goodness and loving kindness of God our Savior appeared, he saved us, not because of works done by us in righteousness, but according to his own mercy, by the washing of regeneration and renewal of the Holy Spirit, whom he poured out on us richly through Jesus Christ our Savior, so that being justified by his grace we might become heirs according to the hope of eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Mercies—Propitiation</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-mercies-propitiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-mercies-propitiation/</guid>
      <description>Luke 18:13
But the tax collector, standing far off, would not even lift up his eyes to heaven, but beat his breast, saying, ‘God, be merciful to me, a sinner!’
Leviticus 6:28
And the earthenware vessel in which it is boiled shall be broken. But if it is boiled in a bronze vessel, that shall be scoured and rinsed in water.
Isaiah 53:1-12
Who has believed what he has heard from us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Mind—Repentence</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-mind-repentence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-mind-repentence/</guid>
      <description>Numbers 23:19
God is not man, that he should lie,
or a son of man, that he should change his mind.
Has he said, and will he not do it?
Or has he spoken, and will he not fulfill it?
Deuteronomy 5:29
Oh that they had such a mind as this always, to fear me and to keep all my commandments, that it might go well with them and with their descendants forever!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your New Heart—Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-new-heart-regeneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-new-heart-regeneration/</guid>
      <description>Genesis 6:5-6
The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually. And the LORD was sorry that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart.
Lamentations 5:3
We have become orphans, fatherless;
our mothers are like widows.
1 Chronicles 29:15
For we are strangers before you and sojourners, as all our fathers were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Righteousness—Perfection</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-righteousness-perfection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-righteousness-perfection/</guid>
      <description>Isaiah 64:6
We have all become like one who is unclean,
and all our righteous deeds are like a polluted garment.
We all fade like a leaf,
and our iniquities, like the wind, take us away.
Genesis 3:21
And the LORD God made for Adam and for his wife garments of skins and clothed them.
Genesis 6:5-9
The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Weight–Glorification</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-weight-glorification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-weight-glorification/</guid>
      <description>Exodus 14:1-4
Then the LORD said to Moses, “Tell the people of Israel to turn back and encamp in front of Pi-hahiroth, between Migdol and the sea, in front of Baal-zephon; you shall encamp facing it, by the sea. For Pharaoh will say of the people of Israel, ‘They are wandering in the land; the wilderness has shut them in.’ And I will harden Pharaoh’s heart, and he will pursue them, and I will get glory over Pharaoh and all his host, and the Egyptians shall know that I am the LORD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Word—Scriptures</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-word-scriptures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-word-scriptures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John 1:1-5; 14-18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. He was in the beginning with God. All things were made through him, and without him was not any thing made that was made. In him was life, and the life was the light of men. The light shines in the darkness, and the darkness has not overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the Word became flesh and dwelt among us, and we have seen his glory, glory as of the only Son from the Father, full of grace and truth. (John bore witness about him, and cried out, “This was he of whom I said, ‘He who comes after me ranks before me, because he was before me.’”) And from his fullness we have all received, grace upon grace. For the law was given through Moses; grace and truth came through Jesus Christ. No one has ever seen God; the only God, who is at the Father’s side, he has made him known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genesis 3:15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will put enmity between you and the woman,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and between your offspring and her offspring;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;he shall bruise your head,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and you shall bruise his heel.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Work–Sanctification</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-work-sanctification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-work-sanctification/</guid>
      <description>Exodus 29:43
There I will meet with the people of Israel, and it shall be sanctified by my glory.
Exodus 31:13
“You are to speak to the people of Israel and say, ‘Above all you shall keep my Sabbaths, for this is a sign between me and you throughout your generations, that you may know that I, the LORD, sanctify you.
Leviticus 10:3
Then Moses said to Aaron, “This is what the LORD has said, ‘Among those who are near me I will be sanctified, and before all the people I will be glorified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Solid Rock</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/the-solid-rock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/the-solid-rock/</guid>
      <description>My hope is built on nothing less Than Jesus’ blood and righteousness; I dare not trust the sweetest frame, But wholly lean on Jesus’ name. When darkness veils His lovely face, I rest on His unchanging grace; In every high and stormy gale, My anchor holds within the veil. His oath, His covenant, His blood Support me in the whelming flood; When all around my soul gives way, He then is all my hope and stay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To God Be The Glory</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/to-god-be-the-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/to-god-be-the-glory/</guid>
      <description>To God be the glory, great things He has done; So loved He the world that He gave us His Son, Who yielded His life an atonement for sin, And opened the life gate that all may go in. O perfect redemption, the purchase of blood, To every believer the promise of God; The vilest offender who truly believes, That moment from Jesus a pardon receives. Great things He has taught us, great things He has done, And great our rejoicing through Jesus the Son; But purer, and higher, and greater will be Our wonder, our transport, when Jesus we see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ungratefulness</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/ungratefulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/ungratefulness/</guid>
      <description>Lord, with what bounty and rare clemency Have you redeemed us from the grave! If you had let us run, Gladly had man adored the sun, And thought his god most brave; Where now we shall be better gods than he. You have but two rare cabinets full of treasure, The Trinity, and Incarnation: You have unlocked them both, And made them jewels to betroth The work of your creation Unto your self in everlasting pleasure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Have Not Known Thee As We Ought</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/we-have-not-known-thee-as-we-ought/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/we-have-not-known-thee-as-we-ought/</guid>
      <description>We have not known Thee as we ought, Nor learned Thy wisdom, grace and power; The things of earth have filled our thought, And trifles of the passing hour. Lord, give us light Thy truth to see, And make us wise in knowing Thee. We have not feared Thee as we ought, Nor bowed beneath Thine awful eye, Nor guarded deed and word and thought, Remembering that God was nigh. Lord, give us faith to know Thee near, And grant the grace of holy fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Will Worship The Lamb of Glory</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/we-will-worship-the-lamb-of-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/we-will-worship-the-lamb-of-glory/</guid>
      <description>We will worship the Lamb of glory, We will worship the King of kings. We will worship the Lamb of glory, We will worship the King. We bless the name of the Lamb of Glory. We bless the name of the King of Kings. We bless the name of the Lamb of Glory. We bless the name of the King. We give all praise to the Lamb of Glory. We give all praise to the King of Kings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are So Good To Me</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/you-are-so-good-to-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/you-are-so-good-to-me/</guid>
      <description>You are so good to me You heal my broken heart You are my Father in heaven You ride upon the clouds You lead me to the truth You are the Spirit inside me You are beautiful my sweet, sweet, song  I will sing again   You are my strong melody You are my dancing rhythm You are my perfect rhyme And I want to sing forever  You poured out all your blood You died upon the cross You are my Jesus who loves me You are my Father in heaven You are the Spirit inside me You are the Jesus who loves me And I will sing again… &amp;#8211; 100 Portraits and Waterdeep</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Have Redeemed My Soul</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/you-have-redeemed-my-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/you-have-redeemed-my-soul/</guid>
      <description>I was a hungry child
A dried up river
I was a burned out forest
And no one could do anything for me
But You put food in my body
And water in my dried bed
And to my blackened branches
You brought the springtime
green of new life
And nothing is impossible for You
_You have redeemed my soul
From the pit of emptiness
You have redeemed my soul</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Won’t Relent</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/you-wont-relent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/you-wont-relent/</guid>
      <description>You won’t relent until You have it all My heart is Yours I’ll set You as a seal upon my heart As a seal upon my arm For there is love that is as strong as death Jealousy demanding as the grave Many waters cannot quench this love Come be the fire inside of me Come be the flame upon my heart come be the fire inside of me Until You and I are one &amp;#8211; Misty Edwards</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>