<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Douglas Wilson on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/douglas-wilson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Douglas Wilson on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/douglas-wilson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything But</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/anything-but/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/anything-but/</guid>
      <description>Sarah Leading Hagar to Abraham by Matthias Stom&amp;#8220;The parable, in Luke 18:9-14, was directed against those who thought they were righteous and looked down on everyone else. We need to place due emphasis on the phrase &amp;#8216;who thought they were righteous.&amp;#8217; People who preen themselves on their own righteousness go home unjustified even if they were baptized in a joint service with the pope and Billy Graham officiating. The self-righteous can trust in anything but Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faith Replacing Works?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/faith-replacing-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/faith-replacing-works/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;_Fides salvifica_ receives all of Scripture as good news from a gracious God. In a general sense, all is gospel. But the Scripture does contain what might be called the Gospel proper, the good news of Christ’s death, burial, and resurrection. This is why the Protestant scholastics also said that there was a _fides evangelica_ that specifically trusts in the revelation that God gives to us in the gospel of the death, burial, and resurrection of Jesus Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God Knew Ahead</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-knew-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-knew-ahead/</guid>
      <description>Wilson: &amp;#8220;God knew that we were going to need to pick up dimes, and so He gave us fingernails. He knew that twilights displayed in blue, apricot, and battle gray would be entirely astonishing and beyond us, and so He gave us eyes that can see in color. He could have made all food quite nourishing, but which tasted like wadded up newspaper soaked in machine oil. Instead He gave us the tastes of watermelon, pecans, oatmeal stout, buttered corn, apples, fresh bread, grilled sirloin, and 25-year-old scotch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Christianity Good for the World? by Christopher Hitchens and Douglas Wilson, A Quick Review</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/books/is-christianity-good-for-the-world-by-christopher-hitchens-and-douglas-wilson-a-quick-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/books/is-christianity-good-for-the-world-by-christopher-hitchens-and-douglas-wilson-a-quick-review/</guid>
      <description>Good, good, good, so good.
Wilson is top-notch and has the upper hand to give the response.
Hitchens is spot-on typical atheist:
 Remove God from the equation Plug-in Evolution as the new source Profit$  In this, the main hard-hitting topic was Morals and Ethics or the source of Morals and Ethics.
Wilson&amp;#8217;s explanation needs none here. Hitchens&amp;#8217; explanation is that there is no source but rather, our morals have evolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Our Britches Lined With Footnotes</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/keeping-our-britches-lined-with-footnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/keeping-our-britches-lined-with-footnotes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;I will assert that serious theology cannot expect to get anywhere until we knock off the urbane silliness that characterizes so much theological discussion today. The Scriptures say the fear of the Lord is the beginning of knowledge; some have taken this to mean that unbelief and autonomous rationality must be the beginning of knowledge. In light of this, the ache that some conservative scholars have to be taken seriously in the unbelieving academy is a pitiful thing indeed, and so I would like to take this opportunity to give the whole thing the universal raspberry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowing τελοσ or Bust!</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/knowing-%CF%84%CE%B5%CE%BB%CE%BF%CF%83-or-bust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/knowing-%CF%84%CE%B5%CE%BB%CE%BF%CF%83-or-bust/</guid>
      <description>Studying Philosophy, I am wrestling with the meaning and understanding of telos as in teleological arguments or teleology.
For several weeks, I keep running into the Gk. root _telos- _and for weeks, I had to keep looking it up on my iPhone to remind me what it means and more importantly, &amp;#8220;what the sentence is actually saying&amp;#8220;.
And the cement becomes bone-dry when I read this little quote:
&amp;#8220;Moses declared that the law was not too hard for Israel to keep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Haven’t Evolved In Rising Above Sin</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/we-havent-evolved-in-rising-above-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/we-havent-evolved-in-rising-above-sin/</guid>
      <description>Wilson: You say, incidentally, that this kind of law was bringing coals to Newcastle—Moses came down from the mount and told people that murder, theft, and perjury were wrong, and all the assembled rolled their collective eyes. &amp;#8220;We already knew that!&amp;#8221; But the problem is that ancient man didn&amp;#8217;t know that, and modern man still doesn&amp;#8217;t know it. To state some of the issues that are subsumed under just one of the three categories you mention is to point to controversies that continue down to this day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>