<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 12:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Ivy</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/personal/love-letter-ivy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/personal/love-letter-ivy/</guid>
      <description>Ivy, my sweetest and most precious girl,
I could not begin to tell you what we were going through when we heard about you: death of my father, my grandmother, your Momma&amp;#8217;s grandfather, and the passing away of your sister, Olivia.
These storms and the pains that we were going through in our own heart and souls tested the mettle of your Momma and Papa&amp;#8217;s marriage and relationship and shook the foundation of our family to the bedrock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harshness vs Expressing One’s Feelings</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/books/harshness-vs-expressing-ones-feelings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 15:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/books/harshness-vs-expressing-ones-feelings/</guid>
      <description>Take a look at this hot mess that someone might call a &amp;#8216;book review&amp;#8217;:
For so long, the gospel of God has been assumed in our churches. We now stand on the cusp of the gospel being denied from those who grew up in church and yet was never taught the fullness of the gospel and the full council of the Bible. Nevermind, the true gospel being scoffed at from the unbeliever&amp;#8211;we know that would happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping It Personally Real</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/personal/keeping-it-personally-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/personal/keeping-it-personally-real/</guid>
      <description>For a tad over 300 hundred posts, I was able to keep this blog free from personal feelings and insight. I was doing my best to bifurcate my theological pursuits and the pursuits of the heart.
But over the last year, with the maturity of my emotions increasing, I am beginning to see that is an impossibility. To do so would be to go against the tagline of this site as penned by Samuel Rutherford: “No pen, no words, no image can express to you the loveliness of my only, only Lord Jesus”.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>