<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timothy Keller on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/timothy-keller/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timothy Keller on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/timothy-keller/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fanatical Christians Actually Haven’t Gone Far Enough</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/fanatical-christians-actually-havent-gone-far-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/fanatical-christians-actually-havent-gone-far-enough/</guid>
      <description>Think of people you consider fanatical. They’re overbearing, self-righteous, opinionated, insensitive, and harsh. Why? It’s not because they are too Christian but because they are not Christian enough. They are fanatically zealous and courageous, but they are not fanatically humble, sensitive, loving, empathetic, forgiving, or understanding – as Christ was. Because they think of Christianity as a self-improvement program they emulate the Jesus of the whips in the temple, but not the Jesus who said, “Let him who is without sin cast the first stone” (John 8:7).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let Me Control My Environment in Order To Make My Life Better</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/let-me-control-my-environment-in-order-to-make-my-life-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/let-me-control-my-environment-in-order-to-make-my-life-better/</guid>
      <description>In ancient times it was understood that there was a transcendent moral order outside the self, built in to the fabric of the universe. If you violated that metaphysical order there were consequences just as severe as if you violated physical reality by placing your hand in a fire. The path of wisdom was to learn to live in conformity with this unyielding reality. That wisdom rested largely in developing qualities of character, such as humility, compassion, courage, discretion, and loyalty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Current Philosophies of Not Wanting To Think</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-current-philosophies-of-not-wanting-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-current-philosophies-of-not-wanting-to-think/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Every effort to account for the birth of the church apart from Jesus&amp;#8217;s resurrection flies in the face of what we know about first-century history and culture. If you don&amp;#8217;t short-circuit the process with philosophical bias against the possibility of miracle, the resurrection of Jesus has the most evidence for it.
The problem is, however, that people do short-circuit the investigation. Instead of doing the work of answering these very tough historical questions and then following the answers where they lead, they bail out with the objection that miracles are impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gospel Does One Better</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-gospel-does-one-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-gospel-does-one-better/</guid>
      <description>Reflecting on the movie, Angels with Dirty Faces and the novel, A Tale of Two Cities:
&amp;#8220;I always found these stories of sacrifice very emotionally affecting. I came away from them resolving to live more courageously and unselfishly. I never did follow through on my resolutions, however. The stories moved my emotions and pricked my conscience, but my heart&amp;#8217;s basic patterns stayed intact. I was still driving by a need to prove myself to others, to win approval acclaim, to control what people thought of me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Logic of Miracles</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-logic-of-miracles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-logic-of-miracles/</guid>
      <description>The other hidden premise in the statement &amp;#8220;miracles cannot happen&amp;#8221; is &amp;#8220;there can’t be a God who does miracles.&amp;#8221; If there is a Creator God, there is nothing illogical at all about the possibility of miracles. After all, if he created everything out of nothing, it would hardly be a problem for him to rearrange parts of it as and when he wishes. To be sure that miracles cannot occur you would have to be sure beyond a doubt that God didn’t exist, and that is an article of faith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mainstream of Religion</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-mainstream-of-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-mainstream-of-religion/</guid>
      <description>Religion is not just a temporary thing that helped us adapt to our environment. Rather it is a permanent and central aspect of the human condition. This is a bitter pill for secular, nonreligious people to swallow. Everyone wants to think that they are in the mainstream, that they are not extremists. But robust religious beliefs dominate the world. There is no reason to expect that to change. Timothy Keller. The Reason for God: Belief in an Age of Skepticism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Do I Believe What I Believe?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/why-do-i-believe-what-i-believe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/why-do-i-believe-what-i-believe/</guid>
      <description>A faith without some doubts is like a human body without any antibodies in it. People who blithely go through life too busy or indifferent to ask hard questions about why they believe as they do will find themselves defenseless against either the experience of tragedy or the probing questions of a smart skeptic. A person&amp;#8217;s faith can collapse almost overnight if she has failed over the years to listen patiently to her own doubts, which should only be discarded after long reflection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Should I Live?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/why-should-i-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/why-should-i-live/</guid>
      <description>I have lived my life boiled down to one simple quote: Nicolaus Zinzendorf&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Preach the gospel, die, and be forgotten&amp;#8217; as to shine light on the meaning of 1 Corinthians 2:2 in my life. All of my studies and all of my toiling and to a much larger, unavoidable influence, the way that I love and live my life, are all wrapped in up that one little quote. It is a quote that I have mediated much on and it is a now philosophy I cannot let go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Ha, ha! Too Late!” said God never</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/ha-ha-too-late-said-god-never/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/ha-ha-too-late-said-god-never/</guid>
      <description>Modern people inevitably think that hell works like this: God gives us time, but if we haven&amp;#8217;t made the right choices by the end of our lives, he casts our souls into hell for all eternity. As the poor souls fall through space, they cry out for mercy, but God says &amp;#8220;Too late!&amp;#8221; You had your chance! Now you will suffer!&amp;#8221; This caricature misunderstands the very nature of evil. The Biblical picture is that sin separates us from the presence of God, which is the source of all joy and indeed all love, wisdom, or good things of any sort.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>