<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paul David Tripp on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/tags/paul-david-tripp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paul David Tripp on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/tags/paul-david-tripp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Calling by Paul David Tripp: A Review</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/books/dangerous-calling-by-paul-david-tripp-a-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/books/dangerous-calling-by-paul-david-tripp-a-review/</guid>
      <description>I like this book and I am not even a pastor. And I am not going to preface this review with any sort of calling that God has on my life or whatever He might be walking me through. I think this book is suited for any Christian for we are all saints who are being equipped for the work of the ministry. 1{#return-note-1548-1.simple-footnote} But I think it would be a shame for any Christian to look at the cover, dismiss it because &amp;#8220;Oh I am not a pastor&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Calling: Blind to My True Condition</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/dangerous-calling-blind-to-my-true-condition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/dangerous-calling-blind-to-my-true-condition/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;You see, sin is not first an intellectual problem. (Yes, it does affect my intellect, as it does all parts of my functioning.) Sin is first a moral problem. It is about my rebellion against God and my quest to have for myself the glory that is due to him. Sin is not first about the breaking of an abstract set of rules. Sin is first and foremost about breaking relationship with God, and because I have broken this relationship, it is then easy and natural to rebel against God’s rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Calling: God Will Give Us What We Want</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/dangerous-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/dangerous-calling/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, we think of God as a pragmatic god. We think we do exactly as he says, we make it appear that all is well, and do everything to please him, he will give us whatever our heart&amp;#8217;s desires.
Wait, what if my heart&amp;#8217;s desires are for something not Him? What if I want more money, more sex, more work, more security, more of anything out of God but not God himself?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Calling: Where’s The Grace?</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/dangerous-calling-wheres-the-grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/dangerous-calling-wheres-the-grace/</guid>
      <description>Lectures. Speaking engagements. One-on-one counseling. Teaching. Preaching. Speaking. Whispering. Is it possible to continuously proclaiming the glorious, loving, gracious gospel of Jesus Christ? What if I preached to myself His gospel? What if I continuously filled my mind not with mindless entertainment but with His glorious revelation? What if I stepped into the world and loved the world in the way He did? What if I could get ever moment of my life to proclaim His goodness and grace?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>