<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Athanasius on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/athanasius/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Athanasius on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/athanasius/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: Death Has Been Brought to Nothing</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-death-has-been-brought-to-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-death-has-been-brought-to-nothing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Have no fears then. Now that the common Savior of all has died on our behalf, we who believe in Christ no longer die, as men died aforetime, in fulfillment of the threat of the law. That condemnation has come to an end; and now that, by the grace of the resurrection, corruption has been banished and done away, we are loosed from our mortal bodies in God&amp;#8217;s good time for each, so that we may obtain thereby a better resurrection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: Fully God, Fully Human</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-fully-god-fully-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-fully-god-fully-human/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;For this purpose, then, the incorporeal and incorruptible and immaterial Word of God entered our world. In one sense, indeed, He was not far from it before, for no part of creation had ever been without Him Who, while ever abiding in union with the Father, yet fills all things that are. But now He entered the world in a new way, stooping to our level in His love and Self-revealing to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: God Comes To Us</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-god-comes-to-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-god-comes-to-us/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;But how was He to do it? By the same means as before, perhaps you will say, that is, through the works of creation. But this was proven insufficient. Men had neglected to consider the heavens before, and now they were looking in the opposite direction. Wherefore, in all naturalness and fitness, desiring to do good to men, as Man He dwells, taking to Himself a body like the rest; and through His actions done in that body, as it were on their own level, He teaches those who would not learn by other means to know Himself, the Word of God, and through Him the Father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: He Did Not Leave Us Like Brutes</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-he-did-not-leave-us-like-brutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-he-did-not-leave-us-like-brutes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Was He to keep silence before so great a wrong and let men go on being thus deceived and kept in ignorance of Himself? If so, what was the use of having made them in His own Image originally? It would surely have been better for them always to have been brutes, rather than to revert to that condition when once they had shared the nature of the Word. Again, things being as they were, what was the use of their ever having had the knowledge of God?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: His Honor In Exchange For Our Destruction</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-his-honor-in-exchange-for-our-destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-his-honor-in-exchange-for-our-destruction/</guid>
      <description>[][1]The Course of Empire Destruction by Thomas Cole &amp;#8220;This great work was, indeed, supremely worthy of the goodness of God. A king who has founded a city, so far from neglecting it when through the carelessness of the inhabitants it is attacked by robbers, avenges it and saves it from destruction, having regard rather to his own honor than to the people&amp;#8217;s neglect. Much more, then, the Word of the All-good Father was not unmindful of the human race that He had called to be; but rather, by the offering of His own body He abolished the death which they had incurred, and corrected their neglect by His own teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: His Works Made Visible For the World to See</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-his-works-made-visible-for-the-world-to-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-his-works-made-visible-for-the-world-to-see/</guid>
      <description>There were thus two things which the Savior did for us by becoming Man. He banished death from us and made us anew; and, invisible and imperceptible as in Himself He is, He became visible through His works and revealed Himself as the Word of the Father, the Ruler and King of the whole creation.
 Athanasius. On The Incarnation of the Word. 245-247. Kindle Edition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: Reasonable Beings That Could Apprehend the Father</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-reasonable-beings-that-could-apprehend-the-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-reasonable-beings-that-could-apprehend-the-father/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;For of what use is existence to the creature if it cannot know its Maker? How could men be reasonable beings if they had no knowledge of the Word and Reason of the Father, through Whom they had received their being? They would be no better than the beasts, had they no knowledge save of earthly things; and why should God have made them at all, if He had not intended them to know Him?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: So That God Might Be Revealed to All</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-so-that-god-might-be-revealed-to-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-so-that-god-might-be-revealed-to-all/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Whose all-ruling providence makes known the Father to all. Or, if this was beyond them, they could converse with holy men, and through them learn to know God, the Artificer of all things, the Father of Christ, and to recognize the worship of idols as the negation of the truth and full of all impiety. Or else, in the third place, they could cease from lukewarmness and lead a good life merely by knowing the law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: Taking On Our Weakness</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-taking-on-our-weakness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-taking-on-our-weakness/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The death of men under ordinary circumstances is the result of their natural weakness. They are essentially impermanent, so after a time they fall ill and when worn out they die. But the Lord is not like that. He is not weak, He is the Power of God and Word of God and Very Life Itself. If He had died quietly in His bed like other men it would have looked as if He did so in accordance with His nature, and as though He was indeed no more than other men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: The Death of Death in the Death of the Word Made Man</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-the-death-of-death-in-the-death-of-the-word-made-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-the-death-of-death-in-the-death-of-the-word-made-man/</guid>
      <description>For by the sacrifice of His own body He did two things: He put an end to the law of death which barred our way; and He made a new beginning of life for us, by giving us the hope of resurrection. By man death has gained its power over men; by the Word made Man death has been destroyed and life raised up anew.
 Athanasius. On The Incarnation of the Word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: The Mystery That We Adore</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-the-mystery-that-we-adore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-the-mystery-that-we-adore/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Now, Macarius, true lover of Christ, we must take a step further in the faith of our holy religion, and consider also the Word&amp;#8217;s becoming Man and His divine Appearing in our midst. That mystery the Jews traduce, the Greeks deride, but we adore; and your own love and devotion to the Word also will be the greater, because in His Manhood He seems so little worth. For it is a fact that the more unbelievers pour scorn on Him, so much the more does He make His Godhead evident.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: The Truth Behind the Imago Dei</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-the-truth-behind-the-imago-dei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-the-truth-behind-the-imago-dei/</guid>
      <description>Creation of Adam by Buonarroti Michelangelo &amp;#8220;His own Word, our Lord Jesus Christ and of all these His earthly creatures He reserved especial mercy for the race of men. Upon them, therefore, upon men who, as animals, were essentially impermanent, He bestowed a grace which other creatures lacked&amp;#8211;namely the impress of His own Image, a share in the reasonable being of the very Word Himself, so that, reflecting Him and themselves becoming reasonable and expressing the Mind of God even as He does, though in limited degree they might continue for ever in the blessed and only true life of the saints in paradise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On The Incarnation: Why Did God Become Flesh?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-why-did-god-become-flesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-why-did-god-become-flesh/</guid>
      <description>He has been manifested in a human body for this reason only, out of the love and goodness of His Father, for the salvation of us men.
 Athanasius. On The Incarnation of the Word. 15-16 . Kindle Edition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: Worthy Enough To Suffer For Us</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-worthy-enough-to-suffer-for-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-worthy-enough-to-suffer-for-us/</guid>
      <description>[][1]The Crucifixion: Christ on the Cross by Diego Velazquez &amp;#8220;What&amp;#8211;or rather Who was it that was needed for such grace and such recall as we required? Who, save the Word of God Himself, Who also in the beginning had made all things out of nothing? His part it was, and His alone, both to bring again the corruptible to incorruption and to maintain for the Father His consistency of character with all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>