<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Perspective on Paul on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/tags/new-perspective-on-paul/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New Perspective on Paul on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/tags/new-perspective-on-paul/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything But</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/theology/anything-but/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/theology/anything-but/</guid>
      <description>Sarah Leading Hagar to Abraham by Matthias Stom&amp;#8220;The parable, in Luke 18:9-14, was directed against those who thought they were righteous and looked down on everyone else. We need to place due emphasis on the phrase &amp;#8216;who thought they were righteous.&amp;#8217; People who preen themselves on their own righteousness go home unjustified even if they were baptized in a joint service with the pope and Billy Graham officiating. The self-righteous can trust in anything but Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faith Replacing Works?</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/theology/faith-replacing-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/theology/faith-replacing-works/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;_Fides salvifica_ receives all of Scripture as good news from a gracious God. In a general sense, all is gospel. But the Scripture does contain what might be called the Gospel proper, the good news of Christ’s death, burial, and resurrection. This is why the Protestant scholastics also said that there was a _fides evangelica_ that specifically trusts in the revelation that God gives to us in the gospel of the death, burial, and resurrection of Jesus Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Our Britches Lined With Footnotes</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/theology/keeping-our-britches-lined-with-footnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/theology/keeping-our-britches-lined-with-footnotes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;I will assert that serious theology cannot expect to get anywhere until we knock off the urbane silliness that characterizes so much theological discussion today. The Scriptures say the fear of the Lord is the beginning of knowledge; some have taken this to mean that unbelief and autonomous rationality must be the beginning of knowledge. In light of this, the ache that some conservative scholars have to be taken seriously in the unbelieving academy is a pitiful thing indeed, and so I would like to take this opportunity to give the whole thing the universal raspberry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowing τελοσ or Bust!</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/knowing-%CF%84%CE%B5%CE%BB%CE%BF%CF%83-or-bust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/knowing-%CF%84%CE%B5%CE%BB%CE%BF%CF%83-or-bust/</guid>
      <description>Studying Philosophy, I am wrestling with the meaning and understanding of telos as in teleological arguments or teleology.
For several weeks, I keep running into the Gk. root _telos- _and for weeks, I had to keep looking it up on my iPhone to remind me what it means and more importantly, &amp;#8220;what the sentence is actually saying&amp;#8220;.
And the cement becomes bone-dry when I read this little quote:
&amp;#8220;Moses declared that the law was not too hard for Israel to keep.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>