<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Valley of Vision on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/categories/valley-of-vision/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Valley of Vision on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 12:00:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/categories/valley-of-vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Love of Jesus</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-love-of-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-love-of-jesus/</guid>
      <description>My heart melts at the love of Jesus, my brother, bone of my bone, flesh of my flesh, married to me, dead for me, risen for me; He is mine and I am his, given to me as well as for me;  &amp;#8211; from The Love of Jesus
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jesus My Glory</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/jesus-my-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/jesus-my-glory/</guid>
      <description>His water and blood were not severed in their flow at the cross, may they never be separated in my creed and experiences;  &amp;#8211; from Jesus My Glory
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christ Alone</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/christ-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 12:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/christ-alone/</guid>
      <description>Though here I love him but little, may this be my portion at last. In this world thou hast given me a beginning, one day it will be perfected in the realm above. Thou hast helped me to see and know Christ, though obscurely, to take him, receive him, to possess him, love him, to bless him in my heart, mouth, life.  &amp;#8211; from Christ Alone
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Name of Jesus</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-name-of-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 12:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-name-of-jesus/</guid>
      <description>I am ready to flee from myself because of my abominations; Yet thou dost not abhor me but hast devised means for my return to thee, and that, by thy Son who died to give me life.  &amp;#8211; from The Name of Jesus
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Union with Christ</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/union-with-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 12:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/union-with-christ/</guid>
      <description>The more I hunger and thirst after thee, the more I faint and fail in finding thee, The more my heart is broken for sin, the more I pray it may be far more broken.  &amp;#8211; from Union with Christ
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fullness in Christ</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/fullness-in-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 12:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/fullness-in-christ/</guid>
      <description>... that it is my duty, out of a sense of emptiness, to go to Christ, possess, enjoy his fullness as mine, as if I had it in myself, because it is for me in him; that when I do this I am full of the Spirit, as a fish that has got from the shore to the sea and has all fullness of waters to move in, for when faith fills me, then I am full; that this is the way to be filled with the Spirit, like Stephen, first faith, then fullness, for this way makes me most empty, and so most fit for the Spirit to fill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christ is All</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/christ-is-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 12:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/christ-is-all/</guid>
      <description>I think of thy glory and my vileness, thy majesty and my meanness, thy beauty and my deformity, thy purity and my filth, thy righteousness and my iniquity. Thou hast loved me everlastingly, unchangeably, may I love thee as I am loved; Thou hast given thyself for me, may I give myself to thee;  &amp;#8211; from Christ is All
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christ the Word</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/christ-the-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/christ-the-word/</guid>
      <description>When I sin against thee I cross thy will, love, life, and have no comforter, no creature, to go to. My sin is not so much this or that particular evil, but my continual separation, disunion, distance from thee, and having a loose spirit towards thee. But thou hast given me a present, Jesus thy Son, as Mediator between thyself and my soul, as middle-man who in a pit holds both him below and him above, for only he can span the chasm breached by sin, and satisfy divine justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gift of Gifts</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-gift-of-gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 12:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-gift-of-gifts/</guid>
      <description>In him thou hast given me so much that heaven can give no more.  &amp;#8211; from The Gift of Gifts
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Praise and Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/praise-and-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/praise-and-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>When I think upon and converse with thee ten thousand delightful thoughts spring up, ten thousand sources of pleasure are unsealed, ten thousand refreshing joys spread over my heart, crowding into every moment of happiness.  &amp;#8211; from Praise and Thanksgiving
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God Honored</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/god-honored/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/god-honored/</guid>
      <description>The sea, dry land, winter cold, summer heat, morning light, evening shade are full of thee, and thou givest me them richly to enjoy. Thou art King of kings and Lord of lords; At thy pleasure empires rise and fall; All thy works praise thee and thy saints bless thee; Let me be numbered with thy holy ones, resemble them in character and condition, sit with them at Jesus’ feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man’s Great End</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/mans-great-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 12:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/mans-great-end/</guid>
      <description>There is one thing that deserves my greatest care, that calls forth my ardent desires, That is, that I may answer the great end for which I am made — to glorify thee who hast given me being, and to do all the good I can for my fellow men; Verily, life is not worth having if it be not improved for this noble purpose.  &amp;#8211; from Man&amp;#8217;s Great End</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Present Salvation</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/a-present-salvation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/a-present-salvation/</guid>
      <description>I adore thee for making me capable of knowing thee, for giving me reason and conscience, for leading me to desire thee; I praise thee for the revelation of thyself in the gospel, for thy heart as a dwelling place of pity, for thy thoughts of peace towards me, for thy patience and thy graciousness, for the vastness of thy mercy.  &amp;#8211; from A Present Salvation
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God Enjoyed</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/god-enjoyed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 12:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/god-enjoyed/</guid>
      <description>Known, but beyond knowledge, revealed, but unrevealed, my wants and welfare draw me to thee, for thou hast never said, ‘Seek ye me in vain’.  &amp;#8211; from God Enjoyed
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Divine Mercies</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/divine-mercies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/divine-mercies/</guid>
      <description>Thine is surpassing greatness, unspeakable goodness, super-abundant grace; I can as soon count the sands of ocean’s ‘lip’ as number thy favours towards me;  &amp;#8211; from Divine Mercies
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Divine Will</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-divine-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 12:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-divine-will/</guid>
      <description>Strengthen me to pray with the conviction that whatever I receive is thy gift, so that I may pray until prayer be granted;  &amp;#8211; from The Divine Will
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mover</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-mover/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-mover/</guid>
      <description>Who made me to differ, but thee? for I was no more ready to receive Christ than were others; I could not have begun to love thee hadst thou not first loved me, or been willing unless thou hadst first made me so. O that such a crown should fit the head of such a sinner! such high advancement be for an unfruitful person! such joys for so vile a rebel!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The All Good</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-all-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-all-good/</guid>
      <description>Let me know the need of renovation as well as of forgiveness, in order to serve and enjoy thee for ever. I come to thee in the all-prevailing name of Jesus, with nothing of my own to plead, no works, no worthiness, no promises.  &amp;#8211; from The All Good
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great God</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-great-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-great-god/</guid>
      <description>Let me know the need of renovation as well as of forgiveness, in order to serve and enjoy thee for ever. I come to thee in the all-prevailing name of Jesus, with nothing of my own to plead, no works, no worthiness, no promises.  &amp;#8211; from The Great God
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God The All: The All-Prevailing Name</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/god-the-all-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 12:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/god-the-all-2/</guid>
      <description>Let me know the need of renovation as well as of forgiveness, in order to serve and enjoy thee for ever. I come to thee in the all-prevailing name of Jesus, with nothing of my own to plead, no works, no worthiness, no promises.  &amp;#8211; from God the All
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God The All: The Author and Finisher of all the Good Work Within Me</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/god-the-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 14:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/god-the-all/</guid>
      <description>I know that thou art the author and finisher of faith, that the whole work of redemption is thine alone, that every good work or thought found in me is the effect of thy power and grace, that thy sole motive in working in me to will and to do is for thy good pleasure.  &amp;#8211; from God the All
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trinity</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-trinity/</guid>
      <description>O Father, I thank thee that in fullness of grace thou hast given me to Jesus, to be his sheep, jewel, portion; O Jesus, I thank thee that in fullness of grace thou hast accepted, espoused, bound me; O Holy Spirit, I thank thee that in fullness of grace thou hast exhibited Jesus as my salvation, implanted faith within me, subdued my stubborn heart, made me one with him for ever.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>