<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family Devotions on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/family-devotions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family Devotions on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 12:00:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/family-devotions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 10:46-52 God Alone Receives Those Who Cannot See Him</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1046-52-god-alone-receives-those-who-cannot-see-him/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1046-52-god-alone-receives-those-who-cannot-see-him/</guid>
      <description>Mark 10:46-52 And they came to Jericho. And as he was leaving Jericho with his disciples and a great crowd, Bartimaeus, a blind beggar, the son of Timaeus, was sitting by the roadside. And when he heard that it was Jesus of Nazareth, he began to cry out and say, “Jesus, Son of David, have mercy on me!” And many rebuked him, telling him to be silent. But he cried out all the more, “Son of David, have mercy on me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 10:32-45 God Alone Receives the Dead</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1032-45-god-alone-receives-the-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1032-45-god-alone-receives-the-dead/</guid>
      <description>Mark 10:32-34 And they were on the road, going up to Jerusalem, and Jesus was walking ahead of them. And they were amazed, and those who followed were afraid. And taking the twelve again, he began to tell them what was to happen to him, saying, “See, we are going up to Jerusalem, and the Son of Man will be delivered over to the chief priests and the scribes, and they will condemn him to death and deliver him over to the Gentiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 10:28-31 God Alone Receives the Last</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1028-31-god-alone-receives-the-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 12:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1028-31-god-alone-receives-the-last/</guid>
      <description>Mark 10:28-31 Peter began to say to him, “See, we have left everything and followed you.” Jesus said, “Truly, I say to you, there is no one who has left house or brothers or sisters or mother or father or children or lands, for my sake and for the gospel, who will not receive a hundredfold now in this time, houses and brothers and sisters and mothers and children and lands, with persecutions, and in the age to come eternal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 10:23-27 God Alone Receives the Outcasts</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1023-27-god-alone-receives-the-outcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 12:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1023-27-god-alone-receives-the-outcasts/</guid>
      <description>Mark 10:23-27 And Jesus looked around and said to his disciples, “How difficult it will be for those who have wealth to enter the kingdom of God!” And the disciples were amazed at his words. But Jesus said to them again, “Children, how difficult it is to enter the kingdom of God! It is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle than for a rich person to enter the kingdom of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 10:17-22 God Alone Receives the Brokenhearted</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1017-22-god-alone-receives-the-brokenhearted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 12:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1017-22-god-alone-receives-the-brokenhearted/</guid>
      <description>Mark 10:17-22 And as he was setting out on his journey, a man ran up and knelt before him and asked him, “Good Teacher, what must I do to inherit eternal life?” And Jesus said to him, “Why do you call me good? No one is good except God alone. You know the commandments: ‘Do not murder, Do not commit adultery, Do not steal, Do not bear false witness, Do not defraud, Honor your father and mother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 10:13-16: God Alone Receives the Fatherless</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1013-18-god-alone-receives-the-fatherless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1013-18-god-alone-receives-the-fatherless/</guid>
      <description>Mark 10:13-16 And they were bringing children to him that he might touch them, and the disciples rebuked them. But when Jesus saw it, he was indignant and said to them, “Let the children come to me; do not hinder them, for to such belongs the kingdom of God. Truly, I say to you, whoever does not receive the kingdom of God like a child shall not enter it.” And he took them in his arms and blessed them, laying his hands on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 10:1-12 God Alone Binds Us to One Another</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-101-12-god-alone-binds-us-to-one-another/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-101-12-god-alone-binds-us-to-one-another/</guid>
      <description>Mark 10:1–12 And he left there and went to the region of Judea and beyond the Jordan, and crowds gathered to him again. And again, as was his custom, he taught them. And Pharisees came up and in order to test him asked, “Is it lawful for a man to divorce his wife?” He answered them, “What did Moses command you?” They said, “Moses allowed a man to write a certificate of divorce and to send her away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 9:49-50 God Alone is Our Source</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-949-50-god-alone-is-our-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 12:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-949-50-god-alone-is-our-source/</guid>
      <description>Mark 9:49-50 For everyone will be salted with fire. Salt is good, but if the salt has lost its saltiness, how will you make it salty again? Have salt in yourselves, and be at peace with one another.&amp;#8221;  Who created us? What is our source of life? What does life look like when you are plugged into yourself versus being &amp;#8220;plugged&amp;#8221; into God? In other words, what are your thoughts like when you just think about yourself or focus on yourself or trying to figure out by yourself?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 9:43-49 God Alone Is Far Above Sin</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-943-49-god-alone-is-far-above-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-943-49-god-alone-is-far-above-sin/</guid>
      <description>Mark 9:43-48 And if your hand causes you to sin, cut it off. It is better for you to enter life crippled than with two hands to go to hell, to the unquenchable fire. And if your foot causes you to sin, cut it off. It is better for you to enter life lame than with two feet to be thrown into hell. And if your eye causes you to sin, tear it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 9:42  God Alone Is Strong</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-942-god-alone-is-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 12:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-942-god-alone-is-strong/</guid>
      <description>Mark 9:42 “Whoever causes one of these little ones who believe in me to sin, it would be better for him if a great millstone were hung around his neck and he were thrown into the sea.&amp;#8221;  How serious do you think Jesus is about teaching about Himself?
  Why do you think he was so serious about teaching his little ones? Are little ones weak or strong?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 9:38-41 God Alone Over All Who Would Believe In His Name</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-938-41-god-alone-over-all-who-would-believe-in-his-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 12:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-938-41-god-alone-over-all-who-would-believe-in-his-name/</guid>
      <description>Mark 9:38-41 John said to him, “Teacher, we saw someone casting out demons in your name, and we tried to stop him because he was not following us.” But Jesus said, “Do not stop him, for no one who does a mighty work in my name will be able soon afterward to speak evil of me. For the one who is not against us is for us. For truly, I say to you, whoever gives you a cup of water to drink because you belong to Christ will by no means lose his reward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 9:33-37 God Alone Receives All Who Would Come</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-933-37-god-alone-receives-all-who-would-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 12:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-933-37-god-alone-receives-all-who-would-come/</guid>
      <description>Mark 9:33-37 And they came to Capernaum. And when he was in the house he asked them, “What were you discussing on the way?” But they kept silent, for on the way they had argued with one another about who was the greatest. And he sat down and called the twelve. And he said to them, “If anyone would be first, he must be last of all and servant of all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 9:30-32 God Alone is Over Death</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-930-32-god-alone-is-over-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 12:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-930-32-god-alone-is-over-death/</guid>
      <description>Mark 9:30-32 They went on from there and passed through Galilee. And he did not want anyone to know, for he was teaching his disciples, saying to them, “The Son of Man is going to be delivered into the hands of men, and they will kill him. And when he is killed, after three days he will rise.” But they did not understand the saying, and were afraid to ask him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 9:14-29 God Alone is Over Life</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-914-29-god-alone-is-over-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 12:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-914-29-god-alone-is-over-life/</guid>
      <description>Mark 9:14–29 And when they came to the disciples, they saw a great crowd around them, and scribes arguing with them. And immediately all the crowd, when they saw him, were greatly amazed and ran up to him and greeted him. And he asked them, “What are you arguing about with them?” And someone from the crowd answered him, “Teacher, I brought my son to you, for he has a spirit that makes him mute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 9:2-13 Jesus Must Suffer</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-92-13-jesus-must-suffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-92-13-jesus-must-suffer/</guid>
      <description>Mark 9:2-13 And after six days Jesus took with him Peter and James and John, and led them up a high mountain by themselves. And he was transfigured before them, and his clothes became radiant, intensely white, as no one on earth could bleach them. And there appeared to them Elijah with Moses, and they were talking with Jesus. And Peter said to Jesus, “Rabbi, it is good that we are here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 8:34-9:1 We Must Die</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-834-91-we-must-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-834-91-we-must-die/</guid>
      <description>Mark 8:34-9:1 And calling the crowd to him with his disciples, he said to them, “If anyone would come after me, let him deny himself and take up his cross and follow me. For whoever would save his life will lose it, but whoever loses his life for my sake and the gospel&amp;#8217;s will save it. For what does it profit a man to gain the whole world and forfeit his soul?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 8:31-33 Jesus Must Die</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-831-33-jesus-must-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-831-33-jesus-must-die/</guid>
      <description>Mark 8:31-33 And he began to teach them that the Son of Man must suffer many things and be rejected by the elders and the chief priests and the scribes and be killed, and after three days rise again. And he said this plainly. And Peter took him aside and began to rebuke him. But turning and seeing his disciples, he rebuked Peter and said, “Get behind me, Satan! For you are not setting your mind on the things of God, but on the things of man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 8:27–30 Jesus Opens the Only Way to God Because He is the Only Way to God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-827-30-jesus-opens-the-only-way-to-god-because-he-is-the-only-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-827-30-jesus-opens-the-only-way-to-god-because-he-is-the-only-way/</guid>
      <description>Mark 8:27–30 And Jesus went on with his disciples to the villages of Caesarea Philippi. And on the way he asked his disciples, “Who do people say that I am?” And they told him, “John the Baptist; and others say, Elijah; and others, one of the prophets.” And he asked them, “But who do you say that I am?” Peter answered him, “You are the Christ.” And he strictly charged them to tell no one about him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 8:22–26 Jesus Opens Our Eyes So That We Would See God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-822-26-jesus-opens-our-eyes-so-that-we-would-see-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 12:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-822-26-jesus-opens-our-eyes-so-that-we-would-see-god/</guid>
      <description>Mark 8:22–26 And they came to Bethsaida. And some people brought to him a blind man and begged him to touch him. And he took the blind man by the hand and led him out of the village, and when he had spit on his eyes and laid his hands on him, he asked him, “Do you see anything?” And he looked up and said, “I see people, but they look like trees, walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His Banner Over Me Is Love</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/his-banner-over-me-is-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 23:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/his-banner-over-me-is-love/</guid>
      <description>Series: Once a month, I get to teach the Elementary kids during our main Worship Gatherings. My incredible Children&amp;#8217;s Pastor, Kim, does the amazing work of feeding me that weekend&amp;#8217;s lesson, much like a lectionary. There will be a power verse, the lesson (or the reading) and then the accompanied Bible passage. Quite often, God will linked everything together to His Son and to His gospel which I am to believe the Scriptures (1 Corinthians 2:12) is through the power of the Holy Spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 8:14–21 Jesus Opens Our Hearts So That We Might Receive God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-814-21-jesus-opens-our-hearts-so-that-we-might-receive-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 17:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-814-21-jesus-opens-our-hearts-so-that-we-might-receive-god/</guid>
      <description>Mark 8:14–21 Now they had forgotten to bring bread, and they had only one loaf with them in the boat. And he cautioned them, saying, “Watch out; beware of the leaven of the Pharisees and the leaven of Herod.” And they began discussing with one another the fact that they had no bread. And Jesus, aware of this, said to them, “Why are you discussing the fact that you have no bread?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 8:11–13 Jesus Opens Our Minds So We Now Understand God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-811-13-jesus-opens-our-minds-so-we-now-understand-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 12:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-811-13-jesus-opens-our-minds-so-we-now-understand-god/</guid>
      <description>Mark 8:11–13 The Pharisees came and began to argue with him, seeking from him a sign from heaven to test him. And he sighed deeply in his spirit and said, “Why does this generation seek a sign? Truly, I say to you, no sign will be given to this generation.” And he left them, got into the boat again, and went to the other side.
Luke 24:44-49 Then he said to them, “These are my words that I spoke to you while I was still with you, that everything written about me in the Law of Moses and the Prophets and the Psalms must be fulfilled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 8:1-10 Jesus Opens Up Our Mouths So That We May Now Be Fed by God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-81-10-jesus-opens-up-our-mouths-so-that-we-may-now-be-fed-by-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-81-10-jesus-opens-up-our-mouths-so-that-we-may-now-be-fed-by-god/</guid>
      <description>Mark 8:1–10 In those days, when again a great crowd had gathered, and they had nothing to eat, he called his disciples to him and said to them, “I have compassion on the crowd, because they have been with me now three days and have nothing to eat. And if I send them away hungry to their homes, they will faint on the way. And some of them have come from far away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 7:31-37 Jesus Opens Our Ears So We Now Hear God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-731-37-jesus-opens-our-ears-so-we-now-hear-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-731-37-jesus-opens-our-ears-so-we-now-hear-god/</guid>
      <description>Mark 7:31-37 Then he returned from the region of Tyre and went through Sidon to the Sea of Galilee, in the region of the Decapolis. And they brought to him a man who was deaf and had a speech impediment, and they begged him to lay his hand on him. And taking him aside from the crowd privately, he put his fingers into his ears, and after spitting touched his tongue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 7:24-30 The Word of God Saves</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-724-30-the-word-of-god-saves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-724-30-the-word-of-god-saves/</guid>
      <description>Mark 7:24-30 And from there he arose and went away to the region of Tyre and Sidon. And he entered a house and did not want anyone to know, yet he could not be hidden. But immediately a woman whose little daughter had an unclean spirit heard of him and came and fell down at his feet. Now the woman was a Gentile, a Syrophoenician by birth. And she begged him to cast the demon out of her daughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 7:14-23 The Word of God is Righteousness</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-714-23-the-word-of-god-is-righteousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-714-23-the-word-of-god-is-righteousness/</guid>
      <description>Mark 7:14-23
And he called the people to him again and said to them, “Hear me, all of you, and understand: There is nothing outside a person that by going into him can defile him, but the things that come out of a person are what defile him.” And when he had entered the house and left the people, his disciples asked him about the parable. And he said to them, “Then are you also without understanding?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 7:7-13 The Word of God is First</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-77-13-the-word-of-god-is-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 12:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-77-13-the-word-of-god-is-first/</guid>
      <description>Mark 7:7-13  &amp;#8230; in vain do they worship me, teaching as doctrines the commandments of men.’ You leave the commandment of God and hold to the tradition of men.”  And he said to them, “You have a fine way of rejecting the commandment of God in order to establish your tradition! For Moses said, ‘Honor your father and your mother’; and, ‘Whoever reviles father or mother must surely die.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Legacy of Leading Your Family in Devotions</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/the-legacy-of-leading-your-family-in-devotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 19:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/the-legacy-of-leading-your-family-in-devotions/</guid>
      <description>By God&amp;#8217;s grace, I heard this wonderful message shortly before I got married. When I first heard it, I got what Dr. Beeke was laying out but it seems to be too much. However, when I started a new family, it became crystal clear what I needed to do and that same weight became glorious. (2 Corinthians 4:17-18)
You don&amp;#8217;t have to perfectly subscribe to what Dr. Beeke advised here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devotions in Mark: An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>I still remember our first night of devotions. I was a brand new stepdad and barely getting to know my four new bonus kids, whom I loved so much. I was quite nervous because I had no clue how my kids would receive God&amp;#8217;s words. I prayed and God reminded me that He sends out His Word according to Isaiah 55:10-11. His Spirit through His Word gave me peace.
Now, it was time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devotions in Mark: A Few Resources</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-a-few-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-a-few-resources/</guid>
      <description>Here just the very small list of resources on Mark that I have found most helpful.
The Bible &amp;#8211; Should go without say. However, many times, many teachers, preachers, and small group leaders (myself included) will &amp;#8220;cut straight to the chase&amp;#8221; and engage the commentary instead of engaging the Word of God. Remember, the commentaries are not without error—they are the observations of the author. Slow down, pray, read, chew and meditate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids’ Spiritual Well-Being For ‘the Sake of the Gospel’?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/kids-spiritual-well-belng-for-the-sake-of-the-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/kids-spiritual-well-belng-for-the-sake-of-the-gospel/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;I sometimes wonder, my dear friends, if one of the questions—if one of the first questions—God would ask me at the day of judgment, as He assesses my life, is not going to be, &amp;#8216;How well did you preach?&amp;#8217; but &amp;#8216;What kind of father were you?&amp;#8217; &amp;#8216;How faithful were you to the charges I gave you?&amp;#8217;. That&amp;#8217;s your first ministry, isn&amp;#8217;t it? Not to be using your gifts here and there, in the church, here and there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 1:1 Jesus is the Good News</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1-1-jesus-is-the-good-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-1-1-jesus-is-the-good-news/</guid>
      <description>Mark 1:1 The beginning of the gospel of Jesus Christ, the Son of God.
****Lets go through this grand introduction, idea by idea.
The beginning
Who wrote Mark?
Who is Mark
Mark is said to be the writer for Peter
What does Mark write about?
Mark testifies about Christ Jesus
Each of the Gospels tells a different perspective about Jesus:
Matthew &amp;#8211; Jesus is King (Lion of Judah)
Mark &amp;#8211; Jesus is Servant (The Ox)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 1:12-13 Jesus is Led by the Holy Spirit</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-112-13-jesus-is-lead-by-the-holy-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-112-13-jesus-is-lead-by-the-holy-spirit/</guid>
      <description>Mark 1:12-13 The Spirit immediately drove him out into the wilderness. And he was in the wilderness forty days, being tempted by Satan. And he was with the wild animals, and the angels were ministering to him.
Was Jesus human?
Was Jesus the Son of God?
Did Jesus have in him, the Spirit of God?
Do we have the Spirit of God?
Are we sons and daughters of God?
Romans 8:14 For all who are led by the Spirit of God are sons of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 1:14-15 Jesus Is The Good News Pt. 2</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-114-15-jesus-is-the-good-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-114-15-jesus-is-the-good-news/</guid>
      <description>**Mark 1:14-15 Now after John was arrested, Jesus came into Galilee, proclaiming the gospel of God, and saying, “The time is fulfilled, and the kingdom of God is at hand; repent and believe in the gospel.”
**
1. Is the kingdom of God right here, right now?
What is the kingdom of God? Is it like a country like the United States—does it have a location? Does it include all of the earth, all of heaven and all of outer space?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 1:16-20 Jesus Calls Out</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-116-20-jesus-calls-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-116-20-jesus-calls-out/</guid>
      <description>Mark 1:16-20 Passing alongside the Sea of Galilee, he saw Simon and Andrew the brother of Simon casting a net into the sea, for they were fishermen. And Jesus said to them, “Follow me, and I will make you become fishers of men.” And immediately they left their nets and followed him. And going on a little farther, he saw James the son of Zebedee and John his brother, who were in their boat mending the nets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 1:2-3 Jesus Will Be Here Soon</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-12-3-jesus-will-be-here-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-12-3-jesus-will-be-here-soon/</guid>
      <description>**Mark 1:2-3 As it is written in Isaiah the prophet,
“Behold, I send my messenger before your face,
who will prepare your way,
the voice of one crying in the wilderness:
‘Prepare the way of the Lord,
make his paths straight,’”**
500 years before Jesus came as a little baby, the entire Old Testament spoke of Jesus Christ.
Jesus said it himself:
And beginning with Moses and all the Prophets, Christ interpreted to them in all the Scriptures the things concerning himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 1:21-28 Jesus Rules and Reigns Over Satan and Demons</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-121-28-jesus-rules-and-reigns-over-satan-and-demons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-121-28-jesus-rules-and-reigns-over-satan-and-demons/</guid>
      <description>Mark 1:21-28 And they went into Capernaum, and immediately on the Sabbath he entered the synagogue and was teaching. And they were astonished at his teaching, for he taught them as one who had authority, and not as the scribes.
Be confident in God&amp;#8217;s Word. If the Bible says it, it is as good as gold. It is as good as done. (See 2 Timothy 3:16-17)
And immediately there was in their synagogue a man with an unclean spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 1:29-34 Jesus Heals the Sick</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-129-34-jesus-heals-the-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-129-34-jesus-heals-the-sick/</guid>
      <description>Mark 1:29-34 And immediately he left the synagogue and entered the house of Simon and Andrew, with James and John. Now Simon&amp;#8217;s mother-in-law lay ill with a fever, and immediately they told him about her. And he came and took her by the hand and lifted her up, and the fever left her, and she began to serve them.
That evening at sundown they brought to him all who were sick or oppressed by demons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 1:35-39 Jesus Prayed</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-135-39-jesus-prayed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-135-39-jesus-prayed/</guid>
      <description>Mark 1:35-39 And rising very early in the morning, while it was still dark, he departed and went out to a desolate place, and there he prayed. And Simon and those who were with him searched for him, and they found him and said to him, “Everyone is looking for you.” And he said to them, “Let us go on to the next towns, that I may preach there also, for that is why I came out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 1:4-7 Jesus Baptizes With the Holy Spirit</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-14-11-jesus-baptizes-with-holy-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-14-11-jesus-baptizes-with-holy-spirit/</guid>
      <description>Mark 1:4-7 John appeared, baptizing in the wilderness and proclaiming a baptism of repentance for the forgiveness of sins. And all the country of Judea and all Jerusalem were going out to him and were being baptized by him in the river Jordan, confessing their sins. Now John was clothed with camel&amp;#8217;s hair and wore a leather belt around his waist and ate locusts and wild honey. And he preached, saying, “After me comes he who is mightier than I, the strap of whose sandals I am not worthy to stoop down and untie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 1:40-45 Jesus Will Never Reject Us</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-140-45-jesus-will-never-reject-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-140-45-jesus-will-never-reject-us/</guid>
      <description>Mark 1:40-45 And a leper came to him, imploring him, and kneeling said to him, “If you will, you can make me clean.” Moved with pity, he stretched out his hand and touched him and said to him, “I will; be clean.” And immediately the leprosy left him, and he was made clean. And Jesus sternly charged him and sent him away at once, and said to him, “See that you say nothing to anyone, but go, show yourself to the priest and offer for your cleansing what Moses commanded, for a proof to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 1:9-11 God is Three in One Not Three</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-19-11-god-is-three-in-one-not-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-19-11-god-is-three-in-one-not-three/</guid>
      <description>Mark 1:9-11 In those days Jesus came from Nazareth of Galilee and was baptized by John in the Jordan. And when he came up out of the water, immediately he saw the heavens being torn open and the Spirit descending on him like a dove. And a voice came from heaven, “You are my beloved Son; with you I am well pleased.”
How many people were here with John?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 2:1-12 Jesus Forgives Our Sins</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-21-12-jesus-forgives-our-sins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-21-12-jesus-forgives-our-sins/</guid>
      <description>Mark 2:1-12 And when he returned to Capernaum after some days, it was reported that he was at home. And many were gathered together, so that there was no more room, not even at the door. And he was preaching the word to them. And they came, bringing to him a paralytic carried by four men. And when they could not get near him because of the crowd, they removed the roof above him, and when they had made an opening, they let down the bed on which the paralytic lay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 2:13-17 Jesus is the Good Doctor</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-213-17-jesus-is-the-good-doctor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-213-17-jesus-is-the-good-doctor/</guid>
      <description>Mark 2:13-17 He went out again beside the sea, and all the crowd was coming to him, and he was teaching them. And as he passed by, he saw Levi the son of Alphaeus sitting at the tax booth, and he said to him, “Follow me.” And he rose and followed him. And as he reclined at table in his house, many tax collectors and sinners were reclining with Jesus and his disciples, for there were many who followed him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 2:18-22 Jesus is the Bridegroom</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-218-22-jesus-is-the-bridegroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-218-22-jesus-is-the-bridegroom/</guid>
      <description>Mark 2:18-22 ESV Now John&amp;#8217;s disciples and the Pharisees were fasting. And people came and said to him, “Why do John&amp;#8217;s disciples and the disciples of the Pharisees fast, but your disciples do not fast?” And Jesus said to them, “Can the wedding guests fast while the bridegroom is with them? As long as they have the bridegroom with them, they cannot fast. The days will come when the bridegroom is taken away from them, and then they will fast in that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 2:23-28 Jesus is Our Rest</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/13-mark-223-28-jesus-is-our-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/13-mark-223-28-jesus-is-our-rest/</guid>
      <description>Mark 2:23-28 One Sabbath he was going through the grainfields, and as they made their way, his disciples began to pluck heads of grain. And the Pharisees were saying to him, “Look, why are they doing what is not lawful on the Sabbath?” And he said to them, “Have you never read what David did, when he was in need and was hungry, he and those who were with him: how he entered the house of God, in the time of Abiathar the high priest, and ate the bread of the Presence, which it is not lawful for any but the priests to eat, and also gave it to those who were with him?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 3:1-6 Jesus Softens Hearts</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-31-6-jesus-softens-hearts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-31-6-jesus-softens-hearts/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean to harden your heart?
Pharaoh hardened his heart.
Exodus 7:13, 22; 8:15, 19, 32; 9:7, 34-35;
I will harden his heart.
Exodus 7:14; 9:12, 34-34; 10:1, 20, 27; 11:10; 14:8
I have harden his heart.
For the Scripture says to Pharaoh, “For this very purpose I have raised you up, that I might show my power in you, and that my name might be proclaimed in all the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 3:22-27 Christ is Stronger</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-322-27-christ-is-stronger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-322-27-christ-is-stronger/</guid>
      <description>Mark 3:22-27 And the scribes who came down from Jerusalem were saying, “He is possessed by Beelzebul,” and “by the prince of demons he casts out the demons.” And he called them to him and said to them in parables, “How can Satan cast out Satan? If a kingdom is divided against itself, that kingdom cannot stand. And if a house is divided against itself, that house will not be able to stand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 3:28-30 Listen to the Holy Spirit</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-328-30-listen-to-the-holy-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-328-30-listen-to-the-holy-spirit/</guid>
      <description>Mark 3:28-30 “Truly, I say to you, all sins will be forgiven the children of man, and whatever blasphemies they utter, but whoever blasphemes against the Holy Spirit never has forgiveness, but is guilty of an eternal sin”—for they were saying, “He has an unclean spirit.” 
What is blasphemy?
Saying that God is something not when He is (i.e. goodness, faithfulness, just, loving, etc.) or saying that God is something when he is not (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 3:31-35 Jesus is Family</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-331-35-jesus-is-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-331-35-jesus-is-family/</guid>
      <description>Mark 3:31-35 And his mother and his brothers came, and standing outside they sent to him and called him. And a crowd was sitting around him, and they said to him, “Your mother and your brothers are outside, seeking you.” And he answered them, “Who are my mother and my brothers?” And looking about at those who sat around him, he said, “Here are my mother and my brothers! For whoever does the will of God, he is my brother and sister and mother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 3:6-21 Jesus is on Mission from the Father</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-36-21-jesus-is-on-mission-from-the-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-36-21-jesus-is-on-mission-from-the-father/</guid>
      <description>_People wanted to kill Christ_
 The Pharisees went out and immediately held counsel with the Herodians against him, how to destroy him.
&amp;#8230; but fail and fail again because Christ is life.
&amp;nbsp;
People wanted to make him king because he makes food &amp;#8220;magically&amp;#8221;
 Jesus withdrew with his disciples to the sea, and a great crowd followed, from Galilee and Judea and Jerusalem and Idumea and from beyond the Jordan and from around Tyre and Sidon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 4:1-9 Jesus Teaches, How Do We Respond?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-41-9-jesus-teaches-how-do-we-respond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-41-9-jesus-teaches-how-do-we-respond/</guid>
      <description>Mark 4:1-9 Again he began to teach beside the sea. And a very large crowd gathered about him, so that he got into a boat and sat in it on the sea, and the whole crowd was beside the sea on the land. And he was teaching them many things in parables, and in his teaching he said to them: “Listen! Behold, a sower went out to sow. And as he sowed, some seed fell along the path, and the birds came and devoured it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 4:10-13 Jesus Helps Us to Understand, See, Hear, Feel, and Know God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-410-13-jesus-helps-us-to-understand-see-hear-feel-and-know-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-410-13-jesus-helps-us-to-understand-see-hear-feel-and-know-god/</guid>
      <description>Mark 4:10-13 **And when he was alone, those around him with the twelve asked him about the parables. And he said to them, “To you has been given the secret of the kingdom of God, but for those outside everything is in parables, so that
“they may indeed see but not perceive,
and may indeed hear but not understand,
lest they should turn and be forgiven.”
And he said to them, “Do you not understand this parable?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 4:13-20 Jesus Sows, We Grow</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-413-20-jesus-sows-we-grow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-413-20-jesus-sows-we-grow/</guid>
      <description>Mark 4:13-20 And he said to them, “Do you not understand this parable? How then will you understand all the parables?
The sower sows the word. And these are the ones along the path, where the word is sown: when they hear, Satan immediately comes and takes away the word that is sown in them. And these are the ones sown on rocky ground: the ones who, when they hear the word, immediately receive it with joy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 4:21-22 Jesus is the Light</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-421-22-jesus-is-the-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-421-22-jesus-is-the-light/</guid>
      <description>Mark 4:21-25 And he said to them, “Is a lamp brought in to be put under a basket, or under a bed, and not on a stand? For nothing is hidden except to be made manifest; nor is anything secret except to come to light.
John 1:1-13 In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. He was in the beginning with God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 4:23-25 Jesus Gives More, Do We Receive?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-423-25-jesus-gives-more-do-we-receive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-423-25-jesus-gives-more-do-we-receive/</guid>
      <description>[][1]McFarland Trout. Photo by Courtney Michalik Mark 4:23-25 If anyone has ears to hear, let him hear.” And he said to them, “Pay attention to what you hear: with the measure you use, it will be measured to you, and still more will be added to you. For to the one who has, more will be given, and from the one who has not, even what he has will be taken away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 4:26-29 Jesus Loves; Jesus Obeys</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-426-29-jesus-loves-jesus-obeys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-426-29-jesus-loves-jesus-obeys/</guid>
      <description>Mark 4:26-29 And he said, “The kingdom of God is as if a man should scatter seed on the ground. He sleeps and rises night and day, and the seed sprouts and grows; he knows not how. The earth produces by itself, first the blade, then the ear, then the full grain in the ear. But when the grain is ripe, at once he puts in the sickle, because the harvest has come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 4:30-32 Jesus Builds His Kingdom</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-430-32-jesus-builds-his-kingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-430-32-jesus-builds-his-kingdom/</guid>
      <description>Mark 4:30-32 And he said, “With what can we compare the kingdom of God, or what parable shall we use for it? It is like a grain of mustard seed, which, when sown on the ground, is the smallest of all the seeds on earth, yet when it is sown it grows up and becomes larger than all the garden plants and puts out large branches, so that the birds of the air can make nests in its shade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 4:33-34 Jesus Teaches</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-433-34-jesus-teaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-433-34-jesus-teaches/</guid>
      <description>Mark 4:33-34 With many such parables he spoke the word to them, as they were able to hear it. He did not speak to them without a parable, but privately to his own disciples he explained everything.
We have already spoken on how Jesus taught.
What is a parable?
A little story to tell us something bigger.
How did Jesus use parables?
He used to teach bigger crowds.
Did he always explained what the parable meant?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 4:35-41 Jesus Is Lord Over The Storm</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-435-41-jesus-is-lord-over-the-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-435-41-jesus-is-lord-over-the-storm/</guid>
      <description>Mark 4:35-41 On that day, when evening had come, he said to them, “Let us go across to the other side.” And leaving the crowd, they took him with them in the boat, just as he was. And other boats were with him. And a great windstorm arose, and the waves were breaking into the boat, so that the boat was already filling. But he was in the stern, asleep on the cushion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 5:1-13 Jesus Rules &amp; Reigns Over Satan and Demons, Pt 2</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-51-13-jesus-rules-reigns-over-satan-and-demons-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-51-13-jesus-rules-reigns-over-satan-and-demons-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>Mark 5:1-13 They came to the other side of the sea, to the country of the Gerasenes. And when Jesus had stepped out of the boat, immediately there met him out of the tombs a man with an unclean spirit. He lived among the tombs. And no one could bind him anymore, not even with a chain, for he had often been bound with shackles and chains, but he wrenched the chains apart, and he broke the shackles in pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 5:14-20 Jesus Commissions Us to Tell The Good News, Pt 1</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-514-20-jesus-commissions-us-to-tell-the-good-news-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-514-20-jesus-commissions-us-to-tell-the-good-news-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>Mark 5:14-20 The herdsmen fled and told it in the city and in the country. And people came to see what it was that had happened. And they came to Jesus and saw the demon-possessed man, the one who had had the legion, sitting there, clothed and in his right mind, and they were afraid. And those who had seen it described to them what had happened to the demon-possessed man and to the pigs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 5:21-24 Jesus Hears Our Cries</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-521-24-jesus-hears-our-cries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-521-24-jesus-hears-our-cries/</guid>
      <description>[][1]Raising of the Daughter of Jairus by Paolo Veronese Mark 5:21-24 And when Jesus had crossed again in the boat to the other side, a great crowd gathered about him, and he was beside the sea. Then came one of the rulers of the synagogue, Jairus by name, and seeing him, he fell at his feet and implored him earnestly, saying, “My little daughter is at the point of death. Come and lay your hands on her, so that she may be made well and live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 5:25-34 Jesus Has The Power Over Disease</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-525-34-jesus-has-the-power-over-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-525-34-jesus-has-the-power-over-disease/</guid>
      <description>Mark 5:24-34 And a great crowd followed him and thronged about him. And there was a woman who had had a discharge of blood for twelve years, and who had suffered much under many physicians, and had spent all that she had, and was no better but rather grew worse. She had heard the reports about Jesus and came up behind him in the crowd and touched his garment. For she said, “If I touch even his garments, I will be made well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 5:35-43 Jesus Has the Power Over Death</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-535-43-jesus-has-the-power-over-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-535-43-jesus-has-the-power-over-death/</guid>
      <description>Mark 5:35-43 While he was still speaking, there came from the ruler&amp;#8217;s house some who said, “Your daughter is dead. Why trouble the Teacher any further?” But overhearing what they said, Jesus said to the ruler of the synagogue, “Do not fear, only believe.” And he allowed no one to follow him except Peter and James and John the brother of James. They came to the house of the ruler of the synagogue, and Jesus saw a commotion, people weeping and wailing loudly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 6:1-6 Jesus Is Human and Yet, More Than Human</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-61-6-jesus-is-human-and-yet-more-than-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-61-6-jesus-is-human-and-yet-more-than-human/</guid>
      <description>Mark 6:1-6 He went away from there and came to his hometown, and his disciples followed him. And on the Sabbath he began to teach in the synagogue, and many who heard him were astonished, saying, “Where did this man get these things? What is the wisdom given to him? How are such mighty works done by his hands? Is not this the carpenter, the son of Mary and brother of James and Joses and Judas and Simon?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 6:14-16 Jesus and John Are Not The Same</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-614-16-jesus-and-john-are-not-the-same/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-614-16-jesus-and-john-are-not-the-same/</guid>
      <description>Mark 6:14-29 King Herod heard of it, for Jesus&amp;#8217; name had become known. Some said, “John the Baptist has been raised from the dead. That is why these miraculous powers are at work in him.” But others said, “He is Elijah.” And others said, “He is a prophet, like one of the prophets of old.” But when Herod heard of it, he said, “John, whom I beheaded, has been raised.”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 6:17-29 Jesus’ Cousin Dies</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-617-29-jesus-cousin-dies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-617-29-jesus-cousin-dies/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Salome with the Head of John the Baptist&amp;#8221; by Caravaggio Mark 6:17-29 For it was Herod who had sent and seized John and bound him in prison for the sake of Herodias, his brother Philip&amp;#8217;s wife, because he had married her. For John had been saying to Herod, “It is not lawful for you to have your brother&amp;#8217;s wife.” And Herodias had a grudge against him and wanted to put him to death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 6:30-44 Pt. 1 Jesus is the Giver of Life</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-630-44-pt-1-jesus-is-the-giver-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-630-44-pt-1-jesus-is-the-giver-of-life/</guid>
      <description>Mark 6:30-44 The apostles returned to Jesus and told him all that they had done and taught. And he said to them, “Come away by yourselves to a desolate place and rest a while.” For many were coming and going, and they had no leisure even to eat. And they went away in the boat to a desolate place by themselves. Now many saw them going and recognized them, and they ran there on foot from all the towns and got there ahead of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 6:30-44 Pt. 2 Jesus is the Bread of Life</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-630-44-pt-2-jesus-is-the-bread-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-630-44-pt-2-jesus-is-the-bread-of-life/</guid>
      <description>1. In the feeding of the five thousand, what was the purpose of the story?
Check and see what Apostle John says about this account:
When they found him on the other side of the sea, they said to him, “Rabbi, when did you come here?” Jesus answered them, “Truly, truly, I say to you, you are seeking me, not because you saw signs, but because you ate your fill of the loaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 6:45-52 Jesus is the Lord of Glory</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-645-52-jesus-is-the-lord-of-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-645-52-jesus-is-the-lord-of-glory/</guid>
      <description>1. We know that Jesus is God and Lord. But what does it mean to be the &amp;#8216;Lord&amp;#8217; over something?     
 2. When Jesus took just a little bread and fishes and fed thousands, Jesus would be the Lord over what? What about when he calmed a storm after taking a nap? How about when he raised that girl from the dead?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 6:53-56 The Word of God is Life</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-653-56-the-word-of-god-is-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-653-56-the-word-of-god-is-life/</guid>
      <description>1. When we hardened our hearts against God&amp;#8217;s love (we refuse to hear what God has to say, we refuse to believe what God has done), does God still love us?
2. When we hardened our hearts against God (mad at him, accuse him of being bad), does God still shows us his love?
Mark 6:53-56 When they had crossed over, they came to land at Gennesaret and moored to the shore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 6:7-13 Jesus Sends Us Out</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-67-13-jesus-sends-us-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-67-13-jesus-sends-us-out/</guid>
      <description>Mark 6:7-13 And he called the twelve and began to send them out two by two, and gave them authority over the unclean spirits. He charged them to take nothing for their journey except a staff—no bread, no bag, no money in their belts—but to wear sandals and not put on two tunics. And he said to them, “Whenever you enter a house, stay there until you depart from there. And if any place will not receive you and they will not listen to you, when you leave, shake off the dust that is on your feet as a testimony against them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark 7:1-7 The Word of God is Love</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-71-7-the-word-of-god-is-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/mark-71-7-the-word-of-god-is-love/</guid>
      <description>Mark 7:1-6 Now when the Pharisees gathered to him, with some of the scribes who had come from Jerusalem, they saw that some of his disciples ate with hands that were defiled, that is, unwashed. (For the Pharisees and all the Jews do not eat unless they wash their hands properly, holding to the tradition of the elders, and when they come from the marketplace, they do not eat unless they wash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not-so-smooth Transitions</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/not-so-smooth-transitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/not-so-smooth-transitions/</guid>
      <description>If you ever led small group discussions or family devotions, you know that sometimes there is no smooth way to go into devotions.
Like tonight: our family was having a robust discussion on dinosaurs. In my mind, I knew we would have no other opportunities to do devotions. This is how I transitioned into devotion time:
Me: NO ONE MAKE A MOVE. STAY IN YOUR SEAT. IT&amp;#8217;S&amp;#8230;
Kids: DEVOTION TIME!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>