<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fear and Trembling on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/fear-and-trembling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fear and Trembling on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/fear-and-trembling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Believe, and Believe for Your Life!</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/believe-and-believe-for-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/believe-and-believe-for-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;That sad and yet blissful hour when Abraham was to take leave of all that was dear to him, when yet once more he was to lift up his head, when his countenance would shine like that of the Lord, when he would concentrate his whole soul in a blessing which was potent to make Isaac blessed all his days–this time would not come! For he would indeed take leave of Isaac, but in such a way that he himself would remain behind; death would separate them, but in such a way that Isaac remained its prey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing In Midair</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/dancing-in-mid-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/dancing-in-mid-air/</guid>
      <description>On those who possess actual faith in God:
&amp;#8220;It is supposed to be the most difficult task for a dancer to leap into a definite posture in such a way that there is not a second when he is grasping after the posture, but by the leap itself he stands fixed in that posture. Perhaps no dancer can do it–that is what this knight does. Most people live dejectedly in worldly sorrow and joy; they are the ones who sit along the wall and do not join in the dance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Cannot Close My Eyes To This Leap of Faith</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/i-cannot-close-my-eyes-to-this-leap-of-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/i-cannot-close-my-eyes-to-this-leap-of-faith/</guid>
      <description>I have seen the dreadful before my own eyes, I do not flee from it timorously, but I know very well that, although I advance to meet it, my courage is not the courage of faith, nor anything comparable to it. I am unable to make the movements of faith, I cannot shut my eyes and plunge confidently into the absurd, for me that is an impossibility … but I do not boast of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Would’ve Been Too Scared</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/i-wouldve-been-too-scared/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/i-wouldve-been-too-scared/</guid>
      <description>But what did Abraham do? He arrived neither too soon nor too late. He mounted the ass, he rode slowly along the way. All that time he believed–he believed that God would not require Isaac of him, whereas he was willing nevertheless to sacrifice him if it was required. He believed by virtue of the absurd; for there could be no question of human calculation, and it was indeed the absurd that God who required it of him should the next instant recall the requirement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Faith Knowing What’s Going To Happen?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/is-faith-knowing-whats-going-to-happen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/is-faith-knowing-whats-going-to-happen/</guid>
      <description>Upon this pinnacle stands Abraham. The last stage he loses sight of is the infinite resignation. He really goes further, and reaches faith; for all these caricatures of faith, the miserable lukewarm indolence which thinks, &amp;#8220;There surely is no instant need, it is not worth while sorrowing before the time,&amp;#8221; the pitiful hope which says, &amp;#8220;One cannot know what is going to happen … it might possibly be after all&amp;#8221;–these caricatures of faith are part and parcel of life&amp;#8217;s wretchedness, and the infinite resignation has already consigned them to infinite contempt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laughable, Still An Heir</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/laughable-still-an-heir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/laughable-still-an-heir/</guid>
      <description>Abraham became old, Sarah became a laughingstock in the land, and yet he was God&amp;#8217;s elect and inheritor of the promise that in his seed all the races of the world would be blessed.
 Søren Kierkegaard. Fear and Trembling, 2012. Kindle 140.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loving God But Not Believing God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/loving-god-but-not-believing-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/loving-god-but-not-believing-god/</guid>
      <description>If this had not been the case with Abraham, then perhaps he might have loved God but not believed; for he who loves God without faith reflects upon himself, he who loves God believingly reflects upon God.
 Søren Kierkegaard. Fear and Trembling, 2012. Kindle 385.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>