<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Influences: Bible on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/tags/influences-bible/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Influences: Bible on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/tags/influences-bible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence: Genesis</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/theology/influence-genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/theology/influence-genesis/</guid>
      <description>Nine times out of ten, every other story not in Genesis can be traced back to Genesis. (I logically suspect that that other one time is simply because I am a novice scholar.)
Forgive me as I do this off the top of my noggin but if I am not mistaken, all Biblical doctrines originates in Genesis in a very direct way. 1{#return-note-1105-1.simple-footnote}
Doctrine of creation: Genesis 1 &amp;amp; 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Jeremiah</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-jeremiah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-jeremiah/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet Jeremiah by Michelangelo BuonarrotiIn and around April 2007, I was saved. In and around May 2007, it occurs to me that I should start reading the Bible. I prayed and I felt like I should start with Jeremiah.
Every since reading Jeremiah, there were four truths that did a number on my freshly renewed mind (oddly enough, Jeremiah 29:11 was not one of them):
 God appoints us to Him before we were born:  Jeremiah 1:4-8 Now the word of the Lord came to me, saying,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Ruth</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-ruth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-ruth/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I was given the opportunity to lead a Bible Study. The very first book we studied through was the book of Ruth. Verse by verse. Chapter by chapter.
Given our group consisted of young adults, most of them were single, it was easy to quickly identify with, or want to be identified with, each of the key figures in this little story in the Bible.
Feeling like a stranger in a strange land.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>