<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ordo Salutis on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/ordo-salutis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ordo Salutis on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 12:00:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/ordo-salutis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis XII: Our New Body – Spirit’s Power in Our Glorification</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/our-new-body-spirits-power-in-our-glorification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/our-new-body-spirits-power-in-our-glorification/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 97:9 For you, O LORD,
are most high over all the earth;
you are exalted far above all gods.  And how can we even fathom this glory of God? How can we fully look upon God in his sheer radiance, beauty, and majesty without our minds and eyes and hearts shutting down? It is sheer madness. And that is exactly what God wants! He wants to be with him forever and ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis XI: Our New Lives – Spirit’s Work In Our Sanctification</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-xi-our-new-lives-spirits-work-in-our-sanctification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 12:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-xi-our-new-lives-spirits-work-in-our-sanctification/</guid>
      <description>Isaiah 48:9–11 “For my name’s sake I defer my anger;
for the sake of my praise I restrain it for you,
that I may not cut you off.
 Behold, I have refined you, but not as silver;
I have tried you in the furnace of affliction.
 For my own sake, for my own sake, I do it,
for how should my name be profaned?
My glory I will not give to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis X: Our New Inheritance – Spirit’s Witness in Our Adoption</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-ix-our-new-inheritance-spirits-witness-in-our-adoption/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-ix-our-new-inheritance-spirits-witness-in-our-adoption/</guid>
      <description>We have fully established that we are not fully alive despite being biologically alive. Throughout the Bible, starting in Genesis 2, God states that sin separates the soul of man from the spirit of God. And without God, we are dead. And just being dead is not enough: Ephesians 2:1–3 And you were dead in the trespasses and sinsin which you once walked, following the course of this world, following the prince of the power of the air, the spirit that is now at work in the sons of disobedience—among whom we all once lived in the passions of our flesh, carrying out the desires of the body and the mind, and were by nature children of wrath, like the rest of mankind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis IX: Our New Heart – Spirit’s Power in Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-ix-our-new-heart-spirits-power-in-regeneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-ix-our-new-heart-spirits-power-in-regeneration/</guid>
      <description>When God saved us from eternity past, His saving work was not finished when Christ lived, died, buried, and rose again, as though there is nothing for him for his people. You see, every single person born of man since Adam and Eve were born inherently not in connection with God but being apart from God both infinitely and eternally. That separation is because we have no spirit of God because our hearts were not born of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis VIII: Christ’s Finished Work, We Are Protected</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-viii-christs-finished-work-we-are-protected/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 12:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-viii-christs-finished-work-we-are-protected/</guid>
      <description>This has been one of the most difficult chapters to write because there is so much to be packed into the doctrine of propitiation. The only way I could approach this is to start at the beginning and start at the high altitude and work our way down. To understand propitiation, we must understand God, his law, his love and his holiness.
What can incite the wrath of God? It is when we decide that we don’t need his way but we insist on own our way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis VII: Christ’s Sufficient Work, We Are Clean</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-vii-christs-sufficient-work-we-are-clean/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 12:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-vii-christs-sufficient-work-we-are-clean/</guid>
      <description>This is the magnificence of the True God.
The God of the Old Testament who called down judgment on the wicked and the departed. The same God who expressed His faithfulness to His people who were faithless. The God whose steadfast love never ceased to those whom he promised would make things all things right. The infinitely powerful God who was able to always woo and pursue the hearts of his children and bring them out of death and destruction back into life everlasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis VI: Christ’s Perfect Work, We Are Justified</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-vi-christs-perfect-work-we-are-justified/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-vi-christs-perfect-work-we-are-justified/</guid>
      <description>Many people tried to say that the God of the Old Testament and the God of the New Testament are completely two different gods. Have you heard this argument? Why was God so angry? Why is Jesus so loving and kind? Was God in the Old Testament was the Father and then his Son took over in the New? I don’t understand a god that would punish people. I can only understand a god that loves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis V: God Speaks To The Dead</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-v-but-god-preaches-to-the-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 12:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-v-but-god-preaches-to-the-dead/</guid>
      <description>John 6:44-47 No one can come to me unless the Father who sent me draws him. And I will raise him up on the last day. It is written in the Prophets, ‘And they will all be taught by God.’ Everyone who has heard and learned from the Father comes to me—not that anyone has seen the Father except he is from God; he has seen the Father. Truly, truly, I say to you, whoever believes has eternal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis IV: We Are Destined For Death</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-iv-we-are-destined-for-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 12:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-iv-we-are-destined-for-death/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;How does God determine who he will save and not save?&amp;#8221; If you ever speak about the doctrine of election and predestination, you are sure to get that question asked. Numerous times have I been asked this and numerous times the answer of &amp;#8220;his glory (Isaiah 48:11, Proverbs 25:2) and his pleasure (Isaiah 48:11 cf. Philippians 2:13)&amp;#8221; is simply not good enough. Furthermore, to answer that &amp;#8220;the secret things belong to the LORD (Deuteronomy 29:29)&amp;#8221; is merely a copout to most people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis III: For God So Loved The World</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-iii-for-god-so-loved-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-iii-for-god-so-loved-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Now that we have established who we are in the sight of God, let us tackle the bigger, nay impossible question:
Who is God? Ask my son and he would immediately quote:
God is the universe’s Creator And Sustainer plus the only Savior, there is no one greater. He’s Triune, holy, omnipotent, omniscient, absolute, loving, sovereign and righteous are just a few of His attributes.
&amp;#8211; Shai Lynne, Atonement Q&amp;amp;A</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis II: The Weight of Sin</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-ii-the-weight-of-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 12:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-ii-the-weight-of-sin/</guid>
      <description>Before we can even try to understand what God has done in Salvation, we must first truly understand our condition as human beings born on this earth. I feel compelled to at least touch on this doctrine for I believe that many Christians sometimes either forget their natural state before God saved them or they simply don&amp;#8217;t remember being that &amp;#8216;bad&amp;#8217; of a person before being saved. It is not that we have to dwell on our depravity, our flesh, our sin nature but to ignore or forget about it would absolutely rob our heart of joy and worship before the Lord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis I: The Overflowing Love of God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-i-the-overflowing-love-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-i-the-overflowing-love-of-god/</guid>
      <description>To proclaim ourselves as Christians to proclaim that we believe and trust upon Christ as our Saviour and Lord.   At that beautiful moment when God saved us, we hope and pray that each one of us are immediately surrounded by other brothers and sisters in Christ that are willing to walk alongside us in love, encouragement, teaching and exhortation. It is my sincere hope that no newly saved person is ever alone by themselves trying to figure this thing especially when the cross of Christ has not only saved us to Himself but we have been reconciled to each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give Thanks</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/give-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 16:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/give-thanks/</guid>
      <description>Give thanks with a grateful heart Give thanks to the Holy One Give thanks because He&#39;s given Jesus Christ, His Son And now let the weak say, &#34;I am strong&#34; Let the poor say, &#34;I am rich&#34;, Because of what the Lord has done for us. Give thanks. &amp;#8211; Don Moen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving For Who You Are—You Are God Alone</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-who-you-are-you-are-god-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-who-you-are-you-are-god-alone/</guid>
      <description>I thank him who has given me strength, Christ Jesus our Lord, because he judged me faithful, appointing me to his service, though formerly I was a blasphemer, persecutor, and insolent opponent. But I received mercy because I had acted ignorantly in unbelief, and the grace of our Lord overflowed for me with the faith and love that are in Christ Jesus. The saying is trustworthy and deserving of full acceptance, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are So Good To Me</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/you-are-so-good-to-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/you-are-so-good-to-me/</guid>
      <description>You are so good to me You heal my broken heart You are my Father in heaven You ride upon the clouds You lead me to the truth You are the Spirit inside me You are beautiful my sweet, sweet, song  I will sing again   You are my strong melody You are my dancing rhythm You are my perfect rhyme And I want to sing forever  You poured out all your blood You died upon the cross You are my Jesus who loves me You are my Father in heaven You are the Spirit inside me You are the Jesus who loves me And I will sing again… &amp;#8211; 100 Portraits and Waterdeep</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>