<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Influences: Scriptures on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/tags/influences-scriptures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Influences: Scriptures on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 19:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/tags/influences-scriptures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Blissful Contentment – Psalm 17:15</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-blissful-contentment-psalm17-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 19:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-blissful-contentment-psalm17-15/</guid>
      <description>A sight for sore eyes.
No words have rang truer except for the Son of Man.
The One God who cross the infinite just to save me.
Now my eyes bleared at the first site of him.
The loveliness of his face.
I look into His eyes and my soul is complete. My heart is joy-filled. My mind now knows fully.
I am content.
I am satisfied.
God is perfect in his work in me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: I Know Nothing But Him</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/theology/influences-i-know-nothing-but-him/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/theology/influences-i-know-nothing-but-him/</guid>
      <description>I know one thing, that I know nothing.
 &amp;#8211; Socrates
If I have set the direction of my theology based on the thread of Hebrews 6:1-3, 1 Corinthians 3:21-23, and 1 Corinthians 2:12-13, then I would have to say this would be the basis for all of my reading, studying, writing, lecturing, preaching, and teaching:
1 Corinthians 2:2 For I decided to know nothing among you except Jesus Christ and him crucified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: The Thread of Logic</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/theology/influences-the-thread-of-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/theology/influences-the-thread-of-logic/</guid>
      <description>I believe, trust, understand, love, and think by this principle: my entire grasp, knowledge, relationship, salvation, and love to God, for God, by God, from God, and through God is according to these three Scriptures:
Hebrews 6:1-3 Therefore let us leave the elementary doctrine of Christ and go on to maturity, not laying again a foundation of repentance from dead works and of faith toward God, and of instruction about washings, the laying on of hands, the resurrection of the dead, and eternal judgment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Where Theology and Expectation Meet</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/theology/influences-where-theology-and-expectation-meet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/theology/influences-where-theology-and-expectation-meet/</guid>
      <description>Romans 15:17-21 In Christ Jesus, then, I have reason to be proud of my work for God. For I will not venture to speak of anything except what Christ has accomplished through me to bring the Gentiles to obedience—by word and deed, by the power of signs and wonders, by the power of the Spirit of God—so that from Jerusalem and all the way around to Illyricum I have fulfilled the ministry of the gospel of Christ; and thus I make it my ambition to preach the gospel, not where Christ has already been named, lest I build on someone else&amp;#8217;s foundation, but as it is written, “Those who have never been told of him will see, and those who have never heard will understand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>