<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quotes on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/quotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quotes on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 12:00:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/quotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Love of Jesus</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-love-of-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-love-of-jesus/</guid>
      <description>My heart melts at the love of Jesus, my brother, bone of my bone, flesh of my flesh, married to me, dead for me, risen for me; He is mine and I am his, given to me as well as for me;  &amp;#8211; from The Love of Jesus
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jesus My Glory</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/jesus-my-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/jesus-my-glory/</guid>
      <description>His water and blood were not severed in their flow at the cross, may they never be separated in my creed and experiences;  &amp;#8211; from Jesus My Glory
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christ Alone</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/christ-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 12:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/christ-alone/</guid>
      <description>Though here I love him but little, may this be my portion at last. In this world thou hast given me a beginning, one day it will be perfected in the realm above. Thou hast helped me to see and know Christ, though obscurely, to take him, receive him, to possess him, love him, to bless him in my heart, mouth, life.  &amp;#8211; from Christ Alone
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Name of Jesus</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-name-of-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 12:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-name-of-jesus/</guid>
      <description>I am ready to flee from myself because of my abominations; Yet thou dost not abhor me but hast devised means for my return to thee, and that, by thy Son who died to give me life.  &amp;#8211; from The Name of Jesus
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Union with Christ</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/union-with-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 12:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/union-with-christ/</guid>
      <description>The more I hunger and thirst after thee, the more I faint and fail in finding thee, The more my heart is broken for sin, the more I pray it may be far more broken.  &amp;#8211; from Union with Christ
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fullness in Christ</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/fullness-in-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 12:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/fullness-in-christ/</guid>
      <description>... that it is my duty, out of a sense of emptiness, to go to Christ, possess, enjoy his fullness as mine, as if I had it in myself, because it is for me in him; that when I do this I am full of the Spirit, as a fish that has got from the shore to the sea and has all fullness of waters to move in, for when faith fills me, then I am full; that this is the way to be filled with the Spirit, like Stephen, first faith, then fullness, for this way makes me most empty, and so most fit for the Spirit to fill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:4b Fear No Evil</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-234b-fear-no-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 12:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-234b-fear-no-evil/</guid>
      <description>My God, I fear no evil. For your precious Son has already conquered sin, Satan, demons, hell, and death. I have no enemies on earth. Those are not my real enemies. Rulers, princes, and principalities: they crouch for my soul. They wait to devour my heart. They do not hesitate to fire a million arrows of fire just to consume my being. But you, O Lord, are my strength, my armour, my fortress and strong tower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christ is All</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/christ-is-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 12:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/christ-is-all/</guid>
      <description>I think of thy glory and my vileness, thy majesty and my meanness, thy beauty and my deformity, thy purity and my filth, thy righteousness and my iniquity. Thou hast loved me everlastingly, unchangeably, may I love thee as I am loved; Thou hast given thyself for me, may I give myself to thee;  &amp;#8211; from Christ is All
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christ the Word</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/christ-the-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/christ-the-word/</guid>
      <description>When I sin against thee I cross thy will, love, life, and have no comforter, no creature, to go to. My sin is not so much this or that particular evil, but my continual separation, disunion, distance from thee, and having a loose spirit towards thee. But thou hast given me a present, Jesus thy Son, as Mediator between thyself and my soul, as middle-man who in a pit holds both him below and him above, for only he can span the chasm breached by sin, and satisfy divine justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gift of Gifts</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-gift-of-gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 12:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-gift-of-gifts/</guid>
      <description>In him thou hast given me so much that heaven can give no more.  &amp;#8211; from The Gift of Gifts
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Praise and Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/praise-and-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/praise-and-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>When I think upon and converse with thee ten thousand delightful thoughts spring up, ten thousand sources of pleasure are unsealed, ten thousand refreshing joys spread over my heart, crowding into every moment of happiness.  &amp;#8211; from Praise and Thanksgiving
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God Honored</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-honored/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-honored/</guid>
      <description>The sea, dry land, winter cold, summer heat, morning light, evening shade are full of thee, and thou givest me them richly to enjoy. Thou art King of kings and Lord of lords; At thy pleasure empires rise and fall; All thy works praise thee and thy saints bless thee; Let me be numbered with thy holy ones, resemble them in character and condition, sit with them at Jesus’ feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golgotha</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/golgotha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 12:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/golgotha/</guid>
      <description>Let us muse upon the fact that Jesus was conducted without the gates of the city. It was the common place of death. That little rising ground, which perhaps was called Golgotha, the place of a skull, from its somewhat resembling the crown of a man&#39;s skull, was the common place of execution. It was one of Death&#39;s castles; here he stored his gloomiest trophies; he was the grim lord of that stronghold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man’s Great End</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/mans-great-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 12:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/mans-great-end/</guid>
      <description>There is one thing that deserves my greatest care, that calls forth my ardent desires, That is, that I may answer the great end for which I am made — to glorify thee who hast given me being, and to do all the good I can for my fellow men; Verily, life is not worth having if it be not improved for this noble purpose.  &amp;#8211; from Man&amp;#8217;s Great End</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Present Salvation</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/a-present-salvation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/a-present-salvation/</guid>
      <description>I adore thee for making me capable of knowing thee, for giving me reason and conscience, for leading me to desire thee; I praise thee for the revelation of thyself in the gospel, for thy heart as a dwelling place of pity, for thy thoughts of peace towards me, for thy patience and thy graciousness, for the vastness of thy mercy.  &amp;#8211; from A Present Salvation
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God Enjoyed</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-enjoyed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 12:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-enjoyed/</guid>
      <description>Known, but beyond knowledge, revealed, but unrevealed, my wants and welfare draw me to thee, for thou hast never said, ‘Seek ye me in vain’.  &amp;#8211; from God Enjoyed
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Divine Mercies</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/divine-mercies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/divine-mercies/</guid>
      <description>Thine is surpassing greatness, unspeakable goodness, super-abundant grace; I can as soon count the sands of ocean’s ‘lip’ as number thy favours towards me;  &amp;#8211; from Divine Mercies
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Divine Will</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-divine-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 12:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-divine-will/</guid>
      <description>Strengthen me to pray with the conviction that whatever I receive is thy gift, so that I may pray until prayer be granted;  &amp;#8211; from The Divine Will
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mover</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-mover/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-mover/</guid>
      <description>Who made me to differ, but thee? for I was no more ready to receive Christ than were others; I could not have begun to love thee hadst thou not first loved me, or been willing unless thou hadst first made me so. O that such a crown should fit the head of such a sinner! such high advancement be for an unfruitful person! such joys for so vile a rebel!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The All Good</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-all-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-all-good/</guid>
      <description>Let me know the need of renovation as well as of forgiveness, in order to serve and enjoy thee for ever. I come to thee in the all-prevailing name of Jesus, with nothing of my own to plead, no works, no worthiness, no promises.  &amp;#8211; from The All Good
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Liturgy</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/french-liturgy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 12:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/french-liturgy/</guid>
      <description>For you, little child, Jesus Christ has come, he has fought, he has suffered. For you he entered the shadow of Gethsemane and the horror of Calvary. For you he uttered the cry, ‘It is finished!’ For you he rose from the dead and ascended into heaven and there he intercedes — for you, little child, even though you do not know it. But in this way the word of the Gospel becomes true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Foot of Faith</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-foot-of-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 12:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-foot-of-faith/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Through him that loved us.&amp;#8221; Here is the great secret of our victory, the source of our triumph. Behold the mystery explained, how a weak, timid believer, often running from his own shadow, is yet &amp;#8220;more than a conqueror&amp;#8221; over his many and mighty foes. To Christ who loved him, who gave himself for him, who died in his stead, and lives to intercede on his behalf, the glory of the triumph is ascribed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Condemnation There Cannot Be</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/condemnation-there-cannot-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/condemnation-there-cannot-be/</guid>
      <description>Yet more: Faith is not only the instrument by which we receive a free grace justification, but it harmonizes the outward act of God with the inward feelings of the believing heart. Thus in justification the heart of the Justifier and the heart of the justified beat in the most perfect and holy unison. It is not a stupendous act on the part of God meeting no response on the part of man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Word Made Flesh</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-word-made-flesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-word-made-flesh/</guid>
      <description>We confess the mystery and wonder of God made flesh and rejoice in our great salvation through Jesus Christ our Lord. With the Father and the Holy Spirit, the Son created all things, sustains all things, and makes all things new. Truly God, He became truly man, two natures in one person. He was born of the Virgin Mary and lived among us. Crucified, dead, and buried, He rose on the third day, ascended to heaven, and will come again in glory and judgment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-great-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-great-god/</guid>
      <description>Let me know the need of renovation as well as of forgiveness, in order to serve and enjoy thee for ever. I come to thee in the all-prevailing name of Jesus, with nothing of my own to plead, no works, no worthiness, no promises.  &amp;#8211; from The Great God
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God The All: The All-Prevailing Name</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-the-all-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 12:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-the-all-2/</guid>
      <description>Let me know the need of renovation as well as of forgiveness, in order to serve and enjoy thee for ever. I come to thee in the all-prevailing name of Jesus, with nothing of my own to plead, no works, no worthiness, no promises.  &amp;#8211; from God the All
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God The All: The Author and Finisher of all the Good Work Within Me</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-the-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 14:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-the-all/</guid>
      <description>I know that thou art the author and finisher of faith, that the whole work of redemption is thine alone, that every good work or thought found in me is the effect of thy power and grace, that thy sole motive in working in me to will and to do is for thy good pleasure.  &amp;#8211; from God the All
_The Valley of Vision_</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trinity</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-trinity/</guid>
      <description>O Father, I thank thee that in fullness of grace thou hast given me to Jesus, to be his sheep, jewel, portion; O Jesus, I thank thee that in fullness of grace thou hast accepted, espoused, bound me; O Holy Spirit, I thank thee that in fullness of grace thou hast exhibited Jesus as my salvation, implanted faith within me, subdued my stubborn heart, made me one with him for ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Crap We Wade Through</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-crap-we-wade-through/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 15:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-crap-we-wade-through/</guid>
      <description>With all of my struggles, I found out I was suffering from depression.
Now, by God&amp;#8217;s strength and grace and his love alone, I have to battle this.
And I know that God will deliver me from this&amp;#8211;just like he delivered me from death.
I pray:
May the LORD bless me and keep me;
May the LORD make his face to shine upon me and be gracious to me;
May the LORD lift up his countenance upon me and give me peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give Thanks</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/give-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 16:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/give-thanks/</guid>
      <description>Give thanks with a grateful heart Give thanks to the Holy One Give thanks because He&#39;s given Jesus Christ, His Son And now let the weak say, &#34;I am strong&#34; Let the poor say, &#34;I am rich&#34;, Because of what the Lord has done for us. Give thanks. &amp;#8211; Don Moen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Believe, and Believe for Your Life!</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/believe-and-believe-for-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/believe-and-believe-for-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;That sad and yet blissful hour when Abraham was to take leave of all that was dear to him, when yet once more he was to lift up his head, when his countenance would shine like that of the Lord, when he would concentrate his whole soul in a blessing which was potent to make Isaac blessed all his days–this time would not come! For he would indeed take leave of Isaac, but in such a way that he himself would remain behind; death would separate them, but in such a way that Isaac remained its prey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits in the Person and Work of Christ</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/benefits-in-the-person-and-work-of-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/benefits-in-the-person-and-work-of-christ/</guid>
      <description>ht: Jared Oliphant        &amp;#8220;Owen and his Reformed contemporaries did not simply equate the covenant of grace with justification by faith alone. Soteric benefits—whether justification, adoption, or sanctification—are appropriated in the context of the covenant of grace, and all are necessary for salvation. Yet because these benefits are rooted first in the person and work of Christ, the covenant of grace retains its gracious character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring a Lunch Box</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/bring-a-lunch-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/bring-a-lunch-box/</guid>
      <description>Then there’s the reality that holiness is plain hard work, and we’re often lazy. We like our sins, and dying to them is painful. Almost everything is easier than growing in godliness. So we try and fail, try and fail, and then give up. It’s easier to sign a petition protesting man’s inhumanity to man than to love your neighbor as yourself. It’s one thing to graduate from college ready to change the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cannot Be Taken Lightly</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/cannot-be-taken-lightly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/cannot-be-taken-lightly/</guid>
      <description>This study is important because exegetical fallacies are painfully painfully frequent among us—among us whose God-given grace and responsibility is the faithful proclamation of the Word of God. Make a mistake in the interpretation of one of Shakespeare&amp;#8217;s plays, falsely scan a piece of Spenserian verse, and there is unlikely to be entailment of eternal consequence; but we cannot lightly accept a similar laxity in the interpretation of Scripture. We are dealing with God&amp;#8217;s thoughts: we are obligated to take the greatest pains to understand them truly and to explain them clearly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consider the Tiny and the Mighty</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/consider-the-tiny-and-the-mighty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/consider-the-tiny-and-the-mighty/</guid>
      <description>Kingdom of God: Its appearance may be characterized by weakness and apparent insignificance &amp;#8211; but remember the mustard seed. The day will come when the Kingdom of God will surpass in glory the mightiest kingdoms of the earth, for it is the consequence of God&amp;#8217;s sovereign action. The mustard seed is the word of God proclaimed by Christ. This word possesses the power which one day will make all things new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing In Midair</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/dancing-in-mid-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/dancing-in-mid-air/</guid>
      <description>On those who possess actual faith in God:
&amp;#8220;It is supposed to be the most difficult task for a dancer to leap into a definite posture in such a way that there is not a second when he is grasping after the posture, but by the leap itself he stands fixed in that posture. Perhaps no dancer can do it–that is what this knight does. Most people live dejectedly in worldly sorrow and joy; they are the ones who sit along the wall and do not join in the dance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Calling: Blind to My True Condition</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/dangerous-calling-blind-to-my-true-condition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/dangerous-calling-blind-to-my-true-condition/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;You see, sin is not first an intellectual problem. (Yes, it does affect my intellect, as it does all parts of my functioning.) Sin is first a moral problem. It is about my rebellion against God and my quest to have for myself the glory that is due to him. Sin is not first about the breaking of an abstract set of rules. Sin is first and foremost about breaking relationship with God, and because I have broken this relationship, it is then easy and natural to rebel against God’s rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Calling: God Will Give Us What We Want</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/dangerous-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/dangerous-calling/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, we think of God as a pragmatic god. We think we do exactly as he says, we make it appear that all is well, and do everything to please him, he will give us whatever our heart&amp;#8217;s desires.
Wait, what if my heart&amp;#8217;s desires are for something not Him? What if I want more money, more sex, more work, more security, more of anything out of God but not God himself?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Calling: Where’s The Grace?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/dangerous-calling-wheres-the-grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/dangerous-calling-wheres-the-grace/</guid>
      <description>Lectures. Speaking engagements. One-on-one counseling. Teaching. Preaching. Speaking. Whispering. Is it possible to continuously proclaiming the glorious, loving, gracious gospel of Jesus Christ? What if I preached to myself His gospel? What if I continuously filled my mind not with mindless entertainment but with His glorious revelation? What if I stepped into the world and loved the world in the way He did? What if I could get ever moment of my life to proclaim His goodness and grace?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Make A Difference</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/does-make-a-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/does-make-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>Some pollsters and pundits look at the worldliness of the church and conclude that being born again doesn’t make a difference in how people live. We should come to the opposite conclusion; namely, that many churchgoers are not truly born again.
 Kevin DeYoung. The Hole in Our Holiness: Filling the Gap Between Gospel Passion and the Pursuit of Godliness. Crossway, 2012. 18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fanatical Christians Actually Haven’t Gone Far Enough</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/fanatical-christians-actually-havent-gone-far-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/fanatical-christians-actually-havent-gone-far-enough/</guid>
      <description>Think of people you consider fanatical. They’re overbearing, self-righteous, opinionated, insensitive, and harsh. Why? It’s not because they are too Christian but because they are not Christian enough. They are fanatically zealous and courageous, but they are not fanatically humble, sensitive, loving, empathetic, forgiving, or understanding – as Christ was. Because they think of Christianity as a self-improvement program they emulate the Jesus of the whips in the temple, but not the Jesus who said, “Let him who is without sin cast the first stone” (John 8:7).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God is Not Hoping That You Will Be The Best That You Can Be</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-is-not-hoping-you-can-be-the-best-that-you-can-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-is-not-hoping-you-can-be-the-best-that-you-can-be/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The idea behind moral, therapeutic deism is that we are able to earn favor with God and justify ourselves before God by virtue of our behavior. This mode of thinking is religious, even ‘Christian’ in its content, but it’s more about self-actualization and self-fulfillment, and it posits a God who does not so much intervene and redeem but basically hangs out behind the scenes, cheering on your you-ness and hoping you pick up on the clues he’s left to become the best you can be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God Knew Ahead</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-knew-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/god-knew-ahead/</guid>
      <description>Wilson: &amp;#8220;God knew that we were going to need to pick up dimes, and so He gave us fingernails. He knew that twilights displayed in blue, apricot, and battle gray would be entirely astonishing and beyond us, and so He gave us eyes that can see in color. He could have made all food quite nourishing, but which tasted like wadded up newspaper soaked in machine oil. Instead He gave us the tastes of watermelon, pecans, oatmeal stout, buttered corn, apples, fresh bread, grilled sirloin, and 25-year-old scotch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Cannot Close My Eyes To This Leap of Faith</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/i-cannot-close-my-eyes-to-this-leap-of-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/i-cannot-close-my-eyes-to-this-leap-of-faith/</guid>
      <description>I have seen the dreadful before my own eyes, I do not flee from it timorously, but I know very well that, although I advance to meet it, my courage is not the courage of faith, nor anything comparable to it. I am unable to make the movements of faith, I cannot shut my eyes and plunge confidently into the absurd, for me that is an impossibility … but I do not boast of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Would’ve Been Too Scared</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/i-wouldve-been-too-scared/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/i-wouldve-been-too-scared/</guid>
      <description>But what did Abraham do? He arrived neither too soon nor too late. He mounted the ass, he rode slowly along the way. All that time he believed–he believed that God would not require Isaac of him, whereas he was willing nevertheless to sacrifice him if it was required. He believed by virtue of the absurd; for there could be no question of human calculation, and it was indeed the absurd that God who required it of him should the next instant recall the requirement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In 50 Trillion Years</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/in-50-trillion-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/in-50-trillion-years/</guid>
      <description>So if you and I exist in some way or another 50 trillion years from now, and we exist from now until then and beyond, then this 50-trillion-year mark is far more important than what happens to you at 8, at 16, at 42, at 61, or at any point in this little dew-in-the-morning, gone-in-the-afternoon life of yours and mine. So really and honestly, the cruelty of God would be to protect you here and now in such a way that would rob you of eternal life into the 50-trillion-year mark and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Faith Knowing What’s Going To Happen?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/is-faith-knowing-whats-going-to-happen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/is-faith-knowing-whats-going-to-happen/</guid>
      <description>Upon this pinnacle stands Abraham. The last stage he loses sight of is the infinite resignation. He really goes further, and reaches faith; for all these caricatures of faith, the miserable lukewarm indolence which thinks, &amp;#8220;There surely is no instant need, it is not worth while sorrowing before the time,&amp;#8221; the pitiful hope which says, &amp;#8220;One cannot know what is going to happen … it might possibly be after all&amp;#8221;–these caricatures of faith are part and parcel of life&amp;#8217;s wretchedness, and the infinite resignation has already consigned them to infinite contempt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laughable, Still An Heir</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/laughable-still-an-heir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/laughable-still-an-heir/</guid>
      <description>Abraham became old, Sarah became a laughingstock in the land, and yet he was God&amp;#8217;s elect and inheritor of the promise that in his seed all the races of the world would be blessed.
 Søren Kierkegaard. Fear and Trembling, 2012. Kindle 140.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Left Up To Me, I Would Have Chosen Not God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/left-up-to-me-i-would-have-chosen-not-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/left-up-to-me-i-would-have-chosen-not-god/</guid>
      <description>ht: Reformation Theology        &amp;#8220;I frankly confess that, for myself, even if it could be, I should not want &amp;#8216;free-will; to be given me, nor anything to be left in my own hands to enable me to endeavour after salvation; not merely because in face of so many dangers, and adversities and assaults of devils, I could not stand my ground ; but because even were there no dangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let Me Control My Environment in Order To Make My Life Better</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/let-me-control-my-environment-in-order-to-make-my-life-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/let-me-control-my-environment-in-order-to-make-my-life-better/</guid>
      <description>In ancient times it was understood that there was a transcendent moral order outside the self, built in to the fabric of the universe. If you violated that metaphysical order there were consequences just as severe as if you violated physical reality by placing your hand in a fire. The path of wisdom was to learn to live in conformity with this unyielding reality. That wisdom rested largely in developing qualities of character, such as humility, compassion, courage, discretion, and loyalty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loving God But Not Believing God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/loving-god-but-not-believing-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/loving-god-but-not-believing-god/</guid>
      <description>If this had not been the case with Abraham, then perhaps he might have loved God but not believed; for he who loves God without faith reflects upon himself, he who loves God believingly reflects upon God.
 Søren Kierkegaard. Fear and Trembling, 2012. Kindle 385.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not enough material</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/not-enough-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/not-enough-material/</guid>
      <description>No pen, no words, no image can express to you the loveliness of my only, only Lord Jesus.
 &amp;#8211; Samuel Rutherford</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: Death Has Been Brought to Nothing</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-death-has-been-brought-to-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-death-has-been-brought-to-nothing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Have no fears then. Now that the common Savior of all has died on our behalf, we who believe in Christ no longer die, as men died aforetime, in fulfillment of the threat of the law. That condemnation has come to an end; and now that, by the grace of the resurrection, corruption has been banished and done away, we are loosed from our mortal bodies in God&amp;#8217;s good time for each, so that we may obtain thereby a better resurrection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: Fully God, Fully Human</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-fully-god-fully-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-fully-god-fully-human/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;For this purpose, then, the incorporeal and incorruptible and immaterial Word of God entered our world. In one sense, indeed, He was not far from it before, for no part of creation had ever been without Him Who, while ever abiding in union with the Father, yet fills all things that are. But now He entered the world in a new way, stooping to our level in His love and Self-revealing to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: God Comes To Us</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-god-comes-to-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-god-comes-to-us/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;But how was He to do it? By the same means as before, perhaps you will say, that is, through the works of creation. But this was proven insufficient. Men had neglected to consider the heavens before, and now they were looking in the opposite direction. Wherefore, in all naturalness and fitness, desiring to do good to men, as Man He dwells, taking to Himself a body like the rest; and through His actions done in that body, as it were on their own level, He teaches those who would not learn by other means to know Himself, the Word of God, and through Him the Father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: He Did Not Leave Us Like Brutes</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-he-did-not-leave-us-like-brutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-he-did-not-leave-us-like-brutes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Was He to keep silence before so great a wrong and let men go on being thus deceived and kept in ignorance of Himself? If so, what was the use of having made them in His own Image originally? It would surely have been better for them always to have been brutes, rather than to revert to that condition when once they had shared the nature of the Word. Again, things being as they were, what was the use of their ever having had the knowledge of God?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: His Honor In Exchange For Our Destruction</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-his-honor-in-exchange-for-our-destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-his-honor-in-exchange-for-our-destruction/</guid>
      <description>[][1]The Course of Empire Destruction by Thomas Cole &amp;#8220;This great work was, indeed, supremely worthy of the goodness of God. A king who has founded a city, so far from neglecting it when through the carelessness of the inhabitants it is attacked by robbers, avenges it and saves it from destruction, having regard rather to his own honor than to the people&amp;#8217;s neglect. Much more, then, the Word of the All-good Father was not unmindful of the human race that He had called to be; but rather, by the offering of His own body He abolished the death which they had incurred, and corrected their neglect by His own teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: His Works Made Visible For the World to See</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-his-works-made-visible-for-the-world-to-see/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-his-works-made-visible-for-the-world-to-see/</guid>
      <description>There were thus two things which the Savior did for us by becoming Man. He banished death from us and made us anew; and, invisible and imperceptible as in Himself He is, He became visible through His works and revealed Himself as the Word of the Father, the Ruler and King of the whole creation.
 Athanasius. On The Incarnation of the Word. 245-247. Kindle Edition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: Men Are Due To Die, God Takes That Due</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-men-are-due-to-die-god-takes-that-due/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-men-are-due-to-die-god-takes-that-due/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Who in the beginning made all things out of nothing; that only the Image of the Father could re-create the likeness of the Image in men, that none save our Lord Jesus Christ could give to mortals immortality, and that only the Word Who orders all things and is alone the Father&amp;#8217;s true and sole-begotten Son could teach men about Him and abolish the worship of idols But beyond all this, there was a debt owing which must needs be paid; for, as I said before, all men were due to die.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: Reasonable Beings That Could Apprehend the Father</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-reasonable-beings-that-could-apprehend-the-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-reasonable-beings-that-could-apprehend-the-father/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;For of what use is existence to the creature if it cannot know its Maker? How could men be reasonable beings if they had no knowledge of the Word and Reason of the Father, through Whom they had received their being? They would be no better than the beasts, had they no knowledge save of earthly things; and why should God have made them at all, if He had not intended them to know Him?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: So That God Might Be Revealed to All</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-so-that-god-might-be-revealed-to-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-so-that-god-might-be-revealed-to-all/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Whose all-ruling providence makes known the Father to all. Or, if this was beyond them, they could converse with holy men, and through them learn to know God, the Artificer of all things, the Father of Christ, and to recognize the worship of idols as the negation of the truth and full of all impiety. Or else, in the third place, they could cease from lukewarmness and lead a good life merely by knowing the law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: Taking On Our Weakness</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-taking-on-our-weakness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-taking-on-our-weakness/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The death of men under ordinary circumstances is the result of their natural weakness. They are essentially impermanent, so after a time they fall ill and when worn out they die. But the Lord is not like that. He is not weak, He is the Power of God and Word of God and Very Life Itself. If He had died quietly in His bed like other men it would have looked as if He did so in accordance with His nature, and as though He was indeed no more than other men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: The Death of Death in the Death of the Word Made Man</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-the-death-of-death-in-the-death-of-the-word-made-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-the-death-of-death-in-the-death-of-the-word-made-man/</guid>
      <description>For by the sacrifice of His own body He did two things: He put an end to the law of death which barred our way; and He made a new beginning of life for us, by giving us the hope of resurrection. By man death has gained its power over men; by the Word made Man death has been destroyed and life raised up anew.
 Athanasius. On The Incarnation of the Word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: The Mystery That We Adore</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-the-mystery-that-we-adore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-the-mystery-that-we-adore/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Now, Macarius, true lover of Christ, we must take a step further in the faith of our holy religion, and consider also the Word&amp;#8217;s becoming Man and His divine Appearing in our midst. That mystery the Jews traduce, the Greeks deride, but we adore; and your own love and devotion to the Word also will be the greater, because in His Manhood He seems so little worth. For it is a fact that the more unbelievers pour scorn on Him, so much the more does He make His Godhead evident.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: The Truth Behind the Imago Dei</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-the-truth-behind-the-imago-dei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-the-truth-behind-the-imago-dei/</guid>
      <description>Creation of Adam by Buonarroti Michelangelo &amp;#8220;His own Word, our Lord Jesus Christ and of all these His earthly creatures He reserved especial mercy for the race of men. Upon them, therefore, upon men who, as animals, were essentially impermanent, He bestowed a grace which other creatures lacked&amp;#8211;namely the impress of His own Image, a share in the reasonable being of the very Word Himself, so that, reflecting Him and themselves becoming reasonable and expressing the Mind of God even as He does, though in limited degree they might continue for ever in the blessed and only true life of the saints in paradise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On The Incarnation: Why Did God Become Flesh?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-why-did-god-become-flesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-why-did-god-become-flesh/</guid>
      <description>He has been manifested in a human body for this reason only, out of the love and goodness of His Father, for the salvation of us men.
 Athanasius. On The Incarnation of the Word. 15-16 . Kindle Edition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Incarnation: Worthy Enough To Suffer For Us</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-worthy-enough-to-suffer-for-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/on-the-incarnation-worthy-enough-to-suffer-for-us/</guid>
      <description>[][1]The Crucifixion: Christ on the Cross by Diego Velazquez &amp;#8220;What&amp;#8211;or rather Who was it that was needed for such grace and such recall as we required? Who, save the Word of God Himself, Who also in the beginning had made all things out of nothing? His part it was, and His alone, both to bring again the corruptible to incorruption and to maintain for the Father His consistency of character with all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power of Preaching, Yet, Eternity at Home</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/power-of-preaching-yet-eternity-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/power-of-preaching-yet-eternity-at-home/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signed in Blood</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/signed-in-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/signed-in-blood/</guid>
      <description>The keynote in the mouth of every prophet-preacher, whether in Isaiah&amp;#8217;s day or Jesus&amp;#8217; day or our day, is, &amp;#8220;Your God reigns!&amp;#8221; God is the king of the universe. God is the king of the universe. He has absolute Creator rights over this world and everyone in it. But there is rebellion and mutiny on all sides, and his authority is scorned by millions. So the Lord sends preachers into the world to cry out that God reigns, that he will not suffer his glory to be scorned indefinitely, that he will vindicate his name in great and terrible wrath, but that for now a full and free amnesty is offered to all the rebel subjects who will turn from their rebellion, call on him for mercy, bow before his throne, and swear allegiance and fealty to him forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Comfort: God Knows We Don’t</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/take-comfort-god-knows-we-dont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/take-comfort-god-knows-we-dont/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Evil estimates magma to be the temperature of &amp;#8220;boiling hot&amp;#8221;. &amp;#8220;In addition to the exhaustive depth of his knowledge is the exhaustive breadth of his knowledge. God is aware of every event that has ever occurred and will ever occur, and he knows completely how each event affects other events that create still more events that roll into other events and so on and so forth ad infinitum. From the velocity of every butterfly’s flapping wings at every second to the exact amount of magma to the microgram flowing out of every volcano above and under sea level, he spans it all simultaneously and precisely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That Satan Himself May Understand</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/that-satan-himself-may-understand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/that-satan-himself-may-understand/</guid>
      <description>If Satan fume and roar against you, whether it be against your bodies by persecution, or inward in your conscience by a spiritual battle, do not be discouraged, as though you were less acceptable in God’s presence, or that Satan might at any time prevail against you. No! Your temptations and storms that arise so suddenly argue and witness that the seed that is sown has fallen on good ground, has begun to take root, and shall, by God’s grace, bring forth fruit abundantly in due season and convenient time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Current Philosophies of Not Wanting To Think</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-current-philosophies-of-not-wanting-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-current-philosophies-of-not-wanting-to-think/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Every effort to account for the birth of the church apart from Jesus&amp;#8217;s resurrection flies in the face of what we know about first-century history and culture. If you don&amp;#8217;t short-circuit the process with philosophical bias against the possibility of miracle, the resurrection of Jesus has the most evidence for it.
The problem is, however, that people do short-circuit the investigation. Instead of doing the work of answering these very tough historical questions and then following the answers where they lead, they bail out with the objection that miracles are impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gospel Does One Better</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-gospel-does-one-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-gospel-does-one-better/</guid>
      <description>Reflecting on the movie, Angels with Dirty Faces and the novel, A Tale of Two Cities:
&amp;#8220;I always found these stories of sacrifice very emotionally affecting. I came away from them resolving to live more courageously and unselfishly. I never did follow through on my resolutions, however. The stories moved my emotions and pricked my conscience, but my heart&amp;#8217;s basic patterns stayed intact. I was still driving by a need to prove myself to others, to win approval acclaim, to control what people thought of me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Cry of the Soul</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-hidden-cry-of-the-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-hidden-cry-of-the-soul/</guid>
      <description>People are starving for the greatness of God. But most of them would not give this diagnosis of their troubled lives. The majesty of God is an unknown cure. There are far more popular prescriptions on the market, but the benefit of any other remedy is brief and shallow. Preaching that does not have the aroma of God&amp;#8217;s greatness may entertain for a season, but it will not touch the hidden cry of the soul: &amp;#8220;Show me thy glory!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Logic of Miracles</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-logic-of-miracles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-logic-of-miracles/</guid>
      <description>The other hidden premise in the statement &amp;#8220;miracles cannot happen&amp;#8221; is &amp;#8220;there can’t be a God who does miracles.&amp;#8221; If there is a Creator God, there is nothing illogical at all about the possibility of miracles. After all, if he created everything out of nothing, it would hardly be a problem for him to rearrange parts of it as and when he wishes. To be sure that miracles cannot occur you would have to be sure beyond a doubt that God didn’t exist, and that is an article of faith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mainstream of Religion</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-mainstream-of-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-mainstream-of-religion/</guid>
      <description>Religion is not just a temporary thing that helped us adapt to our environment. Rather it is a permanent and central aspect of the human condition. This is a bitter pill for secular, nonreligious people to swallow. Everyone wants to think that they are in the mainstream, that they are not extremists. But robust religious beliefs dominate the world. There is no reason to expect that to change. Timothy Keller. The Reason for God: Belief in an Age of Skepticism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Preciousness of the Word</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-preciousness-of-the-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-preciousness-of-the-word/</guid>
      <description>Careful handling of the Bible will enable us to &amp;#8220;hear&amp;#8221; it a little better. It is all too easy to read the traditional interpretations and invest them with a false, even idolatrous, degree of certainty. Because traditions are reshaped as they are passed on, after a while we may drift far from God&amp;#8217;s Word while still insisting all our theological opinions are &amp;#8220;biblical&amp;#8221; and therefore true. If when we are in such a state we study the Bible uncritically, more than likely it will simply reinforce our errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sound of the Bloody Cross Gospel</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-sound-of-the-bloody-cross-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-sound-of-the-bloody-cross-gospel/</guid>
      <description>I say to my non-Christian friends and neighbors, if you want to see the gospel of Christ, the gospel that has energized this church for two thousand years, turn off the television. The grinning cartoon characters who claim to speak for Christ don’t speak for him. Find the followers who do what Jesus did. Find the people who risk their lives to carry a beaten stranger to safety. Find the houses opened to unwed mothers and their babies in crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Timeliness of it All</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-timeliness-of-it-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-timeliness-of-it-all/</guid>
      <description>We desperately need a new generation of expositors, men cut from the same bolt of cloth as Calvin. Pastors marked by compassion, humility, and kindness must once again preach the Word. In short, we need Calvins again to stand in pulpits and boldly proclaim the Word of God.
 &amp;#8211; Steven Lawson, What’s the Answer to the Modern Day Church?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weight of Our Sin Pales in Comparison</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-weight-of-our-sin-pales-in-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-weight-of-our-sin-pales-in-comparison/</guid>
      <description>There is no weight of sin that the weight of His glory is not heavier still. The is no shame so bright that His blood cannot blot out. There is no destructive guilt that God&amp;#8217;s love that does not shield. There is no disease that God&amp;#8217;s will does not heal. There is no death that Christ has not conquered. There is no pit that is so deeper that Christ is not deeper still.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Their Joys Are Not Your Joys</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/their-joys-are-not-your-joys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/their-joys-are-not-your-joys/</guid>
      <description>Holiness is written on everything in heaven. And nothing unholy can enter into this heaven (Rev. 21:27; Heb. 12:14). Even if you could enter heaven without holiness, what would you do? What joy would you feel there? What holy man or woman of God would you sit down with for fellowship? Their pleasures are not your pleasures. Their character is not your character. What they love, you do not love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Haven’t Arrived Yet</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/we-havent-arrived-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/we-havent-arrived-yet/</guid>
      <description>The sum total of all useful exegetical knowledge did not reach the apex during the Reformation, or even in the past century. As much as we can must learn from our theological forebears, we face the harsh realities of this century; and neither nostalgia nor the preferred position of an ostrich will remove either the threats or the opportunities that summon our exegetical skills to new rigor. D. A. Carson. Exegetical Fallacies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Haven’t Evolved In Rising Above Sin</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/we-havent-evolved-in-rising-above-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/we-havent-evolved-in-rising-above-sin/</guid>
      <description>Wilson: You say, incidentally, that this kind of law was bringing coals to Newcastle—Moses came down from the mount and told people that murder, theft, and perjury were wrong, and all the assembled rolled their collective eyes. &amp;#8220;We already knew that!&amp;#8221; But the problem is that ancient man didn&amp;#8217;t know that, and modern man still doesn&amp;#8217;t know it. To state some of the issues that are subsumed under just one of the three categories you mention is to point to controversies that continue down to this day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When and When Not To Strive For Balance</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/when-and-when-not-to-strive-for-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/when-and-when-not-to-strive-for-balance/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;It is easy to think of other polarities under this heading that sustain relationships that are more complex yet. For example, the Bible urges Christian unity (think John 17), and the Bible insists on the non-negotiability of sound doctrine (think Gal 1), even if this means the most fundamental disruption of unity, namely, excommunication. The two desiderata are not quite parallel: one, the truth of the gospel, is always non-negotiable; the other, the virtue of unity, is often presented as something eminently desirable, but sometimes as an act of compromise (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Does The Gospel Start With?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/where-does-the-good-news-start-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/where-does-the-good-news-start-with/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The great message that we call the gospel begins, then, not with us, or our need, or even the meeting of that need, but with the writer of the news and the sender of its heralds: God himself.&amp;#8221;
 Matt Chandler. _The Explicit Gospel_. 1st ed. Crossway, 2012. 21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Do I Believe What I Believe?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/why-do-i-believe-what-i-believe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/why-do-i-believe-what-i-believe/</guid>
      <description>A faith without some doubts is like a human body without any antibodies in it. People who blithely go through life too busy or indifferent to ask hard questions about why they believe as they do will find themselves defenseless against either the experience of tragedy or the probing questions of a smart skeptic. A person&amp;#8217;s faith can collapse almost overnight if she has failed over the years to listen patiently to her own doubts, which should only be discarded after long reflection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worship Beyond Singing</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/worship-beyond-singing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/worship-beyond-singing/</guid>
      <description>More than ever I believe in preaching as a part of worship in the gathered church. Preaching is worship, and it belongs in the regular worship life of the church no matter the size of the church. In the small church it does not become conversation or &amp;#8220;sharing.&amp;#8221; In the megachurch it does not become hype and jingles. Preaching is worshiping over the Word of God—the text of Scripture—with explanation and exultation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can’t Tell Me Philosophy Affects Us—Just Look at the Church</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/you-cant-tell-me-philosophy-affects-us-just-look-at-the-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/you-cant-tell-me-philosophy-affects-us-just-look-at-the-church/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;In the 1950s and ’60s, rationalism began to erode evangelical scholarship, from academia on down, resulting in a liberal theology that crept into seminaries and churches. As a defensive maneuver, conservatives grabbed hold of the pendulum and swung it all the way over to the right side, wanting to believe they’d got “God” down to a science, his thoughts and ways explainable like mathematics. Romans 11:33 tells us instead that God is incomprehensibly immense, exceedingly expansive, and eternally powerful, and so much so that time and time again our response to many of the things of God ought to be “I don’t know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Ha, ha! Too Late!” said God never</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/ha-ha-too-late-said-god-never/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/ha-ha-too-late-said-god-never/</guid>
      <description>Modern people inevitably think that hell works like this: God gives us time, but if we haven&amp;#8217;t made the right choices by the end of our lives, he casts our souls into hell for all eternity. As the poor souls fall through space, they cry out for mercy, but God says &amp;#8220;Too late!&amp;#8221; You had your chance! Now you will suffer!&amp;#8221; This caricature misunderstands the very nature of evil. The Biblical picture is that sin separates us from the presence of God, which is the source of all joy and indeed all love, wisdom, or good things of any sort.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>