<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Influences: Passages on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/tags/influences-passages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Influences: Passages on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 20:10:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/tags/influences-passages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: What Else Can I Say? Psalm 16:11</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-what-else-can-i-say-psalm-1611/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 20:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-what-else-can-i-say-psalm-1611/</guid>
      <description>The God who alone is awesome.
This is Love, Election, Calling, Atonement, Justification, Propitiation, Expiation, Adoption, Sanctification, and Glorification rolled into one.
Even typing these words, meagerly and fumblingly, is drawing away from the sheer beauty, breath snatching, eye-rubbing gorgeousness, ever-swelling joy, tear-pouring grace and heart-bursting love that is this one verse.
Psalm 16:11
**You make known to me the path of life;
in your presence there is fullness of joy;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: The Apex of the Glory of God – Romans 8</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-the-apex-of-the-glory-of-god-romans-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-the-apex-of-the-glory-of-god-romans-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Mount-Everest-1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-928&#34; title=&#34;Mount-Everest-1&#34; src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Mount-Everest-1.jpg?resize=300%2C225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Mount-Everest-1.jpg?resize=300%2C225 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Mount-Everest-1.jpg?w=1024 1024w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;All Scripture read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every instinct preached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every thought taught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any book studied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every sermon heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every theology revealed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every doctrine learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any and all things processed were with Romans 8 in my sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have heard it said, &amp;#8220;The Epistle to the Romans is the Himalayas of the Bible and with Romans 8 is the Everest.&amp;#8221; Martin Luther calls Romans 8, &amp;#8220;the clearest Gospel of them all&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to memorize any passage of Scripture, it is because I wanted to get to where I can memorize Romans 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any passage memorized now is because I am camped out on the summit that is Romans 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memorized it. Dwelled on it. Read about it. Focused on it. Prayed on it. Prayed using it. Recite it. Practiced preaching it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to write a multi-part blog series on the entirety of Romans 8 in a few weeks so I won&amp;#8217;t expand on it here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, enjoy your view of God&amp;#8217;s glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width=&#34;25%&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Walking Into Death, Walking Into Life – Ephesians 2:1-10</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/theology/will-of-dead-will-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/theology/will-of-dead-will-of-god/</guid>
      <description>Either I was dead or I wasn’t.
Either I was following the course of this world or I wasn’t.
Either I was following Satan or I wasn’t.
Either I was a son of disobedience or I wasn’t.
If I deny to be any of those things or pretend I was not that bad off, then God did not come to save me.
Luke 5:31-32 And Jesus answered them, “Those who are well have no need of a physician, but those who are sick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: What Shall I Pray? 1 Timothy 1:12-17</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/doxology/influences-what-shall-i-pray-1-timothy-112-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/doxology/influences-what-shall-i-pray-1-timothy-112-17/</guid>
      <description>So in all of this, what shall I pray?
What can I say?
I pray to worship You.
I pray to praise Your holy name forever.
I pray to sing to You.
I pray because I want You.
I pray because I need You near.
I pray because I have no life without You.
I pray because You are my Lord and God.
I pray because You are my Father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: But Who Am I? 1 Chronicles 29:10-18</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/theology/influences-but-who-am-i-1-chronicles-2910-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/theology/influences-but-who-am-i-1-chronicles-2910-18/</guid>
      <description>This was the very first passage I memorized. I picked this passage because I heard this particular verse mentioned in a long list of other verses:
1 Chronicles 29:14 “But who am I, and what is my people, that we should be able thus to offer willingly? For all things come from you, and of your own have we given you.
When I looked up the verse and read it in context, I was blown away from David&amp;#8217;s commencement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: He Saved Us, Titus 3:3-7</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-he-saved-us-titus-33-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-he-saved-us-titus-33-7/</guid>
      <description>All of our sins are laid bare before us.
When we truly see who we really are, we see our shunning of God’s wisdom; ignoring of God’s word; our turning away from His lovely face; our insistence to the crap the world has offer; our addiction to the pains and sickness; and our desires fueled by the love for ourselves at the increase of hate and apathy towards one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Indeed He Says! Romans 9:22-26</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/theology/influences-indeed-he-says-romans-922-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/theology/influences-indeed-he-says-romans-922-26/</guid>
      <description>Romans 9:22-26
What if God, desiring to show his wrath and to make known his power, has endured with much patience vessels of wrath prepared for destruction, in order to make known the riches of his glory for vessels of mercy, which he has prepared beforehand for glory—even us whom he has called, not from the Jews only but also from the Gentiles? As indeed he says in Hosea,
&amp;emsp;“Those who were not my people I will call ‘my people,’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Love Song – Psalm 119</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-love-song-psalm-119/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-love-song-psalm-119/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119 is the love song to God for all time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/record_needle_body_203x152.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-964&#34; title=&#34;record_needle_body_203x152&#34; src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/record_needle_body_203x152.jpg?resize=203%2C152&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;203&#34; height=&#34;152&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It is the extended, smooth-out, quiet storm version. It’s the singer’s voice dropping to a bass-baritone. It is the passion towards the one the writer loves. It has the ultra-smooth whispers of sweet desires over the radio waves and the crackle of the vinyl in the extended beatdrop. This song is the mixtape track that says everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was made for one person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it is all about His righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The psalmist is not in love with the law. The love was never directed towards a bunch of rules that they could never perfectly do. If I fail to do them all correctly, I have fallen. If I break one rule, I have failed. If fail to do one rule, then I separated from my precious love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I realized that there were some laws that supersedes my material reality, I have already failed. If I never realized the laws, then surely I have gone against my conscience and &lt;em&gt;seared&lt;/em&gt; my conscience from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damned if I do and damned if I don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What hope do I have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can I have faith?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, but I have love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have love for the One who did it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the King who wrote the laws and perfectly followed them to the letter. And my lawgiving King doesn’t hold His law over my head. Instead, He showers me with His banner of love over my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My King has me. He has it all. He just needs me to look into His eyes, hold his hands, and trust Him when He says, “Everything’s gonna be alright.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width=&#34;25%&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Sometime Around 33 A.D., This Was Prayed Over Me – John 17</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-sometime-around-33-a-d-this-was-prayed-over-me-john-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-sometime-around-33-a-d-this-was-prayed-over-me-john-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/christ-in-gesthemane-01.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-190&#34; title=&#34;christ-in-gesthemane-01&#34; src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/christ-in-gesthemane-01.jpg?resize=300%2C238&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;238&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/christ-in-gesthemane-01.jpg?resize=300%2C238 300w, https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/christ-in-gesthemane-01.jpg?w=423 423w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Romans 8:34 Who is to condemn? &lt;strong&gt;Christ Jesus is the one who died—more than that, who was raised—who is at the right hand of God, &lt;em&gt;who indeed is interceding for us&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width=&#34;25%&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>