<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matt Chandler on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/tags/matt-chandler/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Matt Chandler on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/tags/matt-chandler/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>God is Not Hoping That You Will Be The Best That You Can Be</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/god-is-not-hoping-you-can-be-the-best-that-you-can-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/god-is-not-hoping-you-can-be-the-best-that-you-can-be/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The idea behind moral, therapeutic deism is that we are able to earn favor with God and justify ourselves before God by virtue of our behavior. This mode of thinking is religious, even ‘Christian’ in its content, but it’s more about self-actualization and self-fulfillment, and it posits a God who does not so much intervene and redeem but basically hangs out behind the scenes, cheering on your you-ness and hoping you pick up on the clues he’s left to become the best you can be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In 50 Trillion Years</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/in-50-trillion-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/in-50-trillion-years/</guid>
      <description>So if you and I exist in some way or another 50 trillion years from now, and we exist from now until then and beyond, then this 50-trillion-year mark is far more important than what happens to you at 8, at 16, at 42, at 61, or at any point in this little dew-in-the-morning, gone-in-the-afternoon life of yours and mine. So really and honestly, the cruelty of God would be to protect you here and now in such a way that would rob you of eternal life into the 50-trillion-year mark and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Comfort: God Knows We Don’t</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/take-comfort-god-knows-we-dont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/take-comfort-god-knows-we-dont/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Evil estimates magma to be the temperature of &amp;#8220;boiling hot&amp;#8221;. &amp;#8220;In addition to the exhaustive depth of his knowledge is the exhaustive breadth of his knowledge. God is aware of every event that has ever occurred and will ever occur, and he knows completely how each event affects other events that create still more events that roll into other events and so on and so forth ad infinitum. From the velocity of every butterfly’s flapping wings at every second to the exact amount of magma to the microgram flowing out of every volcano above and under sea level, he spans it all simultaneously and precisely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Does The Gospel Start With?</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/where-does-the-good-news-start-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/where-does-the-good-news-start-with/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The great message that we call the gospel begins, then, not with us, or our need, or even the meeting of that need, but with the writer of the news and the sender of its heralds: God himself.&amp;#8221;
 Matt Chandler. _The Explicit Gospel_. 1st ed. Crossway, 2012. 21.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can’t Tell Me Philosophy Affects Us—Just Look at the Church</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/you-cant-tell-me-philosophy-affects-us-just-look-at-the-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/you-cant-tell-me-philosophy-affects-us-just-look-at-the-church/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;In the 1950s and ’60s, rationalism began to erode evangelical scholarship, from academia on down, resulting in a liberal theology that crept into seminaries and churches. As a defensive maneuver, conservatives grabbed hold of the pendulum and swung it all the way over to the right side, wanting to believe they’d got “God” down to a science, his thoughts and ways explainable like mathematics. Romans 11:33 tells us instead that God is incomprehensibly immense, exceedingly expansive, and eternally powerful, and so much so that time and time again our response to many of the things of God ought to be “I don’t know.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>