<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parenting on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/categories/parenting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parenting on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 16:41:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/categories/parenting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raising Preachers of the Gospel</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/preaching/raising-preachers-of-the-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 16:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/preaching/raising-preachers-of-the-gospel/</guid>
      <description>When I met these two girls about four years ago, I knew two things:
 They are thieves. They love to take your heart and never give it back. They love the Bible.  If you know me, I have many kids. But none of my kids had that spark, that interest&amp;#8230; that proclivity that these two girls had in the word of God.
From the moment, I met them I knew that I would give them every ounce of theological and doctrinal training, every note, every book, every podcast, every video that I had not just simply to raise preachers and pastors—although that is a small part of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bittersweet Like  Chocolates</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/parenting/bittersweet-like-chocolates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/parenting/bittersweet-like-chocolates/</guid>
      <description>There comes a time and place when your kids won&amp;#8217;t need you anymore. I am not talking about when they hit 18 years old and out the door one last time. I am talking about little milestones along the way.
Take for instance, Elijah.
We call him Bubs because he is. This is our Bubs aka Bubba aka Bubba Lub aka Too Bubs aka Bubbiest. He does everything full throttle with the nitro line wide open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Ivy</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/personal/love-letter-ivy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/personal/love-letter-ivy/</guid>
      <description>Ivy, my sweetest and most precious girl,
I could not begin to tell you what we were going through when we heard about you: death of my father, my grandmother, your Momma&amp;#8217;s grandfather, and the passing away of your sister, Olivia.
These storms and the pains that we were going through in our own heart and souls tested the mettle of your Momma and Papa&amp;#8217;s marriage and relationship and shook the foundation of our family to the bedrock.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>