<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Hole in Our Holiness on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/the-hole-in-our-holiness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Hole in Our Holiness on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/the-hole-in-our-holiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring a Lunch Box</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/bring-a-lunch-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/bring-a-lunch-box/</guid>
      <description>Then there’s the reality that holiness is plain hard work, and we’re often lazy. We like our sins, and dying to them is painful. Almost everything is easier than growing in godliness. So we try and fail, try and fail, and then give up. It’s easier to sign a petition protesting man’s inhumanity to man than to love your neighbor as yourself. It’s one thing to graduate from college ready to change the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Make A Difference</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/does-make-a-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/does-make-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>Some pollsters and pundits look at the worldliness of the church and conclude that being born again doesn’t make a difference in how people live. We should come to the opposite conclusion; namely, that many churchgoers are not truly born again.
 Kevin DeYoung. The Hole in Our Holiness: Filling the Gap Between Gospel Passion and the Pursuit of Godliness. Crossway, 2012. 18.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Their Joys Are Not Your Joys</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/their-joys-are-not-your-joys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/their-joys-are-not-your-joys/</guid>
      <description>Holiness is written on everything in heaven. And nothing unholy can enter into this heaven (Rev. 21:27; Heb. 12:14). Even if you could enter heaven without holiness, what would you do? What joy would you feel there? What holy man or woman of God would you sit down with for fellowship? Their pleasures are not your pleasures. Their character is not your character. What they love, you do not love.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>