<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Love Letters on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/love-letters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Love Letters on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 12:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/love-letters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Ivy</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/personal/love-letter-ivy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/personal/love-letter-ivy/</guid>
      <description>Ivy, my sweetest and most precious girl,
I could not begin to tell you what we were going through when we heard about you: death of my father, my grandmother, your Momma&amp;#8217;s grandfather, and the passing away of your sister, Olivia.
These storms and the pains that we were going through in our own heart and souls tested the mettle of your Momma and Papa&amp;#8217;s marriage and relationship and shook the foundation of our family to the bedrock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Elijah</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letters-elijah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letters-elijah/</guid>
      <description>My sweet Elijah,
Before you were born, I would look at your beautiful, gorgeous mom and I would look at myself and kept thinking, “What is Elijah going to look like?” Most of all, what is Elijah going to be like—as a baby, a toddler, a kid, a teenager, an adult and even an old man. I was so curious about your life and all the possibilities therein.
I know this much to be true: I loved you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Emma</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-emma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-emma/</guid>
      <description>My beautiful Emma,
You are far more than what people see. Or as the saying goes, you are more than the sum of your parts. When people see you, they may see only your incredible beauty. And as wonderful as your beauty may be, your mind, heart and soul runs so much deeper.
This much I know of you: You are a scholar of the highest rank. Honestly, you are every bit the academic that I wish was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Gabe</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-gabe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-gabe/</guid>
      <description>My great Gabriel,
You know what I love about you? You are completely different compared to your other siblings. You are nothing like your brothers and sisters. Heck, you are nothing like any person I have ever met.
First and foremost, you are marked with intense amount of passion. For art and singing, I could talk on end about that but that is not what I am talking about. What I do know, see and feel every single day is your passion to love and to give love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Grace</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-grace/</guid>
      <description>My strongest Grace,
Your love is tremendous. I love the way you adore others. I love that you are always thoughtful of me. Every time you say goodbye, you always give me a hug. For that love, thank you.
After you go off to sleep, your mom and I stay up and talk about our children—all of the hopes and dreams that we have for you kids. I love it when we get to talk about you because I love bragging on you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Griffen</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-griffen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-griffen/</guid>
      <description>My wisest Griffen,
Knowing you has been one of the greatest honors of my life. It is pure joy being with you, getting to raise you, being in family with you, and getting the chance to love you. In more ways than I could possibly count, you are the best parts of me (and we are not even blood related). I am smart but you are smarter. I have some wisdom but you are wiser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Yusef</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-yusef/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-yusef/</guid>
      <description>My incredible Yusef,
You are my first child. You are my first born. You are my first son. And for a decade, you were my only kid.
I have been always quick to tell you how much of a father I was not to you when you were a baby but I have never gone into too many details. When you were younger, oh, I was around. I never left to go anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>