<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thanksgiving on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/tags/thanksgiving/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thanksgiving on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 16:30:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/tags/thanksgiving/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Give Thanks</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/give-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 16:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/give-thanks/</guid>
      <description>Give thanks with a grateful heart Give thanks to the Holy One Give thanks because He&#39;s given Jesus Christ, His Son And now let the weak say, &#34;I am strong&#34; Let the poor say, &#34;I am rich&#34;, Because of what the Lord has done for us. Give thanks. &amp;#8211; Don Moen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doxology</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/doxology/doxology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/doxology/doxology/</guid>
      <description>Awake, my soul, and with the sun Thy daily stage of duty run; Shake off dull sloth, and joyful rise, To pay thy morning sacrifice. Thy precious time misspent, redeem, Each present day thy last esteem, Improve thy talent with due care; For the great day thyself prepare. By influence of the Light divine Let thy own light to others shine. Reflect all Heaven’s propitious ways In ardent love, and cheerful praise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving For Who You Are—You Are God Alone</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-who-you-are-you-are-god-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-who-you-are-you-are-god-alone/</guid>
      <description>I thank him who has given me strength, Christ Jesus our Lord, because he judged me faithful, appointing me to his service, though formerly I was a blasphemer, persecutor, and insolent opponent. But I received mercy because I had acted ignorantly in unbelief, and the grace of our Lord overflowed for me with the faith and love that are in Christ Jesus. The saying is trustworthy and deserving of full acceptance, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Adoption—Family</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-adoption-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-adoption-family/</guid>
      <description>John 14:18-21
“I will not leave you as orphans; I will come to you. Yet a little while and the world will see me no more, but you will see me. Because I live, you also will live. In that day you will know that I am in my Father, and you in me, and I in you. Whoever has my commandments and keeps them, he it is who loves me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Blood—Expiation</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-blood-expiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-blood-expiation/</guid>
      <description>Leviticus 6:28
And the earthenware vessel in which it is boiled shall be broken. But if it is boiled in a bronze vessel, that shall be scoured and rinsed in water.
Leviticus 16:21-22
And Aaron shall lay both his hands on the head of the live goat, and confess over it all the iniquities of the people of Israel, and all their transgressions, all their sins. And he shall put them on the head of the goat and send it away into the wilderness by the hand of a man who is in readiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Choice—Election</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-choice-election/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-choice-election/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 90:2
Before the mountains were brought forth,
or ever you had formed the earth and the world,
from everlasting to everlasting you are God.
Ephesians 1:3-10
Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Faith—Trustfulness</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-faith-trustfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-faith-trustfulness/</guid>
      <description>Genesis 24:27
and said, “Blessed be the LORD, the God of my master Abraham, who has not forsaken his steadfast love and his faithfulness toward my master. As for me, the LORD has led me in the way to the house of my master’s kinsmen.”
Genesis 32:10
I am not worthy of the least of all the deeds of steadfast love and all the faithfulness that you have shown to your servant, for with only my staff I crossed this Jordan, and now I have become two camps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Freedom—Redemption</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-freedom-redemption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-freedom-redemption/</guid>
      <description>Titus 3:3
For we ourselves were once foolish, disobedient, led astray, slaves to various passions and pleasures, passing our days in malice and envy, hated by others and hating one another.
Exodus 6:1-9
But the LORD said to Moses, “Now you shall see what I will do to Pharaoh; for with a strong hand he will send them out, and with a strong hand he will drive them out of his land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Friendship—Reconcilation</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-friendship-reconcilation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-friendship-reconcilation/</guid>
      <description>_Lord, you are more precious than silver.
Lord, you are more costly than gold.
Lord, you are more beautiful than diamonds, and
nothing I desire compares with you._
2 Chronicles 20:7
Did you not, our God, drive out the inhabitants of this land before your people Israel, and give it forever to the descendants of Abraham your friend?
Ruth 1:16-18
But Ruth said, “Do not urge me to leave you or to return from following you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Holiness—High and Lifted Up</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-holiness-high-and-lifted-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-holiness-high-and-lifted-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Leviticus 18:24-22:31&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do not make yourselves unclean by any of these things, for by all these the nations I am driving out before you have become unclean, and the land became unclean, so that I punished its iniquity, and the land vomited out its inhabitants. But you shall keep my statutes and my rules and do none of these abominations, either the native or the stranger who sojourns among you (for the people of the land, who were before you, did all of these abominations, so that the land became unclean), lest the land vomit you out when you make it unclean, as it vomited out the nation that was before you. For everyone who does any of these abominations, the persons who do them shall be cut off from among their people. So keep my charge never to practice any of these abominable customs that were practiced before you, and never to make yourselves unclean by them: I am the Lord your God.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Justification—Exoneration</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-justification-exoneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-justification-exoneration/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 51:4
Against you, you only, have I sinned
and done what is evil in your sight,
so that you may be justified in your words
and blameless in your judgment.
Titus 3:4-7 But when the goodness and loving kindness of God our Savior appeared, he saved us, not because of works done by us in righteousness, but according to his own mercy, by the washing of regeneration and renewal of the Holy Spirit, whom he poured out on us richly through Jesus Christ our Savior, so that being justified by his grace we might become heirs according to the hope of eternal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Love—Affections</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-love-affections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-love-affections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, God created the heavens and the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Chronicles 16:34&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh give thanks to the Lord, for he is good;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for his steadfast love endures forever!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew 5:45 For he makes his sun rise on the evil and on the good, and sends rain on the just and on the unjust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Titus 3:4-7&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when the goodness and loving kindness of God our Savior appeared, he saved us, not because of works done by us in righteousness, but according to his own mercy, by the washing of regeneration and renewal of the Holy Spirit, whom he poured out on us richly through Jesus Christ our Savior, so that being justified by his grace we might become heirs according to the hope of eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Mercies—Propitiation</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-mercies-propitiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-mercies-propitiation/</guid>
      <description>Luke 18:13
But the tax collector, standing far off, would not even lift up his eyes to heaven, but beat his breast, saying, ‘God, be merciful to me, a sinner!’
Leviticus 6:28
And the earthenware vessel in which it is boiled shall be broken. But if it is boiled in a bronze vessel, that shall be scoured and rinsed in water.
Isaiah 53:1-12
Who has believed what he has heard from us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Mind—Repentence</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-mind-repentence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-mind-repentence/</guid>
      <description>Numbers 23:19
God is not man, that he should lie,
or a son of man, that he should change his mind.
Has he said, and will he not do it?
Or has he spoken, and will he not fulfill it?
Deuteronomy 5:29
Oh that they had such a mind as this always, to fear me and to keep all my commandments, that it might go well with them and with their descendants forever!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your New Heart—Regeneration</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-new-heart-regeneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-new-heart-regeneration/</guid>
      <description>Genesis 6:5-6
The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually. And the LORD was sorry that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart.
Lamentations 5:3
We have become orphans, fatherless;
our mothers are like widows.
1 Chronicles 29:15
For we are strangers before you and sojourners, as all our fathers were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Righteousness—Perfection</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-righteousness-perfection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-righteousness-perfection/</guid>
      <description>Isaiah 64:6
We have all become like one who is unclean,
and all our righteous deeds are like a polluted garment.
We all fade like a leaf,
and our iniquities, like the wind, take us away.
Genesis 3:21
And the LORD God made for Adam and for his wife garments of skins and clothed them.
Genesis 6:5-9
The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Weight–Glorification</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-weight-glorification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-weight-glorification/</guid>
      <description>Exodus 14:1-4
Then the LORD said to Moses, “Tell the people of Israel to turn back and encamp in front of Pi-hahiroth, between Migdol and the sea, in front of Baal-zephon; you shall encamp facing it, by the sea. For Pharaoh will say of the people of Israel, ‘They are wandering in the land; the wilderness has shut them in.’ And I will harden Pharaoh’s heart, and he will pursue them, and I will get glory over Pharaoh and all his host, and the Egyptians shall know that I am the LORD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Word—Scriptures</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-word-scriptures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-word-scriptures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John 1:1-5; 14-18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. He was in the beginning with God. All things were made through him, and without him was not any thing made that was made. In him was life, and the life was the light of men. The light shines in the darkness, and the darkness has not overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the Word became flesh and dwelt among us, and we have seen his glory, glory as of the only Son from the Father, full of grace and truth. (John bore witness about him, and cried out, “This was he of whom I said, ‘He who comes after me ranks before me, because he was before me.’”) And from his fullness we have all received, grace upon grace. For the law was given through Moses; grace and truth came through Jesus Christ. No one has ever seen God; the only God, who is at the Father’s side, he has made him known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genesis 3:15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will put enmity between you and the woman,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and between your offspring and her offspring;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;he shall bruise your head,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and you shall bruise his heel.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Work–Sanctification</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-work-sanctification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-work-sanctification/</guid>
      <description>Exodus 29:43
There I will meet with the people of Israel, and it shall be sanctified by my glory.
Exodus 31:13
“You are to speak to the people of Israel and say, ‘Above all you shall keep my Sabbaths, for this is a sign between me and you throughout your generations, that you may know that I, the LORD, sanctify you.
Leviticus 10:3
Then Moses said to Aaron, “This is what the LORD has said, ‘Among those who are near me I will be sanctified, and before all the people I will be glorified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Will Worship The Lamb of Glory</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/doxology/we-will-worship-the-lamb-of-glory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/doxology/we-will-worship-the-lamb-of-glory/</guid>
      <description>We will worship the Lamb of glory, We will worship the King of kings. We will worship the Lamb of glory, We will worship the King. We bless the name of the Lamb of Glory. We bless the name of the King of Kings. We bless the name of the Lamb of Glory. We bless the name of the King. We give all praise to the Lamb of Glory. We give all praise to the King of Kings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are So Good To Me</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/doxology/you-are-so-good-to-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/doxology/you-are-so-good-to-me/</guid>
      <description>You are so good to me You heal my broken heart You are my Father in heaven You ride upon the clouds You lead me to the truth You are the Spirit inside me You are beautiful my sweet, sweet, song  I will sing again   You are my strong melody You are my dancing rhythm You are my perfect rhyme And I want to sing forever  You poured out all your blood You died upon the cross You are my Jesus who loves me You are my Father in heaven You are the Spirit inside me You are the Jesus who loves me And I will sing again… &amp;#8211; 100 Portraits and Waterdeep</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>