<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prayer on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/prayer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prayer on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:00:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/prayer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer: On Earth As Is It In Heaven</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-on-earth-as-is-it-in-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-on-earth-as-is-it-in-heaven/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 73:21–26
When my soul was embittered,
when I was pricked in heart,
I was brutish and ignorant;
I was like a beast toward you.
Nevertheless, I am continually with you;
you hold my right hand.
You guide me with your counsel,
and afterward you will receive me to glory.
Whom have I in heaven but you?
And there is nothing on earth that I desire besides you.
My flesh and my heart may fail,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:5c My Cup Overflows</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-235c-my-cup-overflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 12:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-235c-my-cup-overflows/</guid>
      <description>My Lord, I am reminded of all of your sweet blessings. You are my inheritance. You are my portion. You are my lot. Because you are my Christ, the Son of God, in whom is my All-of-all. My God, you have called me into your family and I share my inheritance. But just as you drank from the cup, I gladly and with great joy drink from the cup. I am yours and your are my Beloved forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer: Your Will Be Done</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-your-will-be-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 12:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-your-will-be-done/</guid>
      <description>Ephesians 1:11-14 In him we have obtained an inheritance, having been predestined according to the purpose of him who works all things according to the counsel of his will, so that we who were the first to hope in Christ might be to the praise of his glory. In him you also, when you heard the word of truth, the gospel of your salvation, and believed in him, were sealed with the promised Holy Spirit, who is the guarantee of our inheritance until we acquire possession of it, to the praise of his glory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:5b The Gift of Your Spirit</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/3821/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 12:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/3821/</guid>
      <description>My God, Because of everything your Son has done for me, I now walk in the power of Your Spiirt. He leads me. He guides me. He teaches me. He reminds me of what You have said. He reminds me of my righteousness. He reminds me that I am your son. More so than that, He is the seal upon my heart and the promise of your strength. And because He dwells in me, I fear no death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer: Your Kingdom Come</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-your-kingdom-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-your-kingdom-come/</guid>
      <description>Matthew 16:15-19 He said to them, “But who do you say that I am?” Simon Peter replied, “You are the Christ, the Son of the living God.” And Jesus answered him, “Blessed are you, Simon Bar-Jonah! For flesh and blood has not revealed this to you, but my Father who is in heaven. And I tell you, you are Peter, and on this rock I will build my church, and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:5a Circumstances Abound</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-235a-circumstances-abound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 12:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-235a-circumstances-abound/</guid>
      <description>My God, I have been crushed and discarded a hundred times. But, I have warred against you thousand more. Yet, you sent your Son to live and die for me. And now I live for you. I will never understand why you saved me, but I only know that because I have sin much I have been forgiven much. Now I know you let me sit at your table, when I should been condemned for treason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer: Hallowed Be Your Name</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-hallowed-be-your-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 12:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-hallowed-be-your-name/</guid>
      <description>Revelation 4:8 And the four living creatures, each of them with six wings, are full of eyes all around and within, and day and night they never cease to say, “Holy, holy, holy, is the Lord God Almighty,
who was and is and is to come!” Hallowed be Your name — Because You are my good Father in heaven, I now get to say this: You are holy. You are far above, far from all of my sin, and the sins of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:4d The Comfort of Your Power</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-234d-the-comfort-of-your-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-234d-the-comfort-of-your-power/</guid>
      <description>My God, It is the might and strength of your protection on my life and heart that gives me peace. That no other thing in all of creation can ever separate me from you in the name of your Son, Christ Jesus my Lord. Nothing ever compares to you. You alone are powerful and worthy. Thank you for protecting me. Thank you for loving me. Thank you for calling me your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer: Our Father in Heaven</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-our-father-in-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-our-father-in-heaven/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:14-17 For all who are led by the Spirit of God are sons of God. For you did not receive the spirit of slavery to fall back into fear, but you have received the Spirit of adoption as sons, by whom we cry, “Abba! Father!” The Spirit himself bears witness with our spirit that we are children of God, and if children, then heirs—heirs of God and fellow heirs with Christ, provided we suffer with him in order that we may also be glorified with him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:4c You Are With Me</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-234c-you-are-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 12:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-234c-you-are-with-me/</guid>
      <description>My Lord and my God, Even when I was dead, you called my name. Even when I was lost, you found me. Even when I was blind, you touched my eyes and opened them to see. Even when I was deaf, you opened them to hear. Even when I was hard-hearted, you took my heart of stone and gave me your tender heart. Even when I couldn’t know you, you gave me Your Spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer: Do What He Does</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/do-what-he-does/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 12:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/do-what-he-does/</guid>
      <description>Ezekiel 11:19-20 And I will give them one heart, and a new spirit I will put within them. I will remove the heart of stone from their flesh and give them a heart of flesh, that they may walk in my statutes and keep my rules and obey them. And they shall be my people, and I will be their God. Do what He does  I look up to You, my Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 12:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer/</guid>
      <description>Pray then like this:
“Our Father in heaven,
hallowed be Your name.
Your kingdom come,
Your will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our debts,
as we also have forgiven our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil. For if you forgive others their trespasses, your heavenly Father will also forgive you, but if you do not forgive others their trespasses, neither will your Father forgive your trespasses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:4a Through the Valley of the Shadow of Death</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-0234a-through-the-valley-of-the-shadow-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-0234a-through-the-valley-of-the-shadow-of-death/</guid>
      <description>My Great God,
How many times have you rescued me from not only eternal death but certain death and doom?
How many times have I sinned that did and did not lead to my death?
The answer is countless. The truth is infinite.
But yet, you are my great God and Savior! I have fallen into the abyssmal pit too many times to count. But because of your grace upon grace, you were deeper still!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:3b He leads me in paths of righteousness for his name’s sake</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-0233b-he-leads-me-in-paths-of-righteousness-for-his-names-sake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-0233b-he-leads-me-in-paths-of-righteousness-for-his-names-sake/</guid>
      <description>My Precious God, I am often reminded of my sinful ways of the past. As the vines grew up from my heart and slowly and surely tightened around my neck as I continuously die without thought But you, my God, broke the spell of the sin over my life. But time after time, I see those weeds grow. I feel the cancer thriving in my heart. I sense the sin that crouches for me and waits to pierce my soul with his poison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:3a He Restores My Soul</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-23_3a-he-restores-my-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-23_3a-he-restores-my-soul/</guid>
      <description>My Lord, I perish without you. I cannot live without you. Apart from you., the hole in my inner being remained infinitely empty. Without you, I strived and pushed and pulled and made idols and did whatever I need to do in order to fill my soul. But all of it comes up empty. But you, O Lord, not only fills my heart to the brim but gives my soul brand new life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:2b He Leads Me Beside Still Waters</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-232b-he-leads-me-beside-still-waters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 12:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-232b-he-leads-me-beside-still-waters/</guid>
      <description>My Lord, You are the fountain of true life. I am dead without you. It is not that I can find this water on my own. For I am lost. and, my soul is dried-up and dead. I have no wisdom, strength, or spirit to find you. But you, O Lord, rescued me. You have brought me into your life and in your life alone, I am fully alive. My soul is no longer dried in sin but restored, covered, and filled with your never-ending grace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:2a He makes me lie down in green pastures</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-232a-he-makes-me-lie-down-in-green-pastures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 12:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-232a-he-makes-me-lie-down-in-green-pastures/</guid>
      <description>My Lord, You are the Prince of Peace. Where you are, there I find satisfaction of my wearied soul and find perfect peace where I can truly rest. Apart from you, I die and I perish. Away from you, I am only tormented by confusion and despair. Without you, there is nothing but destructions by my own hands and by everything around me. But you, O Lord, call me to enter through you and abide in you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:1b I Shall Not Want</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-231b-i-shall-not-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 12:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-231b-i-shall-not-want/</guid>
      <description>My Lord Above, I thank you for your perfect provision. You are my Good Father in heaven and because I am your child, you have always provided for me. When I was younger, I wanted many things but you did not provide them. But looking back, those things I wanted would have harmed me or cause me to turn away from you. But what you have always done is gave something even better, which turned out to be actually good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:1a The Lord Is My Shepherd</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/psalm-231a-the-lord-is-my-shepherd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 12:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/psalm-231a-the-lord-is-my-shepherd/</guid>
      <description>You are my Good Shepherd. You fled the ninety-nine in order to come rescue me, when I could not possibly rescue myself. You saved me from certain damnation, you’ve rescued me from the slaughter. You’ve taken all of my sin, and you let the wrath of Father fall upon your heart You bled out for me, so that I might live forever. Lord, keep me in your care, I pray that you keep good shepherds to care and feed me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 22:25-31</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2225-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 12:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2225-31/</guid>
      <description>My Worthy Lord,
Let my words and my songs be a sweetness to your ears.
For I know that you sit on the throne of our praises because you are the God who alone saves.
I know that not only are you willing and able to save, you and you alone are the only one who is mighty to save.
So I praise you with all of my breath and strength and life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 22:22-24</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2222-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2222-24/</guid>
      <description>My God in Heaven,
There is none like you!
You are God who sits high above all of my sins, my hardness, my wickedness, my trespasses and my calamity. You are exalted far above all of my gods.
But in your steadfast love, abounding grace, and tender mercies, you saved me! You sent your son, Jesus Christ, to come live and die for me. More than that, your Son rose from the grave and conquered all of the sins, hell, Satan, demons, and death once and for all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 22:19-21</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2219-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 12:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2219-21/</guid>
      <description>Almighty God,
Who are you, my Lord, whose glory fills the entire earth? Whether I am in the heavens or make my bed in hell, you are there with me. If I ascend the mountain of your glory or wander in the desert of the wilderness, you are face to face and closer than a whisper.
My God, you are never far! You are with me! Always. While I might feel desperate or despair sadness or anger or happiness, you are with me and within me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 22:12-18</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2212-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2212-18/</guid>
      <description>Dear God,
My enemies are on all sides and their attacks are relentless, you are my protector.
When lions clamp down on my guts, you are the teeth-breaker and my healer.
When I am buried, you call me out of the ground.
When I was dead in my sins, you lived, died, and rose alive so that I might live.
You have never left me.
You have always been with me even when I did not know nor loved you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 22:6-11</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-22-6-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 12:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-22-6-11/</guid>
      <description>My Lord,
Who am I that I have been rejected a million times and despised a million times more?
You say, “Speak of my love” and it falls on deaf ears. You say, “Speak of my power” and it means little to the strong. You say, “Speak of my glory” and their eyes remain blind.
However, you saved me. You made me with your hands. You are the one who started my heartbeat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 22: 1-5</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-22-1-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 12:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-22-1-5/</guid>
      <description>God!
Where are you?
I am in trouble!
Sin and wickedness have surrounded me. Everything goes dark and cold. Satan and his minions look upon my flesh with lust and hunger.
Temptations are too much. I cannot do battle. My muscles are weak, small, and frail.
I cry and scream: HELP ME, O GOD!
But you are my powerful Champion. You are the people’s Savior. You are invincible. You are forever strong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 21</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-21/</guid>
      <description>My Lord and My God,
My focus is far from you, the one who sets up Kings and puts them down.
I have been distracted by the choosing of kings rather to place my focus on the King of kings.
It is in you, O Lord, where my strength resides
my salvation is present
my heart&amp;#8217;s desire
my soul&amp;#8217;s fulfillment.
Be my provision. Be my grace. Be my mercy.
Be my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pastor’s Promise</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/a-pastors-promise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/a-pastors-promise/</guid>
      <description>Having been made an overseer by the Lord Jesus Christ,
affirmed as such by His Church,
and enabled solely by His grace,
I commit to live in a manner worthy of His calling,
loving Him with all my heart, soul and mind,
always on guard for myself that I maintain a testimony that is above reproach;
I commit to preach His Word,
standing ready in season and out of season,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Elijah</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letters-elijah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letters-elijah/</guid>
      <description>My sweet Elijah,
Before you were born, I would look at your beautiful, gorgeous mom and I would look at myself and kept thinking, “What is Elijah going to look like?” Most of all, what is Elijah going to be like—as a baby, a toddler, a kid, a teenager, an adult and even an old man. I was so curious about your life and all the possibilities therein.
I know this much to be true: I loved you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Emma</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-emma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-emma/</guid>
      <description>My beautiful Emma,
You are far more than what people see. Or as the saying goes, you are more than the sum of your parts. When people see you, they may see only your incredible beauty. And as wonderful as your beauty may be, your mind, heart and soul runs so much deeper.
This much I know of you: You are a scholar of the highest rank. Honestly, you are every bit the academic that I wish was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Gabe</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-gabe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-gabe/</guid>
      <description>My great Gabriel,
You know what I love about you? You are completely different compared to your other siblings. You are nothing like your brothers and sisters. Heck, you are nothing like any person I have ever met.
First and foremost, you are marked with intense amount of passion. For art and singing, I could talk on end about that but that is not what I am talking about. What I do know, see and feel every single day is your passion to love and to give love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Grace</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-grace/</guid>
      <description>My strongest Grace,
Your love is tremendous. I love the way you adore others. I love that you are always thoughtful of me. Every time you say goodbye, you always give me a hug. For that love, thank you.
After you go off to sleep, your mom and I stay up and talk about our children—all of the hopes and dreams that we have for you kids. I love it when we get to talk about you because I love bragging on you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Griffen</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-griffen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-griffen/</guid>
      <description>My wisest Griffen,
Knowing you has been one of the greatest honors of my life. It is pure joy being with you, getting to raise you, being in family with you, and getting the chance to love you. In more ways than I could possibly count, you are the best parts of me (and we are not even blood related). I am smart but you are smarter. I have some wisdom but you are wiser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Letter: Yusef</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-yusef/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/love-letter-yusef/</guid>
      <description>My incredible Yusef,
You are my first child. You are my first born. You are my first son. And for a decade, you were my only kid.
I have been always quick to tell you how much of a father I was not to you when you were a baby but I have never gone into too many details. When you were younger, oh, I was around. I never left to go anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 51: Confession and Repentance</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/psalm-51-confession-and-repentance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/psalm-51-confession-and-repentance/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 51  Have mercy on me, O God, according to your steadfast love; according to your abundant mercy blot out my transgressions. Wash me thoroughly from my iniquity, and cleanse me from my sin! For I know my transgressions, and my sin is ever before me. Against you, you only, have I sinned and done what is evil in your sight, so that you may be justified in your words and blameless in your judgment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scared Shitless</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/scared-shitless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/scared-shitless/</guid>
      <description>I honestly thought they would have done the right thing.
I honestly thought there would have been justice for Mike Brown and every other person of color who have been gunned down by the police.
But America has made it abundantly clear that we will remain a hateful, ignorant country.
On this day of Thanksgiving, I give thanks to God for the mercy and grace that He has given me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That Satan Himself May Understand</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/that-satan-himself-may-understand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/that-satan-himself-may-understand/</guid>
      <description>If Satan fume and roar against you, whether it be against your bodies by persecution, or inward in your conscience by a spiritual battle, do not be discouraged, as though you were less acceptable in God’s presence, or that Satan might at any time prevail against you. No! Your temptations and storms that arise so suddenly argue and witness that the seed that is sown has fallen on good ground, has begun to take root, and shall, by God’s grace, bring forth fruit abundantly in due season and convenient time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>