<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exegetical Fallacies on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/exegetical-fallacies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exegetical Fallacies on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/exegetical-fallacies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cannot Be Taken Lightly</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/cannot-be-taken-lightly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/cannot-be-taken-lightly/</guid>
      <description>This study is important because exegetical fallacies are painfully painfully frequent among us—among us whose God-given grace and responsibility is the faithful proclamation of the Word of God. Make a mistake in the interpretation of one of Shakespeare&amp;#8217;s plays, falsely scan a piece of Spenserian verse, and there is unlikely to be entailment of eternal consequence; but we cannot lightly accept a similar laxity in the interpretation of Scripture. We are dealing with God&amp;#8217;s thoughts: we are obligated to take the greatest pains to understand them truly and to explain them clearly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Preciousness of the Word</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-preciousness-of-the-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-preciousness-of-the-word/</guid>
      <description>Careful handling of the Bible will enable us to &amp;#8220;hear&amp;#8221; it a little better. It is all too easy to read the traditional interpretations and invest them with a false, even idolatrous, degree of certainty. Because traditions are reshaped as they are passed on, after a while we may drift far from God&amp;#8217;s Word while still insisting all our theological opinions are &amp;#8220;biblical&amp;#8221; and therefore true. If when we are in such a state we study the Bible uncritically, more than likely it will simply reinforce our errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Haven’t Arrived Yet</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/we-havent-arrived-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/we-havent-arrived-yet/</guid>
      <description>The sum total of all useful exegetical knowledge did not reach the apex during the Reformation, or even in the past century. As much as we can must learn from our theological forebears, we face the harsh realities of this century; and neither nostalgia nor the preferred position of an ostrich will remove either the threats or the opportunities that summon our exegetical skills to new rigor. D. A. Carson. Exegetical Fallacies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>