<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Lord&#39;s Prayer on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/the-lords-prayer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Lord&#39;s Prayer on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:00:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/the-lords-prayer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer: On Earth As Is It In Heaven</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-on-earth-as-is-it-in-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-on-earth-as-is-it-in-heaven/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 73:21–26
When my soul was embittered,
when I was pricked in heart,
I was brutish and ignorant;
I was like a beast toward you.
Nevertheless, I am continually with you;
you hold my right hand.
You guide me with your counsel,
and afterward you will receive me to glory.
Whom have I in heaven but you?
And there is nothing on earth that I desire besides you.
My flesh and my heart may fail,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer: Your Will Be Done</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-your-will-be-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 12:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-your-will-be-done/</guid>
      <description>Ephesians 1:11-14 In him we have obtained an inheritance, having been predestined according to the purpose of him who works all things according to the counsel of his will, so that we who were the first to hope in Christ might be to the praise of his glory. In him you also, when you heard the word of truth, the gospel of your salvation, and believed in him, were sealed with the promised Holy Spirit, who is the guarantee of our inheritance until we acquire possession of it, to the praise of his glory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer: Your Kingdom Come</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-your-kingdom-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-your-kingdom-come/</guid>
      <description>Matthew 16:15-19 He said to them, “But who do you say that I am?” Simon Peter replied, “You are the Christ, the Son of the living God.” And Jesus answered him, “Blessed are you, Simon Bar-Jonah! For flesh and blood has not revealed this to you, but my Father who is in heaven. And I tell you, you are Peter, and on this rock I will build my church, and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer: Hallowed Be Your Name</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-hallowed-be-your-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 12:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-hallowed-be-your-name/</guid>
      <description>Revelation 4:8 And the four living creatures, each of them with six wings, are full of eyes all around and within, and day and night they never cease to say, “Holy, holy, holy, is the Lord God Almighty,
who was and is and is to come!” Hallowed be Your name — Because You are my good Father in heaven, I now get to say this: You are holy. You are far above, far from all of my sin, and the sins of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer: Our Father in Heaven</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-our-father-in-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer-our-father-in-heaven/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:14-17 For all who are led by the Spirit of God are sons of God. For you did not receive the spirit of slavery to fall back into fear, but you have received the Spirit of adoption as sons, by whom we cry, “Abba! Father!” The Spirit himself bears witness with our spirit that we are children of God, and if children, then heirs—heirs of God and fellow heirs with Christ, provided we suffer with him in order that we may also be glorified with him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer: Do What He Does</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/do-what-he-does/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 12:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/do-what-he-does/</guid>
      <description>Ezekiel 11:19-20 And I will give them one heart, and a new spirit I will put within them. I will remove the heart of stone from their flesh and give them a heart of flesh, that they may walk in my statutes and keep my rules and obey them. And they shall be my people, and I will be their God. Do what He does  I look up to You, my Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lord’s Prayer</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 12:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/the-lords-prayer/</guid>
      <description>Pray then like this:
“Our Father in heaven,
hallowed be Your name.
Your kingdom come,
Your will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our debts,
as we also have forgiven our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil. For if you forgive others their trespasses, your heavenly Father will also forgive you, but if you do not forgive others their trespasses, neither will your Father forgive your trespasses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>