<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abounded All The More on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/tags/abounded-all-the-more/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abounded All The More on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/tags/abounded-all-the-more/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Sola Fide</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-fide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-fide/</guid>
      <description>[][1]Martin Luther by Lucas Cranach dem Älteren Genesis 15:1-6 After these things the word of the LORD came to Abram in a vision: “Fear not, Abram, I am your shield; your reward shall be very great.” But Abram said, “O Lord GOD, what will you give me, for I continue childless, and the heir of my house is Eliezer of Damascus?” And Abram said, “Behold, you have given me no offspring, and a member of my household will be my heir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Sola Gratia</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-gratia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-gratia/</guid>
      <description>[][1]William Tyndale Genesis 3:21
And the LORD God made for Adam and for his wife garments of skins and clothed them.
Genesis 6:5-9
The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually. And the LORD was sorry that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart. So the LORD said, “I will blot out man whom I have created from the face of the land, man and animals and creeping things and birds of the heavens, for I am sorry that I have made them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Sola Scriptura</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-scriptura/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-scriptura/</guid>
      <description>2 Timothy 3:16-4:5
All Scripture is breathed out by God and profitable for teaching, for reproof, for correction, and for training in righteousness, that the man of God may be complete, equipped for every good work.
I charge you in the presence of God and of Christ Jesus, who is to judge the living and the dead, and by his appearing and his kingdom: preach the word; be ready in season and out of season; reprove, rebuke, and exhort, with complete patience and teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Soli Deo Gloria</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-soli-deo-gloria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-soli-deo-gloria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/tulip_2-wallpaper.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-984&#34; title=&#34;tulip_2-wallpaper&#34; src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/tulip_2-wallpaper.jpg?resize=159%2C300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;159&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/tulip_2-wallpaper.jpg?resize=159%2C300 159w, https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/tulip_2-wallpaper.jpg?w=407 407w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 159px) 100vw, 159px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Exodus 33:18-23&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moses said, “Please show me your glory.” And he said, “I will make all my goodness pass before you and will proclaim before you my name ‘The LORD.’ And I will be gracious to whom I will be gracious, and will show mercy on whom I will show mercy. But,” he said, “you cannot see my face, for man shall not see me and live.” And the LORD said, “Behold, there is a place by me where you shall stand on the rock, and while my glory passes by I will put you in a cleft of the rock, and I will cover you with my hand until I have passed by. Then I will take away my hand, and you shall see my back, but my face shall not be seen.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leviticus 9:6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And Moses said, “This is the thing that the LORD commanded you to do, that the glory of the LORD may appear to you.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Chronicles 29:10-18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore David blessed the LORD in the presence of all the assembly. And David said: “Blessed are you, O LORD, the God of Israel our father, forever and ever. Yours, O LORD, is the greatness and the power and the glory and the victory and the majesty, for all that is in the heavens and in the earth is yours. Yours is the kingdom, O LORD, and you are exalted as head above all. Both riches and honor come from you, and you rule over all. In your hand are power and might, and in your hand it is to make great and to give strength to all. And now we thank you, our God, and praise your glorious name.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“But who am I, and what is my people, that we should be able thus to offer willingly? For all things come from you, and of your own have we given you. For we are strangers before you and sojourners, as all our fathers were. Our days on the earth are like a shadow, and there is no abiding.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O LORD our God, all this abundance that we have provided for building you a house for your holy name comes from your hand and is all your own. I know, my God, that you test the heart and have pleasure in uprightness. In the uprightness of my heart I have freely offered all these things, and now I have seen your people, who are present here, offering freely and joyously to you. O LORD, the God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel, our fathers, keep forever such purposes and thoughts in the hearts of your people, and direct their hearts toward you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Solus Christus</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-solus-christus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-solus-christus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure id=&#34;attachment_1180&#34; style=&#34;width: 191px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube.jpg?resize=191%2C300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube&#34; width=&#34;191&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1180&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube.jpg?resize=191%2C300 191w, https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube.jpg?w=319 319w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 191px) 100vw, 191px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;Corpus Hypercubus by Salvador Dalí&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;Genesis 3:15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**I will put enmity between you and the woman, and between your offspring and her offspring; he shall bruise your head,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and you shall bruise his heel.”**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exodus 3:14&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God said to Moses, “I Am Who I Am” And he said, “Say this to the people of Israel, ‘I Am&amp;#8217; has sent me to you.’”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leviticus 16:21-22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And Aaron shall lay both his hands on the head of the live goat, and confess over it all the iniquities of the people of Israel, and all their transgressions, all their sins. And he shall put them on the head of the goat and send it away into the wilderness by the hand of a man who is in readiness. The goat shall bear all their iniquities on itself to a remote area, and he shall let the goat go free in the wilderness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>