<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scriptures on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/categories/scriptures/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scriptures on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 19:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/categories/scriptures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Blissful Contentment – Psalm 17:15</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-blissful-contentment-psalm17-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 19:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-blissful-contentment-psalm17-15/</guid>
      <description>A sight for sore eyes.
No words have rang truer except for the Son of Man.
The One God who cross the infinite just to save me.
Now my eyes bleared at the first site of him.
The loveliness of his face.
I look into His eyes and my soul is complete. My heart is joy-filled. My mind now knows fully.
I am content.
I am satisfied.
God is perfect in his work in me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: What Else Can I Say? Psalm 16:11</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-what-else-can-i-say-psalm-1611/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 20:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-what-else-can-i-say-psalm-1611/</guid>
      <description>The God who alone is awesome.
This is Love, Election, Calling, Atonement, Justification, Propitiation, Expiation, Adoption, Sanctification, and Glorification rolled into one.
Even typing these words, meagerly and fumblingly, is drawing away from the sheer beauty, breath snatching, eye-rubbing gorgeousness, ever-swelling joy, tear-pouring grace and heart-bursting love that is this one verse.
Psalm 16:11
**You make known to me the path of life;
in your presence there is fullness of joy;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: The Apex of the Glory of God – Romans 8</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-the-apex-of-the-glory-of-god-romans-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-the-apex-of-the-glory-of-god-romans-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Mount-Everest-1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-928&#34; title=&#34;Mount-Everest-1&#34; src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Mount-Everest-1.jpg?resize=300%2C225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Mount-Everest-1.jpg?resize=300%2C225 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Mount-Everest-1.jpg?w=1024 1024w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;All Scripture read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every instinct preached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every thought taught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any book studied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every sermon heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every theology revealed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every doctrine learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any and all things processed were with Romans 8 in my sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have heard it said, &amp;#8220;The Epistle to the Romans is the Himalayas of the Bible and with Romans 8 is the Everest.&amp;#8221; Martin Luther calls Romans 8, &amp;#8220;the clearest Gospel of them all&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to memorize any passage of Scripture, it is because I wanted to get to where I can memorize Romans 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any passage memorized now is because I am camped out on the summit that is Romans 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memorized it. Dwelled on it. Read about it. Focused on it. Prayed on it. Prayed using it. Recite it. Practiced preaching it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to write a multi-part blog series on the entirety of Romans 8 in a few weeks so I won&amp;#8217;t expand on it here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, enjoy your view of God&amp;#8217;s glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width=&#34;25%&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Sola Fide</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-fide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-fide/</guid>
      <description>[][1]Martin Luther by Lucas Cranach dem Älteren Genesis 15:1-6 After these things the word of the LORD came to Abram in a vision: “Fear not, Abram, I am your shield; your reward shall be very great.” But Abram said, “O Lord GOD, what will you give me, for I continue childless, and the heir of my house is Eliezer of Damascus?” And Abram said, “Behold, you have given me no offspring, and a member of my household will be my heir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Sola Gratia</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-gratia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-gratia/</guid>
      <description>[][1]William Tyndale Genesis 3:21
And the LORD God made for Adam and for his wife garments of skins and clothed them.
Genesis 6:5-9
The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually. And the LORD was sorry that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart. So the LORD said, “I will blot out man whom I have created from the face of the land, man and animals and creeping things and birds of the heavens, for I am sorry that I have made them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Sola Scriptura</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-scriptura/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-scriptura/</guid>
      <description>2 Timothy 3:16-4:5
All Scripture is breathed out by God and profitable for teaching, for reproof, for correction, and for training in righteousness, that the man of God may be complete, equipped for every good work.
I charge you in the presence of God and of Christ Jesus, who is to judge the living and the dead, and by his appearing and his kingdom: preach the word; be ready in season and out of season; reprove, rebuke, and exhort, with complete patience and teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Soli Deo Gloria</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-soli-deo-gloria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-soli-deo-gloria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/tulip_2-wallpaper.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-984&#34; title=&#34;tulip_2-wallpaper&#34; src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/tulip_2-wallpaper.jpg?resize=159%2C300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;159&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/tulip_2-wallpaper.jpg?resize=159%2C300 159w, https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/tulip_2-wallpaper.jpg?w=407 407w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 159px) 100vw, 159px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Exodus 33:18-23&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moses said, “Please show me your glory.” And he said, “I will make all my goodness pass before you and will proclaim before you my name ‘The LORD.’ And I will be gracious to whom I will be gracious, and will show mercy on whom I will show mercy. But,” he said, “you cannot see my face, for man shall not see me and live.” And the LORD said, “Behold, there is a place by me where you shall stand on the rock, and while my glory passes by I will put you in a cleft of the rock, and I will cover you with my hand until I have passed by. Then I will take away my hand, and you shall see my back, but my face shall not be seen.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leviticus 9:6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And Moses said, “This is the thing that the LORD commanded you to do, that the glory of the LORD may appear to you.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Chronicles 29:10-18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore David blessed the LORD in the presence of all the assembly. And David said: “Blessed are you, O LORD, the God of Israel our father, forever and ever. Yours, O LORD, is the greatness and the power and the glory and the victory and the majesty, for all that is in the heavens and in the earth is yours. Yours is the kingdom, O LORD, and you are exalted as head above all. Both riches and honor come from you, and you rule over all. In your hand are power and might, and in your hand it is to make great and to give strength to all. And now we thank you, our God, and praise your glorious name.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“But who am I, and what is my people, that we should be able thus to offer willingly? For all things come from you, and of your own have we given you. For we are strangers before you and sojourners, as all our fathers were. Our days on the earth are like a shadow, and there is no abiding.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O LORD our God, all this abundance that we have provided for building you a house for your holy name comes from your hand and is all your own. I know, my God, that you test the heart and have pleasure in uprightness. In the uprightness of my heart I have freely offered all these things, and now I have seen your people, who are present here, offering freely and joyously to you. O LORD, the God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel, our fathers, keep forever such purposes and thoughts in the hearts of your people, and direct their hearts toward you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Solus Christus</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-solus-christus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-solus-christus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure id=&#34;attachment_1180&#34; style=&#34;width: 191px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube.jpg?resize=191%2C300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube&#34; width=&#34;191&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1180&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube.jpg?resize=191%2C300 191w, https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube.jpg?w=319 319w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 191px) 100vw, 191px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;Corpus Hypercubus by Salvador Dalí&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;Genesis 3:15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**I will put enmity between you and the woman, and between your offspring and her offspring; he shall bruise your head,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and you shall bruise his heel.”**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exodus 3:14&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God said to Moses, “I Am Who I Am” And he said, “Say this to the people of Israel, ‘I Am&amp;#8217; has sent me to you.’”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leviticus 16:21-22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And Aaron shall lay both his hands on the head of the live goat, and confess over it all the iniquities of the people of Israel, and all their transgressions, all their sins. And he shall put them on the head of the goat and send it away into the wilderness by the hand of a man who is in readiness. The goat shall bear all their iniquities on itself to a remote area, and he shall let the goat go free in the wilderness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: He Saved Us, Titus 3:3-7</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-he-saved-us-titus-33-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-he-saved-us-titus-33-7/</guid>
      <description>All of our sins are laid bare before us.
When we truly see who we really are, we see our shunning of God’s wisdom; ignoring of God’s word; our turning away from His lovely face; our insistence to the crap the world has offer; our addiction to the pains and sickness; and our desires fueled by the love for ourselves at the increase of hate and apathy towards one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Jeremiah</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-jeremiah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-jeremiah/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet Jeremiah by Michelangelo BuonarrotiIn and around April 2007, I was saved. In and around May 2007, it occurs to me that I should start reading the Bible. I prayed and I felt like I should start with Jeremiah.
Every since reading Jeremiah, there were four truths that did a number on my freshly renewed mind (oddly enough, Jeremiah 29:11 was not one of them):
 God appoints us to Him before we were born:  Jeremiah 1:4-8 Now the word of the Lord came to me, saying,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Leviticus</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-leviticus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-leviticus/</guid>
      <description>Leviticus is Christology 101.
This might be a strange statement. I know. Stay with me.
When I finally got around into reading Leviticus, I had just finished all the gospels with the crucifixion of our Lord Jesus Christ still being very fresh in my mind.
Then I was reading through Leviticus and as clear as any book as ever been, I knew the main point that God was driving into my soul:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Love Song – Psalm 119</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-love-song-psalm-119/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-love-song-psalm-119/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119 is the love song to God for all time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/record_needle_body_203x152.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-964&#34; title=&#34;record_needle_body_203x152&#34; src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/record_needle_body_203x152.jpg?resize=203%2C152&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;203&#34; height=&#34;152&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It is the extended, smooth-out, quiet storm version. It’s the singer’s voice dropping to a bass-baritone. It is the passion towards the one the writer loves. It has the ultra-smooth whispers of sweet desires over the radio waves and the crackle of the vinyl in the extended beatdrop. This song is the mixtape track that says everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was made for one person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it is all about His righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The psalmist is not in love with the law. The love was never directed towards a bunch of rules that they could never perfectly do. If I fail to do them all correctly, I have fallen. If I break one rule, I have failed. If fail to do one rule, then I separated from my precious love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I realized that there were some laws that supersedes my material reality, I have already failed. If I never realized the laws, then surely I have gone against my conscience and &lt;em&gt;seared&lt;/em&gt; my conscience from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damned if I do and damned if I don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What hope do I have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can I have faith?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, but I have love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have love for the One who did it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the King who wrote the laws and perfectly followed them to the letter. And my lawgiving King doesn’t hold His law over my head. Instead, He showers me with His banner of love over my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My King has me. He has it all. He just needs me to look into His eyes, hold his hands, and trust Him when He says, “Everything’s gonna be alright.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width=&#34;25%&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Ruth</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-ruth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-ruth/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I was given the opportunity to lead a Bible Study. The very first book we studied through was the book of Ruth. Verse by verse. Chapter by chapter.
Given our group consisted of young adults, most of them were single, it was easy to quickly identify with, or want to be identified with, each of the key figures in this little story in the Bible.
Feeling like a stranger in a strange land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Sometime Around 33 A.D., This Was Prayed Over Me – John 17</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-sometime-around-33-a-d-this-was-prayed-over-me-john-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/influences-sometime-around-33-a-d-this-was-prayed-over-me-john-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/christ-in-gesthemane-01.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-190&#34; title=&#34;christ-in-gesthemane-01&#34; src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/christ-in-gesthemane-01.jpg?resize=300%2C238&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;238&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/christ-in-gesthemane-01.jpg?resize=300%2C238 300w, https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/christ-in-gesthemane-01.jpg?w=423 423w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Romans 8:34 Who is to condemn? &lt;strong&gt;Christ Jesus is the one who died—more than that, who was raised—who is at the right hand of God, &lt;em&gt;who indeed is interceding for us&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width=&#34;25%&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just One Thing—That’s All</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/just-one-thing-thats-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/just-one-thing-thats-all/</guid>
      <description>Matthew 28:18-20 And Jesus came and said to them, “All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Go therefore and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father,

&amp;nbsp;
and of the Son,

and of the Holy Spirit,

teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you. And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowing τελοσ or Bust!</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/knowing-%CF%84%CE%B5%CE%BB%CE%BF%CF%83-or-bust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/knowing-%CF%84%CE%B5%CE%BB%CE%BF%CF%83-or-bust/</guid>
      <description>Studying Philosophy, I am wrestling with the meaning and understanding of telos as in teleological arguments or teleology.
For several weeks, I keep running into the Gk. root _telos- _and for weeks, I had to keep looking it up on my iPhone to remind me what it means and more importantly, &amp;#8220;what the sentence is actually saying&amp;#8220;.
And the cement becomes bone-dry when I read this little quote:
&amp;#8220;Moses declared that the law was not too hard for Israel to keep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power of Preaching, Yet, Eternity at Home</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/power-of-preaching-yet-eternity-at-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/power-of-preaching-yet-eternity-at-home/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 51: Confession and Repentance</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/prayer/psalm-51-confession-and-repentance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/prayer/psalm-51-confession-and-repentance/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 51  Have mercy on me, O God, according to your steadfast love; according to your abundant mercy blot out my transgressions. Wash me thoroughly from my iniquity, and cleanse me from my sin! For I know my transgressions, and my sin is ever before me. Against you, you only, have I sinned and done what is evil in your sight, so that you may be justified in your words and blameless in your judgment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalms: I Need You To Tell Me</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/i-need-you-to-tell-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/i-need-you-to-tell-me/</guid>
      <description>O Lord, please say to me, &#34;I am your salvation!&#34; And save me. Psalm 35:1-28</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Separated and High Above</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/separated-and-high-above/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/separated-and-high-above/</guid>
      <description>For you, O LORD, are most high over all the earth; you are exalted far above all gods. O you who love the LORD, hate evil! He preserves the lives of his saints; he delivers them from the hand of the wicked. Light is sown for the righteous, and joy for the upright in heart. Rejoice in the LORD, O you righteous, and give thanks to his holy name! Psalm 97:9-12 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving For Who You Are—You Are God Alone</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-who-you-are-you-are-god-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-who-you-are-you-are-god-alone/</guid>
      <description>I thank him who has given me strength, Christ Jesus our Lord, because he judged me faithful, appointing me to his service, though formerly I was a blasphemer, persecutor, and insolent opponent. But I received mercy because I had acted ignorantly in unbelief, and the grace of our Lord overflowed for me with the faith and love that are in Christ Jesus. The saying is trustworthy and deserving of full acceptance, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Adoption—Family</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-adoption-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-adoption-family/</guid>
      <description>John 14:18-21
“I will not leave you as orphans; I will come to you. Yet a little while and the world will see me no more, but you will see me. Because I live, you also will live. In that day you will know that I am in my Father, and you in me, and I in you. Whoever has my commandments and keeps them, he it is who loves me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Blood—Expiation</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-blood-expiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-blood-expiation/</guid>
      <description>Leviticus 6:28
And the earthenware vessel in which it is boiled shall be broken. But if it is boiled in a bronze vessel, that shall be scoured and rinsed in water.
Leviticus 16:21-22
And Aaron shall lay both his hands on the head of the live goat, and confess over it all the iniquities of the people of Israel, and all their transgressions, all their sins. And he shall put them on the head of the goat and send it away into the wilderness by the hand of a man who is in readiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Calling—Mission</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-calling-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-calling-mission/</guid>
      <description>Genesis 3:15
I will put enmity between you and the woman,
and between your offspring and her offspring;
he shall bruise your head,
and you shall bruise his heel.
Genesis 6:11-22
Now the earth was corrupt in God&amp;#8217;s sight, and the earth was filled with violence. And God saw the earth, and behold, it was corrupt, for all flesh had corrupted their way on the earth. And God said to Noah, “I have determined to make an end of all flesh, for the earth is filled with violence through them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Choice—Election</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-choice-election/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-choice-election/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 90:2
Before the mountains were brought forth,
or ever you had formed the earth and the world,
from everlasting to everlasting you are God.
Ephesians 1:3-10
Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, even as he chose us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and blameless before him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Faith—Trustfulness</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-faith-trustfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-faith-trustfulness/</guid>
      <description>Genesis 24:27
and said, “Blessed be the LORD, the God of my master Abraham, who has not forsaken his steadfast love and his faithfulness toward my master. As for me, the LORD has led me in the way to the house of my master’s kinsmen.”
Genesis 32:10
I am not worthy of the least of all the deeds of steadfast love and all the faithfulness that you have shown to your servant, for with only my staff I crossed this Jordan, and now I have become two camps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Freedom—Redemption</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-freedom-redemption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-freedom-redemption/</guid>
      <description>Titus 3:3
For we ourselves were once foolish, disobedient, led astray, slaves to various passions and pleasures, passing our days in malice and envy, hated by others and hating one another.
Exodus 6:1-9
But the LORD said to Moses, “Now you shall see what I will do to Pharaoh; for with a strong hand he will send them out, and with a strong hand he will drive them out of his land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Friendship—Reconcilation</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-friendship-reconcilation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-friendship-reconcilation/</guid>
      <description>_Lord, you are more precious than silver.
Lord, you are more costly than gold.
Lord, you are more beautiful than diamonds, and
nothing I desire compares with you._
2 Chronicles 20:7
Did you not, our God, drive out the inhabitants of this land before your people Israel, and give it forever to the descendants of Abraham your friend?
Ruth 1:16-18
But Ruth said, “Do not urge me to leave you or to return from following you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Holiness—High and Lifted Up</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-holiness-high-and-lifted-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-holiness-high-and-lifted-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Leviticus 18:24-22:31&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do not make yourselves unclean by any of these things, for by all these the nations I am driving out before you have become unclean, and the land became unclean, so that I punished its iniquity, and the land vomited out its inhabitants. But you shall keep my statutes and my rules and do none of these abominations, either the native or the stranger who sojourns among you (for the people of the land, who were before you, did all of these abominations, so that the land became unclean), lest the land vomit you out when you make it unclean, as it vomited out the nation that was before you. For everyone who does any of these abominations, the persons who do them shall be cut off from among their people. So keep my charge never to practice any of these abominable customs that were practiced before you, and never to make yourselves unclean by them: I am the Lord your God.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Justification—Exoneration</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-justification-exoneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-justification-exoneration/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 51:4
Against you, you only, have I sinned
and done what is evil in your sight,
so that you may be justified in your words
and blameless in your judgment.
Titus 3:4-7 But when the goodness and loving kindness of God our Savior appeared, he saved us, not because of works done by us in righteousness, but according to his own mercy, by the washing of regeneration and renewal of the Holy Spirit, whom he poured out on us richly through Jesus Christ our Savior, so that being justified by his grace we might become heirs according to the hope of eternal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Love—Affections</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-love-affections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-love-affections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, God created the heavens and the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Chronicles 16:34&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh give thanks to the Lord, for he is good;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for his steadfast love endures forever!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew 5:45 For he makes his sun rise on the evil and on the good, and sends rain on the just and on the unjust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Titus 3:4-7&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when the goodness and loving kindness of God our Savior appeared, he saved us, not because of works done by us in righteousness, but according to his own mercy, by the washing of regeneration and renewal of the Holy Spirit, whom he poured out on us richly through Jesus Christ our Savior, so that being justified by his grace we might become heirs according to the hope of eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Mercies—Propitiation</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-mercies-propitiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-mercies-propitiation/</guid>
      <description>Luke 18:13
But the tax collector, standing far off, would not even lift up his eyes to heaven, but beat his breast, saying, ‘God, be merciful to me, a sinner!’
Leviticus 6:28
And the earthenware vessel in which it is boiled shall be broken. But if it is boiled in a bronze vessel, that shall be scoured and rinsed in water.
Isaiah 53:1-12
Who has believed what he has heard from us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Mind—Repentence</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-mind-repentence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-mind-repentence/</guid>
      <description>Numbers 23:19
God is not man, that he should lie,
or a son of man, that he should change his mind.
Has he said, and will he not do it?
Or has he spoken, and will he not fulfill it?
Deuteronomy 5:29
Oh that they had such a mind as this always, to fear me and to keep all my commandments, that it might go well with them and with their descendants forever!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your New Heart—Regeneration</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-new-heart-regeneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-new-heart-regeneration/</guid>
      <description>Genesis 6:5-6
The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually. And the LORD was sorry that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart.
Lamentations 5:3
We have become orphans, fatherless;
our mothers are like widows.
1 Chronicles 29:15
For we are strangers before you and sojourners, as all our fathers were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Righteousness—Perfection</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-righteousness-perfection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-righteousness-perfection/</guid>
      <description>Isaiah 64:6
We have all become like one who is unclean,
and all our righteous deeds are like a polluted garment.
We all fade like a leaf,
and our iniquities, like the wind, take us away.
Genesis 3:21
And the LORD God made for Adam and for his wife garments of skins and clothed them.
Genesis 6:5-9
The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Weight–Glorification</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-weight-glorification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-weight-glorification/</guid>
      <description>Exodus 14:1-4
Then the LORD said to Moses, “Tell the people of Israel to turn back and encamp in front of Pi-hahiroth, between Migdol and the sea, in front of Baal-zephon; you shall encamp facing it, by the sea. For Pharaoh will say of the people of Israel, ‘They are wandering in the land; the wilderness has shut them in.’ And I will harden Pharaoh’s heart, and he will pursue them, and I will get glory over Pharaoh and all his host, and the Egyptians shall know that I am the LORD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Word—Scriptures</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-word-scriptures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-word-scriptures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John 1:1-5; 14-18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. He was in the beginning with God. All things were made through him, and without him was not any thing made that was made. In him was life, and the life was the light of men. The light shines in the darkness, and the darkness has not overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the Word became flesh and dwelt among us, and we have seen his glory, glory as of the only Son from the Father, full of grace and truth. (John bore witness about him, and cried out, “This was he of whom I said, ‘He who comes after me ranks before me, because he was before me.’”) And from his fullness we have all received, grace upon grace. For the law was given through Moses; grace and truth came through Jesus Christ. No one has ever seen God; the only God, who is at the Father’s side, he has made him known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genesis 3:15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will put enmity between you and the woman,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and between your offspring and her offspring;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;he shall bruise your head,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and you shall bruise his heel.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving for Your Work–Sanctification</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-work-sanctification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/scriptures/thanksgiving-for-your-work-sanctification/</guid>
      <description>Exodus 29:43
There I will meet with the people of Israel, and it shall be sanctified by my glory.
Exodus 31:13
“You are to speak to the people of Israel and say, ‘Above all you shall keep my Sabbaths, for this is a sign between me and you throughout your generations, that you may know that I, the LORD, sanctify you.
Leviticus 10:3
Then Moses said to Aaron, “This is what the LORD has said, ‘Among those who are near me I will be sanctified, and before all the people I will be glorified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Desires of the New Heart Given to Me By God</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/preaching/the-desires-of-the-new-heart-given-to-me-by-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/preaching/the-desires-of-the-new-heart-given-to-me-by-god/</guid>
      <description>**2 Timothy 3:14-4:5 But as for you, continue in what you have learned and have firmly believed, knowing from whom you learned it and how from childhood you have been acquainted with the sacred writings, which are able to make you wise for salvation through faith in Christ Jesus. All Scripture is breathed out by God and profitable for teaching, for reproof, for correction, and for training in righteousness, that the man of God may be complete, equipped for every good work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ridiculous, Foolish Power of Christ Crucified</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/preaching/ridiculous-foolish-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/preaching/ridiculous-foolish-power/</guid>
      <description>1 Corinthians 1:20-24 Where is the one who is wise? Where is the scribe? Where is the debater of this age? Has not God made foolish the wisdom of the world? For since, in the wisdom of God, the world did not know God through wisdom, it pleased God through the folly of what we preach to save those who believe. For Jews demand signs and Greeks seek wisdom, but we preach Christ crucified, a stumbling block to Jews and folly to Gentiles, but to those who are called, both Jews and Greeks, Christ the power of God and the wisdom of God.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>