<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 15:00:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Harshness vs Expressing One’s Feelings</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/books/harshness-vs-expressing-ones-feelings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 15:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/books/harshness-vs-expressing-ones-feelings/</guid>
      <description>Take a look at this hot mess that someone might call a &amp;#8216;book review&amp;#8217;:
For so long, the gospel of God has been assumed in our churches. We now stand on the cusp of the gospel being denied from those who grew up in church and yet was never taught the fullness of the gospel and the full council of the Bible. Nevermind, the true gospel being scoffed at from the unbeliever&amp;#8211;we know that would happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence: The Death of Death in the Death of Christ by John Owen</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/books/influence-the-death-of-death-in-the-death-of-christ-by-john-owen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 18:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/books/influence-the-death-of-death-in-the-death-of-christ-by-john-owen/</guid>
      <description>The Doctrine of Limited Atonement.
For those who are not familiar with this doctrine, it seeks to answer this question:
For whom did Christ die?
There are some points to ponder for sure but I have never seen anyone but old theologians wrestle with this question. (I couldn’t even name one New Calvinist who has grappled with this question—understanding the fact that my perspective is quite finite.)
In that context, I wasn’t sure if the polemic nature of John Owen’s work, The Death of Death in the Death of Christ, wasn’t somewhat outdated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: No Condemnation in Christ Jesus by Octavius Winslow</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/books/influences-no-condemnation-in-christ-jesus-by-octavius-winslow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 18:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/books/influences-no-condemnation-in-christ-jesus-by-octavius-winslow/</guid>
      <description>Why haven&amp;#8217;t you read this book yet?
If I had to recommend just one book not including the Bible, it would be this book—above all other works and above all other commentaries. Many call Romans 8, &amp;#8220;The Mount Everest of the Bible&amp;#8221;. Martin Luther called it, &amp;#8220;the clearest gospel of all&amp;#8221;.
It is with this little paperback Octavius Winslow separates himself from the pack of scholars and theologians. I feel like it wasn&amp;#8217;t that Winslow had to explain the depth and weight of Romans 8 for the scholarly purposes but he had to write this book because if he did not, his heart would have burst in worship and love to our sweet God and Lord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Calling by Paul David Tripp: A Review</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/books/dangerous-calling-by-paul-david-tripp-a-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/books/dangerous-calling-by-paul-david-tripp-a-review/</guid>
      <description>I like this book and I am not even a pastor. And I am not going to preface this review with any sort of calling that God has on my life or whatever He might be walking me through. I think this book is suited for any Christian for we are all saints who are being equipped for the work of the ministry. 1{#return-note-1548-1.simple-footnote} But I think it would be a shame for any Christian to look at the cover, dismiss it because &amp;#8220;Oh I am not a pastor&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Calling: Blind to My True Condition</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/dangerous-calling-blind-to-my-true-condition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/dangerous-calling-blind-to-my-true-condition/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;You see, sin is not first an intellectual problem. (Yes, it does affect my intellect, as it does all parts of my functioning.) Sin is first a moral problem. It is about my rebellion against God and my quest to have for myself the glory that is due to him. Sin is not first about the breaking of an abstract set of rules. Sin is first and foremost about breaking relationship with God, and because I have broken this relationship, it is then easy and natural to rebel against God’s rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Calling: God Will Give Us What We Want</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/dangerous-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/dangerous-calling/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, we think of God as a pragmatic god. We think we do exactly as he says, we make it appear that all is well, and do everything to please him, he will give us whatever our heart&amp;#8217;s desires.
Wait, what if my heart&amp;#8217;s desires are for something not Him? What if I want more money, more sex, more work, more security, more of anything out of God but not God himself?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Calling: Where’s The Grace?</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/dangerous-calling-wheres-the-grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/dangerous-calling-wheres-the-grace/</guid>
      <description>Lectures. Speaking engagements. One-on-one counseling. Teaching. Preaching. Speaking. Whispering. Is it possible to continuously proclaiming the glorious, loving, gracious gospel of Jesus Christ? What if I preached to myself His gospel? What if I continuously filled my mind not with mindless entertainment but with His glorious revelation? What if I stepped into the world and loved the world in the way He did? What if I could get ever moment of my life to proclaim His goodness and grace?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devotions in Mark: A Few Resources</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/family-devotions/mark-a-few-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/family-devotions/mark-a-few-resources/</guid>
      <description>Here just the very small list of resources on Mark that I have found most helpful.
The Bible &amp;#8211; Should go without say. However, many times, many teachers, preachers, and small group leaders (myself included) will &amp;#8220;cut straight to the chase&amp;#8221; and engage the commentary instead of engaging the Word of God. Remember, the commentaries are not without error—they are the observations of the author. Slow down, pray, read, chew and meditate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Have A Job For You</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/books/i-have-a-job-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/books/i-have-a-job-for-you/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Jesus looks around at Peter’s fishing boat and tackle. Peter has gone back to the old life again, unsure what to do with himself next. Jesus says, &amp;#8216;Simon, son of John, when I first met you, you were a fisherman, and I called you to be a fisher of humans. You were very happy then to come with me and work alongside me. Now you are back here again. Do you love me more than these?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Christianity Good for the World? by Christopher Hitchens and Douglas Wilson, A Quick Review</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/books/is-christianity-good-for-the-world-by-christopher-hitchens-and-douglas-wilson-a-quick-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/books/is-christianity-good-for-the-world-by-christopher-hitchens-and-douglas-wilson-a-quick-review/</guid>
      <description>Good, good, good, so good.
Wilson is top-notch and has the upper hand to give the response.
Hitchens is spot-on typical atheist:
 Remove God from the equation Plug-in Evolution as the new source Profit$  In this, the main hard-hitting topic was Morals and Ethics or the source of Morals and Ethics.
Wilson&amp;#8217;s explanation needs none here. Hitchens&amp;#8217; explanation is that there is no source but rather, our morals have evolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Slickest Snot</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/books/the-slickest-snot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/books/the-slickest-snot/</guid>
      <description>If I ever got to write commentaries, my page headers will be organized as so:
4 is the number of the chapter of the book of the Bible
1 is the verse from the same chapter
This is the bomb.

Martin Luther. Luther’s Works, Volume 10: Lectures on the Psalms I. Edited by Hilton C. Oswald. Translated by Herbert J. A. Bouman. Concordia Publishing House, 1974.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Supremacy of God in Preaching by John Piper, A Thought</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/books/review-the-supremacy-of-god-in-preaching-by-john-piper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/books/review-the-supremacy-of-god-in-preaching-by-john-piper/</guid>
      <description>For I decided to know nothing among you except Jesus Christ and him crucified. And I was with you in weakness and in fear and much trembling, and my speech and my message were not in plausible words of wisdom, but in demonstration of the Spirit and of power, so that your faith might not rest in the wisdom of men but in the power of God. 1 Corinthians 2:2-5</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>