<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Supremacy of God in Preaching on Theologicus</title>
    <link>http://theologic.us/tags/the-supremacy-of-god-in-preaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Supremacy of God in Preaching on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theologic.us/tags/the-supremacy-of-god-in-preaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Signed in Blood</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/signed-in-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/signed-in-blood/</guid>
      <description>The keynote in the mouth of every prophet-preacher, whether in Isaiah&amp;#8217;s day or Jesus&amp;#8217; day or our day, is, &amp;#8220;Your God reigns!&amp;#8221; God is the king of the universe. God is the king of the universe. He has absolute Creator rights over this world and everyone in it. But there is rebellion and mutiny on all sides, and his authority is scorned by millions. So the Lord sends preachers into the world to cry out that God reigns, that he will not suffer his glory to be scorned indefinitely, that he will vindicate his name in great and terrible wrath, but that for now a full and free amnesty is offered to all the rebel subjects who will turn from their rebellion, call on him for mercy, bow before his throne, and swear allegiance and fealty to him forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Cry of the Soul</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-hidden-cry-of-the-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/the-hidden-cry-of-the-soul/</guid>
      <description>People are starving for the greatness of God. But most of them would not give this diagnosis of their troubled lives. The majesty of God is an unknown cure. There are far more popular prescriptions on the market, but the benefit of any other remedy is brief and shallow. Preaching that does not have the aroma of God&amp;#8217;s greatness may entertain for a season, but it will not touch the hidden cry of the soul: &amp;#8220;Show me thy glory!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Supremacy of God in Preaching by John Piper, A Thought</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/books/review-the-supremacy-of-god-in-preaching-by-john-piper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/books/review-the-supremacy-of-god-in-preaching-by-john-piper/</guid>
      <description>For I decided to know nothing among you except Jesus Christ and him crucified. And I was with you in weakness and in fear and much trembling, and my speech and my message were not in plausible words of wisdom, but in demonstration of the Spirit and of power, so that your faith might not rest in the wisdom of men but in the power of God. 1 Corinthians 2:2-5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worship Beyond Singing</title>
      <link>http://theologic.us/quotes/worship-beyond-singing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theologic.us/quotes/worship-beyond-singing/</guid>
      <description>More than ever I believe in preaching as a part of worship in the gathered church. Preaching is worship, and it belongs in the regular worship life of the church no matter the size of the church. In the small church it does not become conversation or &amp;#8220;sharing.&amp;#8221; In the megachurch it does not become hype and jingles. Preaching is worshiping over the Word of God—the text of Scripture—with explanation and exultation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>