<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theology on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/theology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theology on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 12:00:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/theology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Romans 8:38-39 What Heights or Depths</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-838-39-the-breakdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 12:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-838-39-the-breakdown/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:38–39 For I am sure that neither death nor life, nor angels nor rulers, nor things present nor things to come, nor powers, nor height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God in Christ Jesus our Lord.
In the year of our 2018, we have Christians contending that their faith would be unshaken if the resurrection never took place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Romans 8:37 For Your Consideration</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-837-for-your-consideration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 12:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-837-for-your-consideration/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:37 No, in all these things we are more than conquerors through him who loved us. All of the questions, pushbacks, and opposition that Paul was facing with teaching this one particular truth of God as a through but simple exposition of Christ’s own words when He said: I give them eternal life, and they will never perish, and no one will snatch them out of my hand.  My Father, who has given them to me, is greater than all, and no one is able to snatch them out of the Father’s hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Romans 8:36 Sheep to the Slaughter</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-836-sheep-to-the-slaughter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 12:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-836-sheep-to-the-slaughter/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:36 As it is written, “For your sake we are being killed all the day long; we are regarded as sheep to be slaughtered.” So what if a little “tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or danger, or sword?” 1 comes our way? God promises suffering for his saints. There is no way around it. Just in case you are at odds with the rest of the authors of the Bible and only want the “red letter edition”, let us consider the words of Christ himself: “Do not think that I have come to bring peace to the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Romans 8:35 What Shall Separate?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-835-what-shall-separate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 12:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-835-what-shall-separate/</guid>
      <description>And here is love: Romans 8:35 Who shall separate us from the love of Christ? Shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or danger, or sword? I am not here to try to define for you what each of these circumstances means. I am 43 years old who lives in the Bible Belt of the United States and have been a believer for a quarter of my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Romans 8:34 Who Can Condemn?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-834-who-can-condemn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 12:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-834-who-can-condemn/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:34 Who is to condemn? Christ Jesus is the one who died—more than that, who was raised—who is at the right hand of God, who indeed is interceding for us. Let’s try to find a verse that sums up the whole Bible concerning the gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ, and you will have your choice of a few verses: “For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Romans 8:33 Let The Charges Pile Up!</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-833-all-charges-dropped/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-833-all-charges-dropped/</guid>
      <description>Who shall bring any charge against God’s elect? It is God who justifies. 1 This world and its inhabitants, princes, rulers, and principalities crouching, and ready to pounce and devour your heart and soul. They are not always going to do it with outright accusations, but they might resort to that. “Look at your life! Look at all the mistakes you’ve made! You can’t even stay married.” “You are a failure!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Romans 8:32 God Has Given Us Everything</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-832-god-has-given-us-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-832-god-has-given-us-everything/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:32 He who did not spare his own Son but gave him up for us all, how will he not also with him graciously give us all things? I could sit here and blast you with God’s holy words about God alone provides for us, and we need nothing. The Lord is my shepherd; I shall not want. 1 It is more than “I don’t want” like we are monks in Timbuktu living off the land but rather, because God adopted us, we are co-heirs with the One who has inherited all things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Romans 8:31 The Preeminence of the Love of God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-831-the-preeminence-of-the-love-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 12:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-831-the-preeminence-of-the-love-of-god/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:31 What then shall we say to these things? If God is for us, who can be against us? The love of God cannot be simply defined by the merest of affections and words that we might share with one another. Is our relationship to our spouse, children, family, co-workers, or neighbor compare to one’s relationship with God? Although our relationships should be held in the light of God’s relationship with us, it is perposturous to think that anybody we know would compare to God is perfect in all things especially when it comes to love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis XII: Our New Body – Spirit’s Power in Our Glorification</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/our-new-body-spirits-power-in-our-glorification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/our-new-body-spirits-power-in-our-glorification/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 97:9 For you, O LORD,
are most high over all the earth;
you are exalted far above all gods.  And how can we even fathom this glory of God? How can we fully look upon God in his sheer radiance, beauty, and majesty without our minds and eyes and hearts shutting down? It is sheer madness. And that is exactly what God wants! He wants to be with him forever and ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Romans 8:30d Glorified</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/romans-830d-glorified/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 12:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/romans-830d-glorified/</guid>
      <description>And here is love: “… and for those whom he justified he also glorified.” We look up all of Romans 8:30 as a chain that begins and ends with God. To that end, predestination and glorification are things that our minds cannot fully fathom. But we rest assure that every single person predestined is called is justified is glorified. There is no whittling or dwindling of numbers as we move along the list, Christ said, “I give them eternal life, and they will never perish, and no one will snatch them out of my hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis XI: Our New Lives – Spirit’s Work In Our Sanctification</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-xi-our-new-lives-spirits-work-in-our-sanctification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 12:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-xi-our-new-lives-spirits-work-in-our-sanctification/</guid>
      <description>Isaiah 48:9–11 “For my name’s sake I defer my anger;
for the sake of my praise I restrain it for you,
that I may not cut you off.
 Behold, I have refined you, but not as silver;
I have tried you in the furnace of affliction.
 For my own sake, for my own sake, I do it,
for how should my name be profaned?
My glory I will not give to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Romans 8:30c Justified</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-830c-justified/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-830c-justified/</guid>
      <description>And here is love: &amp;#8230; and those whom he called he also justified...
This is the steadfast chain of salvation that links us to God forever and ever.
Predestination is God&amp;#8217;s mere thoughts, affections, will, and decisions towards us. From eternity past, God thought of us specifically and was mindful of us intentionally.
Calling is the voice of God that actively makes us alive in our dead and sinful state. The calling of God is the voice of the Father bringing us to life and calling us according to His purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis X: Our New Inheritance – Spirit’s Witness in Our Adoption</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-ix-our-new-inheritance-spirits-witness-in-our-adoption/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-ix-our-new-inheritance-spirits-witness-in-our-adoption/</guid>
      <description>We have fully established that we are not fully alive despite being biologically alive. Throughout the Bible, starting in Genesis 2, God states that sin separates the soul of man from the spirit of God. And without God, we are dead. And just being dead is not enough: Ephesians 2:1–3 And you were dead in the trespasses and sinsin which you once walked, following the course of this world, following the prince of the power of the air, the spirit that is now at work in the sons of disobedience—among whom we all once lived in the passions of our flesh, carrying out the desires of the body and the mind, and were by nature children of wrath, like the rest of mankind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Romans 8:30b Called</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-830b-called/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-romans-830b-called/</guid>
      <description>And here is love: Romans 8:30b And those whom he predestined he also called… So if there was nothing in us to attract, sway, or convinced God to love us and save us, what did God see in us before He saved us? There is a war in our world to determine the value of a human’s life. Life today is no longer precious. Consider the life of a newborn or the life of a refugee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis IX: Our New Heart – Spirit’s Power in Regeneration</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-ix-our-new-heart-spirits-power-in-regeneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 12:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-ix-our-new-heart-spirits-power-in-regeneration/</guid>
      <description>When God saved us from eternity past, His saving work was not finished when Christ lived, died, buried, and rose again, as though there is nothing for him for his people. You see, every single person born of man since Adam and Eve were born inherently not in connection with God but being apart from God both infinitely and eternally. That separation is because we have no spirit of God because our hearts were not born of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Romans 8:30a Predestined</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/romans-830a-predestined/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/romans-830a-predestined/</guid>
      <description>And here is love: Romans 8:30a And those whom he predestined … We have now established that God loved us not just for the sake of love by itself. It is a warm and sentiment notion to be sure but when it comes to God, it is not just simply His love as though he can be reduced to one feeling. Likewise, while his love remains supreme, it isn’t all that he is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis VIII: Christ’s Finished Work, We Are Protected</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-viii-christs-finished-work-we-are-protected/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 12:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-viii-christs-finished-work-we-are-protected/</guid>
      <description>This has been one of the most difficult chapters to write because there is so much to be packed into the doctrine of propitiation. The only way I could approach this is to start at the beginning and start at the high altitude and work our way down. To understand propitiation, we must understand God, his law, his love and his holiness.
What can incite the wrath of God? It is when we decide that we don’t need his way but we insist on own our way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: To Whom Are We Saved? – Romans 8:29e</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-to-whom-are-we-saved-romans-829e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 12:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-to-whom-are-we-saved-romans-829e/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:29 For those whom he foreknew he also predestined to be conformed to the image of his Son, in order that he might be the firstborn among many brothers.  When we carefully walked through verse 29 of Romans 8, we saw that there was more than a few questions that rose to the top, namely: What did God saw in us?We now know that he didn’t see anything good, righteousness or lovely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis VII: Christ’s Sufficient Work, We Are Clean</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-vii-christs-sufficient-work-we-are-clean/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 12:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-vii-christs-sufficient-work-we-are-clean/</guid>
      <description>This is the magnificence of the True God.
The God of the Old Testament who called down judgment on the wicked and the departed. The same God who expressed His faithfulness to His people who were faithless. The God whose steadfast love never ceased to those whom he promised would make things all things right. The infinitely powerful God who was able to always woo and pursue the hearts of his children and bring them out of death and destruction back into life everlasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Why Did God Save Us? – Romans 8:29d</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-why-did-god-save-us-romans-829d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 12:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-why-did-god-save-us-romans-829d/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:29 For those whom he foreknew he also predestined to be conformed to the image of his Son, in order that he might be the firstborn among many brothers.  This entire series has been trying to pit the world’s definition of love versus God’s definition of love. And perhaps up until this moment, we have never taken that to actual task. What I mean by that is that comparatively speaking, if I speak of God’s love, we can still find something like that in on earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis VI: Christ’s Perfect Work, We Are Justified</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-vi-christs-perfect-work-we-are-justified/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-vi-christs-perfect-work-we-are-justified/</guid>
      <description>Many people tried to say that the God of the Old Testament and the God of the New Testament are completely two different gods. Have you heard this argument? Why was God so angry? Why is Jesus so loving and kind? Was God in the Old Testament was the Father and then his Son took over in the New? I don’t understand a god that would punish people. I can only understand a god that loves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: By Whom We Are Saved – Romans 8:29c</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-by-whom-we-are-saved-romans-829c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 12:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-by-whom-we-are-saved-romans-829c/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:29 For those whom he foreknew he also predestined to be conformed to the image of his Son, in order that he might be the firstborn among many brothers.
When we speak of Romans 8, most Christians rightfully cling to the verse 1: There is therefore now no condemnation for those who are in Christ Jesus. But Romans 8:1 is not the very first line of this epistle from Paul to the church in Rome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis V: God Speaks To The Dead</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-v-but-god-preaches-to-the-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 12:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-v-but-god-preaches-to-the-dead/</guid>
      <description>John 6:44-47 No one can come to me unless the Father who sent me draws him. And I will raise him up on the last day. It is written in the Prophets, ‘And they will all be taught by God.’ Everyone who has heard and learned from the Father comes to me—not that anyone has seen the Father except he is from God; he has seen the Father. Truly, truly, I say to you, whoever believes has eternal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: How Did God Save Us? – Romans 8:29b</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-how-did-god-save-us-romans-829b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 12:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-how-did-god-save-us-romans-829b/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:29 For those whom he foreknew he also predestined to be conformed to the image of his Son, in order that he might be the firstborn among many brothers.
So we have firmly established that God did not look into the future and see that I was good enough to be saved. I did not make the right decision to be saved or do a bunch of “good” works to be saved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis IV: We Are Destined For Death</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-iv-we-are-destined-for-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 12:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-iv-we-are-destined-for-death/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;How does God determine who he will save and not save?&amp;#8221; If you ever speak about the doctrine of election and predestination, you are sure to get that question asked. Numerous times have I been asked this and numerous times the answer of &amp;#8220;his glory (Isaiah 48:11, Proverbs 25:2) and his pleasure (Isaiah 48:11 cf. Philippians 2:13)&amp;#8221; is simply not good enough. Furthermore, to answer that &amp;#8220;the secret things belong to the LORD (Deuteronomy 29:29)&amp;#8221; is merely a copout to most people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: What God Saw In Us – Romans 8:29a</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-what-god-saw-in-us-romans-829a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-what-god-saw-in-us-romans-829a/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:29 For those whom he foreknew he also predestined to be conformed to the image of his Son, in order that he might be the firstborn among many brothers.
There are many verses that can be used to aptly say what verse twenty-nine so succinctly and definitely says here. I can think of two passages:
1 Peter 1:20–21 He was foreknown before the foundation of the world but was made manifest in the last times for the sake of you who through him are believers in God, who raised him from the dead and gave him glory, so that your faith and hope are in God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis III: For God So Loved The World</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-iii-for-god-so-loved-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-iii-for-god-so-loved-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Now that we have established who we are in the sight of God, let us tackle the bigger, nay impossible question:
Who is God? Ask my son and he would immediately quote:
God is the universe’s Creator And Sustainer plus the only Savior, there is no one greater. He’s Triune, holy, omnipotent, omniscient, absolute, loving, sovereign and righteous are just a few of His attributes.
&amp;#8211; Shai Lynne, Atonement Q&amp;amp;A</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: All Good – Romans 8:28</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-all-good-romans-828/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 12:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-all-good-romans-828/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:28 And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose.
Herein lies love: all things work together for good for those who love God. Within our world, one might dare to ask, “What about those who don’t love God? What about my friend or neighbor or co-worker who is basically a good guy or gal?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis II: The Weight of Sin</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-ii-the-weight-of-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 12:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-ii-the-weight-of-sin/</guid>
      <description>Before we can even try to understand what God has done in Salvation, we must first truly understand our condition as human beings born on this earth. I feel compelled to at least touch on this doctrine for I believe that many Christians sometimes either forget their natural state before God saved them or they simply don&amp;#8217;t remember being that &amp;#8216;bad&amp;#8217; of a person before being saved. It is not that we have to dwell on our depravity, our flesh, our sin nature but to ignore or forget about it would absolutely rob our heart of joy and worship before the Lord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: He is the One Who Knows Us – Romans 8:27</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-he-is-the-one-who-knows-us-romans-827/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 12:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-he-is-the-one-who-knows-us-romans-827/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:27 And he who searches hearts knows what is the mind of the Spirit, because the Spirit intercedes for the saints according to the will of God.
This is a fantastic God
What compares to the knowledge of God when He alone reveals all truth and science to us? Yet, he is not merely the best supercomputer in the world with every single piece of knowledge and scientific fact ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordo Salutis I: The Overflowing Love of God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-i-the-overflowing-love-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/ordo-salutis-i-the-overflowing-love-of-god/</guid>
      <description>To proclaim ourselves as Christians to proclaim that we believe and trust upon Christ as our Saviour and Lord.   At that beautiful moment when God saved us, we hope and pray that each one of us are immediately surrounded by other brothers and sisters in Christ that are willing to walk alongside us in love, encouragement, teaching and exhortation. It is my sincere hope that no newly saved person is ever alone by themselves trying to figure this thing especially when the cross of Christ has not only saved us to Himself but we have been reconciled to each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: He is Our Mediator – Romans 8:26</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-he-is-our-mediator-romans-826/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-he-is-our-mediator-romans-826/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:26 Likewise the Spirit helps us in our weakness. For we do not know what to pray for as we ought, but the Spirit himself intercedes for us with groanings too deep for words.
When coming to the full acknowledgment of the pain and anguish of sin that he seems to never be able to overcome, Paul cries the same incredible prayer in the same spirit as the tax collector in the synagogue:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Word Made Flesh</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-word-made-flesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-word-made-flesh/</guid>
      <description>We confess the mystery and wonder of God made flesh and rejoice in our great salvation through Jesus Christ our Lord. With the Father and the Holy Spirit, the Son created all things, sustains all things, and makes all things new. Truly God, He became truly man, two natures in one person. He was born of the Virgin Mary and lived among us. Crucified, dead, and buried, He rose on the third day, ascended to heaven, and will come again in glory and judgment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>​Here is Love: He is Our Hope – Romans 8:24-25</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/-here-is-love-he-is-our-hope-romans-823/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/-here-is-love-he-is-our-hope-romans-823/</guid>
      <description>​
Romans 8:24-25 For in this hope we were saved. Now hope that is seen is not hope. For who hopes for what he sees? But if we hope for what we do not see, we wait for it with patience.
What is this hope?
Walk backwards from the text. Our hope in adoption as sons? Redemption of our bodies? That creation would be set from its bondage to corruption and obtain the freedom of the glory of the children of God?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: He is Our Longing – Romans 8:23</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-he-is-our-longing-romans-823/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 15:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-he-is-our-longing-romans-823/</guid>
      <description>What is there to look forward to?
Romans 8:23 And not only the creation, but we ourselves, who have the firstfruits of the Spirit, groan inwardly as we wait eagerly for adoption as sons, the redemption of our bodies.
My mother abandoned me when I was five years old and I never seen her since. My father physically, emotionally, mentally, and sexually abused me when I was a child. While I have “grown” physically, my heart and my emotional growth stunted to that of a child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: He is Our Revelation – Romans 8:19-22</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-he-is-our-revelation-romans-819-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 13:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-he-is-our-revelation-romans-819-22/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:19–22 For the creation waits with eager longing for the revealing of the sons of God. For the creation was subjected to futility, not willingly, but because of him who subjected it, in hope that the creation itself will be set free from its bondage to corruption and obtain the freedom of the glory of the children of God. For we know that the whole creation has been groaning together in the pains of childbirth until now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: He is Our End – Romans 8:18</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love_he-is-our-end-romans-8_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love_he-is-our-end-romans-8_18/</guid>
      <description>Why even bother?
****Romans 8:18 For I consider that the sufferings of this present time are not worth comparing with the glory that is to be revealed to us.
That is why we bother.
If your affections, desires, and wants are places on Christ alone, then there is everything that we have endured and suffered will not compared to seeing His glory. What is glory? Here is my weak, futile, mortal attempt to explain what glory is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: You Have Everything– Romans 8:17, Pt. 2</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-you-have-everything-romans-817-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 14:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-you-have-everything-romans-817-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>Will there be suffering?
Is there life? Do we live in this world? Will you suffer anxiety, worry, depression, angst, anger, frustration, and rage?
Will you suffer pain, hurt, torment, cancer, sickness, disease, anguish, and death?
Will you suffer forgetfulness, confusion, doubt, and disbelief?
Will you suffer?
I don’t have to explain all of life and all of mankind to you. You already know this. If you don’t know this, then you are blind and don’t see life around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: We Get Everything—Romans 8:17, Pt. 1</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-we-get-everything-romans-817a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-we-get-everything-romans-817a/</guid>
      <description>A Rake&amp;#8217;s Progress, Plate 1: The Young Heir Takes Possession Of The Miser&amp;#8217;s Effects by William Hogarth Romans 8:17a and if children, then heirs-heirs of God and fellow heirs with Christ,
What does it mean to be a child of God?
To ask that is to ask: What does it mean for the Father to set his affections upon you? What does it mean for Christ to love you, pursue you, die for you, and then live for you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: With Him For Always—Romans 8:16</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-with-him-for-always-romans-816/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 14:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-with-him-for-always-romans-816/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:16 The Spirit himself bears witness with our spirit that we are children of God,
What can I say when I am in the presence of the Almighty God?
I have no defense!
All of my works of righteousness are as used bloody tampons before God.
Everything I did before knowing God was regarded as crap.
This is what I hold in my hands, bloody tampons and shit, before the incredible, awesome, magnificent, glorious Creator God of the Universe, who is high, lifted up, and exalted far above me, my thoughts, my pride, my sin, my iniquities, and my pitiful gods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Unlimited Access–Romans 8:15</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-unlimited-access-romans-815/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 14:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-unlimited-access-romans-815/</guid>
      <description>[][1]Paul Kline/iStockphoto.com Romans 8:15 For you did not receive the spirit of slavery to fall back into fear, but you have received the Spirit of adoption as sons, by whom we cry, &amp;#8220;Abba! Father!&amp;#8221;
Can you have both the spirit of slavery and the Spirit of adoption?
Never mind just twelve verses ago (Romans 8:3-8) that we have already made that distinction. So, let us see what Christ says:
&amp;#8220;Enter by the narrow gate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Never Alone- Romans 8:14</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-never-alone-romans-814/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 14:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-never-alone-romans-814/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:14 For all who are led by the Spirit of God are sons of God.
What does it mean to be led?
The Holy Spirit is a comfort, a teacher, and a bringer of peace. Never is the Spirit of God associated with violence or forcefulness. So what does it mean to be led? Does this mean that Holy Spirit drags the kicking and screaming sons of God to Jesus Christ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Here is Power – Romans 8:13</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-here-is-power-romans-813/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 14:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-here-is-power-romans-813/</guid>
      <description>[][1]The Zombie King by *Rhazcrossbones Romans 8:13 For if you live according to the flesh you will die, but if by the Spirit you put to death the deeds of the body, you will live.
How are you going to live?
So what if you live according to your emotions, thoughts, feelings, and instincts? I feel like this is the right thing to do. This is the wrong thing to do but I am in love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: You Can’t Give a Dead Man Anything – Romans 8:12</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-you-cant-give-a-dead-man-anything-romans-812/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-you-cant-give-a-dead-man-anything-romans-812/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:12 So then, brothers, we are debtors, not to the flesh, to live according to the flesh.
What is the debt?****
In other words, what is there to give to our old life. What do we owe to our former cold hearts of stone? How can you give dead man anything? Paul said it already in Romans 6:
We know that our old self was crucified with him in order that the body of sin might be brought to nothing, so that we would no longer be enslaved to sin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Logic – Romans 8:11</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-logic-romans-811/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 15:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-logic-romans-811/</guid>
      <description>What is certain?
This is certain: if you have the Spirit of God, who raised Jesus from dead, dwells in you, you have life.
How can we be certain that we have the Spirit of God in us? How can we know? Can we know?
On the last day of the feast, the great day, Jesus stood up and cried out, “If anyone thirsts, let him come to me and drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Our Sin is Death, Our God is Life – Romans 8:10</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-our-sin-is-death-our-god-is-life-romans-810/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 15:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-our-sin-is-death-our-god-is-life-romans-810/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:10 But if Christ is in you, although the body is dead because of sin, the Spirit is life because of righteousness.
What is righteousness?
Righteousness is when you are constantly, consistently, always perfect. It is continuous thread of how God is able to do everything: love, create, judge, save, redeem, rescue, glorify.
None of us, any human being, born of Adam, is able to claim righteousness as our own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Never Alone, Can’t Do It Alone – Romans 8:9</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-never-alone-cant-do-it-alone-romans-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 15:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-never-alone-cant-do-it-alone-romans-89/</guid>
      <description>[][1]&amp;#8220;Winter Loneliness&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Dominique Jost Romans 8:9 You, however, are not in the flesh but in the Spirit, if in fact the Spirit of God dwells in you. Anyone who does not have the Spirit of Christ does not belong to him.
In modern times, we tend to talk about mankind’s achievements and possibilities. To the modern mind, humans have achieved so much and therefore, mankind’s possibilities are endless. Likewise, to the individual, we can achieve anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: I Cannot Go On Without You – Romans 8:8</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-i-cannot-go-on-without-you-romans-88-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 15:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-i-cannot-go-on-without-you-romans-88-2/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:8 Those who are in the flesh cannot please God.
Is this true?
**We have all become like one who is unclean,
and all our righteous deeds are like a polluted garment.
We all fade like a leaf,
and our iniquities, like the wind, take us away.** 1{#return-note-1731-1.simple-footnote}
**as it is written:
&amp;#8220;None is righteous, no, not one;
no one understands;
no one seeks for God.
All have turned aside;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Despite Our Limitations – Romans 8:7</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-despite-our-limitations-romans-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-despite-our-limitations-romans-87/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:7 For the mind that is set on the flesh is hostile to God, for it does not submit to God&amp;#8217;s law; indeed, it cannot.
What is Paul suggesting here? That the mind that is not renewed by the Spirit of God cannot possibly obey God’s law? So does that mean we are not breaking the law of God and therefore sinless before God?Absolutely, not!
The mind of man is broken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Despite Us For Us – Romans 8:5-6</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-despite-us-for-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 15:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-despite-us-for-us/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:5-6 For those who live according to the flesh set their minds on the things of the flesh, but those who live according to the Spirit set their minds on the things of the Spirit. For to set the mind on the flesh is death, but to set the mind on the Spirit is life and peace.
What is the flesh?
Is it something inherently evil? Is it that this body cannot do anything right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: No One Else Can Do – Romans 8:3-4</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-no-one-else-can-do-romans-83-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-no-one-else-can-do-romans-83-4/</guid>
      <description>Romans 8:3-4 For God has done what the law, weakened by the flesh, could not do. By sending his own Son in the likeness of sinful flesh and for sin, he condemned sin in the flesh, in order that the righteous requirement of the law might be fulfilled in us, who walk not according to the flesh but according to the Spirit.
What is the law?
The world wants to look upon the Bible and see how hard it is to be a Christian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: You Have Been Set Free – Romans 8:2</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-you-have-been-set-free-romans-82/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 15:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-you-have-been-set-free-romans-82/</guid>
      <description>{.hoverZoomLink}There are 613 commandments in the Old Testament.
Don’t eat pork. 1{#return-note-1367-1.simple-footnote}
Don’t eat eel. 2{#return-note-1367-2.simple-footnote}
Don’t get tattoos. 3{#return-note-1367-3.simple-footnote}
If you have a slave, there are rules on beating your slave. 4{#return-note-1367-4.simple-footnote}
Women, if it is that “time of the month”, there are rules for that. 5{#return-note-1367-5.simple-footnote}
Don’t marry somebody outside of your faith. 6{#return-note-1367-6.simple-footnote}
Be kind to the immigrant—illegal or otherwise—and treat them as you would your own countryman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: I Tell You This So That Your Joy May Be Full – Romans 8:1</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-i-tell-you-this-so-that-your-joy-may-be-full-romans-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-i-tell-you-this-so-that-your-joy-may-be-full-romans-81/</guid>
      <description>My abusing and the abuse done against me.
My lies that I have told.
The wicked thoughts in my head.
My own foolishness.
My sickness.
The iniquities of my heart.
The lusts that captured me for most of my life.
The amount of pornography I have distributed in my lifetime.
My disobedience.
My distrust.
My blasphemy.
My anger.
The poison from my tongue
My hatred.
My self-righteousness.
My pride.
This what defines me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Death and Life – Galatians 2:20</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-death-and-life-galatians-220/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 14:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-death-and-life-galatians-220/</guid>
      <description>My life is not my own. My heart, my soul, my flesh, my mind, and my strength: all of it does not belong to me.
I used to think that it did belong to me. I use to the think that I was solely in charge of my own life, my own purpose, and my own destiny. But as the years rolled on, I noticed that the more and more that I tried to handle my life on my own, I was inching closer and closer to death—leaving a trail of destruction along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Whoever Believes—John 3:16</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-whoever-believes-john3-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 14:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-whoever-believes-john3-16/</guid>
      <description>God loves us. So much so, He came to us.
The one who thinks of themselves as good or even, not-so-bad thinks that this is acceptable. “God should come to us. Why shouldn’t he? God should come to me and meet me and get to know me and love me and save me despite me.”
However, you see, to the renewed mind, the first line of John 3:16 almost doesn’t make sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Blissful Contentment – Psalm 17:15</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-blissful-contentment-psalm17-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 19:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-blissful-contentment-psalm17-15/</guid>
      <description>A sight for sore eyes.
No words have rang truer except for the Son of Man.
The One God who cross the infinite just to save me.
Now my eyes bleared at the first site of him.
The loveliness of his face.
I look into His eyes and my soul is complete. My heart is joy-filled. My mind now knows fully.
I am content.
I am satisfied.
God is perfect in his work in me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Necessary Surgery—Ezekiel 36:22-28</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-necessary-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 15:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-necessary-surgery/</guid>
      <description>This is the good news for all time: that Jesus Christ has come to make all things right-standing with Him. 1{#return-note-944-1.simple-footnote}
This is the unquenchable thirst of holiness: He will do so by saving His people from Him, by Him, for Him, through Him, and to Him forever and ever. 2{#return-note-944-2.simple-footnote}
This is the weight of the glory: His word will be preached among the dead—the valley of dry bones—and because He is life, he speaks life into the dead and those who were once dead, now they shall live!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: The Apex of the Glory of God – Romans 8</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-the-apex-of-the-glory-of-god-romans-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-the-apex-of-the-glory-of-god-romans-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Mount-Everest-1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-928&#34; title=&#34;Mount-Everest-1&#34; src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Mount-Everest-1.jpg?resize=300%2C225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Mount-Everest-1.jpg?resize=300%2C225 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Mount-Everest-1.jpg?w=1024 1024w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;All Scripture read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every instinct preached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every thought taught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any book studied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every sermon heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every theology revealed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every doctrine learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any and all things processed were with Romans 8 in my sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have heard it said, &amp;#8220;The Epistle to the Romans is the Himalayas of the Bible and with Romans 8 is the Everest.&amp;#8221; Martin Luther calls Romans 8, &amp;#8220;the clearest Gospel of them all&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to memorize any passage of Scripture, it is because I wanted to get to where I can memorize Romans 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any passage memorized now is because I am camped out on the summit that is Romans 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memorized it. Dwelled on it. Read about it. Focused on it. Prayed on it. Prayed using it. Recite it. Practiced preaching it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to write a multi-part blog series on the entirety of Romans 8 in a few weeks so I won&amp;#8217;t expand on it here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, enjoy your view of God&amp;#8217;s glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width=&#34;25%&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Walking Into Death, Walking Into Life – Ephesians 2:1-10</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/will-of-dead-will-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/will-of-dead-will-of-god/</guid>
      <description>Either I was dead or I wasn’t.
Either I was following the course of this world or I wasn’t.
Either I was following Satan or I wasn’t.
Either I was a son of disobedience or I wasn’t.
If I deny to be any of those things or pretend I was not that bad off, then God did not come to save me.
Luke 5:31-32 And Jesus answered them, “Those who are well have no need of a physician, but those who are sick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: What Shall I Pray? 1 Timothy 1:12-17</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/influences-what-shall-i-pray-1-timothy-112-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/influences-what-shall-i-pray-1-timothy-112-17/</guid>
      <description>So in all of this, what shall I pray?
What can I say?
I pray to worship You.
I pray to praise Your holy name forever.
I pray to sing to You.
I pray because I want You.
I pray because I need You near.
I pray because I have no life without You.
I pray because You are my Lord and God.
I pray because You are my Father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: God to Man and Man to God—2 Corinthians 5:21</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-god-to-man-and-man-to-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-god-to-man-and-man-to-god/</guid>
      <description>And here is love: 2 Corinthians 5:21 For our sake he made him to be sin who knew no sin, so that in him we might become the righteousness of God.
Ah ha!
Welcome to where things do not make sense in the real world.
This is the incredible. The awesome. The audacious.
Let us chop this verse up.
Who is he who made him to be sin?
He is God the Father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Perfectly—Matthew 1:21</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-perfectly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 14:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-perfectly/</guid>
      <description>{.hoverZoomLink}And here is love: Matthew 1:21 She will bear a son, and you shall call his name Jesus, for he will save his people from their sins.”
I have heard it said many times from the pulpit, “The Bible does not say, ‘Jesus died on the cross for only his people.’”
Then why did Jesus die on the cross?
Did He die for the mere possibility that you might be saved?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: For All Time—Psalm 103:15-18</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-for-all-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 14:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-for-all-time/</guid>
      <description>And here is love: Psalm 103:15-18 As for man, his days are like grass; he flourishes like a flower of the field; for the wind passes over it, and it is gone, and its place knows it no more. But the steadfast love of the LORD is from everlasting to everlasting on those who fear him, and his righteousness to children&amp;#8217;s children, to those who keep his covenant and remember to do his commandments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: Precious in His Sight—Deuteronomy 7:6-8</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-precious-in-his-sight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-precious-in-his-sight/</guid>
      <description>And here is love: Deuteronomy 7:6-8 “For you are a people holy to the LORD your God. The LORD your God has chosen you to be a people for his treasured possession, out of all the peoples who are on the face of the earth. It was not because you were more in number than any other people that the LORD set his love on you and chose you, for you were the fewest of all peoples, but it is because the LORD loves you and is keeping the oath that he swore to your fathers, that the LORD has brought you out with a mighty hand and redeemed you from the house of slavery, from the hand of Pharaoh king of Egypt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: The Cross Was Never Plan B—Genesis 3:15</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-the-cross-was-never-plan-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 14:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-the-cross-was-never-plan-b/</guid>
      <description>Here is love: Genesis 3:15 I will put enmity between you and the woman, and between your offspring and her offspring; he shall bruise your head, and you shall bruise his heel.”
The cosmos shattered.
The universe cracked.
The world broken.
Sin has entered into our lives and began its wanton destruction leaving billions dead and the sons of Adam damned to the eternal wrath of the Holy God.
But the Holy God was not put off by sin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love: All Sin Future Sin—Romans 5:8</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-all-sin-future-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 14:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-all-sin-future-sin/</guid>
      <description>Here is love: Romans 5:8 but God shows his love for us in that while we were still sinners, Christ died for us.
I am confident that 99.8% of people reading this was born in the 20th century. Historically speaking, Christ died about 2000 years ago. I am going to link these two ideas in one moment.
Christ is fully God. That means He fully sees all and fully knows all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is Love, An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/here-is-love-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>What is love?
Isn&amp;#8217;t that a question for the ages and especially, in our day and time? Some think it is abstract and for some, more substantial. Some flee from love and desire it all the more. Others attempt to change love in order to fit their lives and their hearts.
Often, we see these questions in our culture even when culture are not using those three little words, &amp;#8220;what is love?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Sola Fide</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-fide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-fide/</guid>
      <description>[][1]Martin Luther by Lucas Cranach dem Älteren Genesis 15:1-6 After these things the word of the LORD came to Abram in a vision: “Fear not, Abram, I am your shield; your reward shall be very great.” But Abram said, “O Lord GOD, what will you give me, for I continue childless, and the heir of my house is Eliezer of Damascus?” And Abram said, “Behold, you have given me no offspring, and a member of my household will be my heir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Sola Gratia</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-gratia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-gratia/</guid>
      <description>[][1]William Tyndale Genesis 3:21
And the LORD God made for Adam and for his wife garments of skins and clothed them.
Genesis 6:5-9
The LORD saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually. And the LORD was sorry that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart. So the LORD said, “I will blot out man whom I have created from the face of the land, man and animals and creeping things and birds of the heavens, for I am sorry that I have made them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Sola Scriptura</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-scriptura/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-sola-scriptura/</guid>
      <description>2 Timothy 3:16-4:5
All Scripture is breathed out by God and profitable for teaching, for reproof, for correction, and for training in righteousness, that the man of God may be complete, equipped for every good work.
I charge you in the presence of God and of Christ Jesus, who is to judge the living and the dead, and by his appearing and his kingdom: preach the word; be ready in season and out of season; reprove, rebuke, and exhort, with complete patience and teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Soli Deo Gloria</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-soli-deo-gloria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-soli-deo-gloria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/tulip_2-wallpaper.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-984&#34; title=&#34;tulip_2-wallpaper&#34; src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/tulip_2-wallpaper.jpg?resize=159%2C300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;159&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/tulip_2-wallpaper.jpg?resize=159%2C300 159w, https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/tulip_2-wallpaper.jpg?w=407 407w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 159px) 100vw, 159px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Exodus 33:18-23&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moses said, “Please show me your glory.” And he said, “I will make all my goodness pass before you and will proclaim before you my name ‘The LORD.’ And I will be gracious to whom I will be gracious, and will show mercy on whom I will show mercy. But,” he said, “you cannot see my face, for man shall not see me and live.” And the LORD said, “Behold, there is a place by me where you shall stand on the rock, and while my glory passes by I will put you in a cleft of the rock, and I will cover you with my hand until I have passed by. Then I will take away my hand, and you shall see my back, but my face shall not be seen.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leviticus 9:6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And Moses said, “This is the thing that the LORD commanded you to do, that the glory of the LORD may appear to you.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 Chronicles 29:10-18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore David blessed the LORD in the presence of all the assembly. And David said: “Blessed are you, O LORD, the God of Israel our father, forever and ever. Yours, O LORD, is the greatness and the power and the glory and the victory and the majesty, for all that is in the heavens and in the earth is yours. Yours is the kingdom, O LORD, and you are exalted as head above all. Both riches and honor come from you, and you rule over all. In your hand are power and might, and in your hand it is to make great and to give strength to all. And now we thank you, our God, and praise your glorious name.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“But who am I, and what is my people, that we should be able thus to offer willingly? For all things come from you, and of your own have we given you. For we are strangers before you and sojourners, as all our fathers were. Our days on the earth are like a shadow, and there is no abiding.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O LORD our God, all this abundance that we have provided for building you a house for your holy name comes from your hand and is all your own. I know, my God, that you test the heart and have pleasure in uprightness. In the uprightness of my heart I have freely offered all these things, and now I have seen your people, who are present here, offering freely and joyously to you. O LORD, the God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel, our fathers, keep forever such purposes and thoughts in the hearts of your people, and direct their hearts toward you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abounded All The More: Solus Christus</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-solus-christus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/abounded-all-the-more-solus-christus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure id=&#34;attachment_1180&#34; style=&#34;width: 191px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube.jpg?resize=191%2C300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube&#34; width=&#34;191&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1180&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube.jpg?resize=191%2C300 191w, https://i2.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Dali_Crucifixion_hypercube.jpg?w=319 319w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 191px) 100vw, 191px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;Corpus Hypercubus by Salvador Dalí&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;Genesis 3:15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**I will put enmity between you and the woman, and between your offspring and her offspring; he shall bruise your head,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and you shall bruise his heel.”**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exodus 3:14&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God said to Moses, “I Am Who I Am” And he said, “Say this to the people of Israel, ‘I Am&amp;#8217; has sent me to you.’”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leviticus 16:21-22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And Aaron shall lay both his hands on the head of the live goat, and confess over it all the iniquities of the people of Israel, and all their transgressions, all their sins. And he shall put them on the head of the goat and send it away into the wilderness by the hand of a man who is in readiness. The goat shall bear all their iniquities on itself to a remote area, and he shall let the goat go free in the wilderness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All of the Infinite</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/all-of-the-infinite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/all-of-the-infinite/</guid>
      <description> My hope is infinite because of this: The Infinite God in His infinite glory with His infinite love sent His Infinite Son by His infinite power of His Infinite Spirit across the infinite chasm to save my infinite soul from my infinite sins to my Infinite God for all of infinity.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything But</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/anything-but/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/anything-but/</guid>
      <description>Sarah Leading Hagar to Abraham by Matthias Stom&amp;#8220;The parable, in Luke 18:9-14, was directed against those who thought they were righteous and looked down on everyone else. We need to place due emphasis on the phrase &amp;#8216;who thought they were righteous.&amp;#8217; People who preen themselves on their own righteousness go home unjustified even if they were baptized in a joint service with the pope and Billy Graham officiating. The self-righteous can trust in anything but Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits in the Person and Work of Christ</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/benefits-in-the-person-and-work-of-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/benefits-in-the-person-and-work-of-christ/</guid>
      <description>ht: Jared Oliphant        &amp;#8220;Owen and his Reformed contemporaries did not simply equate the covenant of grace with justification by faith alone. Soteric benefits—whether justification, adoption, or sanctification—are appropriated in the context of the covenant of grace, and all are necessary for salvation. Yet because these benefits are rooted first in the person and work of Christ, the covenant of grace retains its gracious character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faith Replacing Works?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/faith-replacing-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/faith-replacing-works/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;_Fides salvifica_ receives all of Scripture as good news from a gracious God. In a general sense, all is gospel. But the Scripture does contain what might be called the Gospel proper, the good news of Christ’s death, burial, and resurrection. This is why the Protestant scholastics also said that there was a _fides evangelica_ that specifically trusts in the revelation that God gives to us in the gospel of the death, burial, and resurrection of Jesus Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuel of Knowledge on the Fires of Worship</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/fuel-of-knowledge-on-the-fires-of-worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/fuel-of-knowledge-on-the-fires-of-worship/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;This book is a plea to embrace serious thinking as a means of loving God and people. It is a plea to reject either-or thinking when it comes to head and heart, thinking and feeling, reason and faith, theology and doxology, mental labor and the ministry of love. It is a plea to see thinking as a necessary, God-ordained means of knowing God. Thinking is one of the most important ways that we put the fuel of knowledge on the fires of worship and service to the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here’s My Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/heres-my-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/heres-my-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>In His righteous judgment, God has determined that the just penalty for sin is death and without the shedding of blood, there is no remission of sins. Now, sin has been committed by man and therefore only man can atone for that sin.
But here’s my dilemma: I can’t atone for my sin. I can’t.
I cannot satisfy God’s righteous requirement.
My disobedience condemns me before a Righteous God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Can A Denomination Come Back From Liberalism?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/how-can-a-denomination-come-back-from-liberalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/how-can-a-denomination-come-back-from-liberalism/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip; it is always wise to have a governing structure where the highest governing offices in the church and the highest positions of influence are open to lay people as well as ordained people. The denominations where only clergy have the highest of authority seem to be the ones that are never able to be brought back once they drift into liberalism because the ordinary lay people who have common sense and are reading their Bibles every day don’t have any way to regain control of a denomination that has gone astray if it has that kind of structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence: Genesis</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/influence-genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/influence-genesis/</guid>
      <description>Nine times out of ten, every other story not in Genesis can be traced back to Genesis. (I logically suspect that that other one time is simply because I am a novice scholar.)
Forgive me as I do this off the top of my noggin but if I am not mistaken, all Biblical doctrines originates in Genesis in a very direct way. 1{#return-note-1105-1.simple-footnote}
Doctrine of creation: Genesis 1 &amp;amp; 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: But Who Am I? 1 Chronicles 29:10-18</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/influences-but-who-am-i-1-chronicles-2910-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/influences-but-who-am-i-1-chronicles-2910-18/</guid>
      <description>This was the very first passage I memorized. I picked this passage because I heard this particular verse mentioned in a long list of other verses:
1 Chronicles 29:14 “But who am I, and what is my people, that we should be able thus to offer willingly? For all things come from you, and of your own have we given you.
When I looked up the verse and read it in context, I was blown away from David&amp;#8217;s commencement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: He Saved Us, Titus 3:3-7</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-he-saved-us-titus-33-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-he-saved-us-titus-33-7/</guid>
      <description>All of our sins are laid bare before us.
When we truly see who we really are, we see our shunning of God’s wisdom; ignoring of God’s word; our turning away from His lovely face; our insistence to the crap the world has offer; our addiction to the pains and sickness; and our desires fueled by the love for ourselves at the increase of hate and apathy towards one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: How Did I Get Here?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/how-did-i-get-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/how-did-i-get-here/</guid>
      <description>Answer: God.
Well, that was easy.
In all seriousness, I got a tweet from a friend of mine:
 Will you share with me some of the blogs/people you read? I love reading and being encouraged by deep thinkers.  Which, in turn, made me think: How did I get here? Why do I think the way that I do? Who has God used to shape my faith in Him, my knowledge of Him and my love of Him?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: I Know Nothing But Him</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/influences-i-know-nothing-but-him/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/influences-i-know-nothing-but-him/</guid>
      <description>I know one thing, that I know nothing.
 &amp;#8211; Socrates
If I have set the direction of my theology based on the thread of Hebrews 6:1-3, 1 Corinthians 3:21-23, and 1 Corinthians 2:12-13, then I would have to say this would be the basis for all of my reading, studying, writing, lecturing, preaching, and teaching:
1 Corinthians 2:2 For I decided to know nothing among you except Jesus Christ and him crucified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Indeed He Says! Romans 9:22-26</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/influences-indeed-he-says-romans-922-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/influences-indeed-he-says-romans-922-26/</guid>
      <description>Romans 9:22-26
What if God, desiring to show his wrath and to make known his power, has endured with much patience vessels of wrath prepared for destruction, in order to make known the riches of his glory for vessels of mercy, which he has prepared beforehand for glory—even us whom he has called, not from the Jews only but also from the Gentiles? As indeed he says in Hosea,
&amp;emsp;“Those who were not my people I will call ‘my people,’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Jeremiah</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-jeremiah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-jeremiah/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet Jeremiah by Michelangelo BuonarrotiIn and around April 2007, I was saved. In and around May 2007, it occurs to me that I should start reading the Bible. I prayed and I felt like I should start with Jeremiah.
Every since reading Jeremiah, there were four truths that did a number on my freshly renewed mind (oddly enough, Jeremiah 29:11 was not one of them):
 God appoints us to Him before we were born:  Jeremiah 1:4-8 Now the word of the Lord came to me, saying,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Leviticus</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-leviticus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-leviticus/</guid>
      <description>Leviticus is Christology 101.
This might be a strange statement. I know. Stay with me.
When I finally got around into reading Leviticus, I had just finished all the gospels with the crucifixion of our Lord Jesus Christ still being very fresh in my mind.
Then I was reading through Leviticus and as clear as any book as ever been, I knew the main point that God was driving into my soul:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Love Song – Psalm 119</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-love-song-psalm-119/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-love-song-psalm-119/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Psalm 119 is the love song to God for all time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/record_needle_body_203x152.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-964&#34; title=&#34;record_needle_body_203x152&#34; src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/record_needle_body_203x152.jpg?resize=203%2C152&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;203&#34; height=&#34;152&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It is the extended, smooth-out, quiet storm version. It’s the singer’s voice dropping to a bass-baritone. It is the passion towards the one the writer loves. It has the ultra-smooth whispers of sweet desires over the radio waves and the crackle of the vinyl in the extended beatdrop. This song is the mixtape track that says everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was made for one person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it is all about His righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The psalmist is not in love with the law. The love was never directed towards a bunch of rules that they could never perfectly do. If I fail to do them all correctly, I have fallen. If I break one rule, I have failed. If fail to do one rule, then I separated from my precious love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I realized that there were some laws that supersedes my material reality, I have already failed. If I never realized the laws, then surely I have gone against my conscience and &lt;em&gt;seared&lt;/em&gt; my conscience from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damned if I do and damned if I don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What hope do I have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can I have faith?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, but I have love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have love for the One who did it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the King who wrote the laws and perfectly followed them to the letter. And my lawgiving King doesn’t hold His law over my head. Instead, He showers me with His banner of love over my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My King has me. He has it all. He just needs me to look into His eyes, hold his hands, and trust Him when He says, “Everything’s gonna be alright.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width=&#34;25%&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Ruth</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-ruth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-ruth/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I was given the opportunity to lead a Bible Study. The very first book we studied through was the book of Ruth. Verse by verse. Chapter by chapter.
Given our group consisted of young adults, most of them were single, it was easy to quickly identify with, or want to be identified with, each of the key figures in this little story in the Bible.
Feeling like a stranger in a strange land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Sometime Around 33 A.D., This Was Prayed Over Me – John 17</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-sometime-around-33-a-d-this-was-prayed-over-me-john-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/influences-sometime-around-33-a-d-this-was-prayed-over-me-john-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/christ-in-gesthemane-01.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-190&#34; title=&#34;christ-in-gesthemane-01&#34; src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/christ-in-gesthemane-01.jpg?resize=300%2C238&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;238&#34; srcset=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/christ-in-gesthemane-01.jpg?resize=300%2C238 300w, https://i1.wp.com/theologic.us/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/christ-in-gesthemane-01.jpg?w=423 423w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; data-recalc-dims=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Romans 8:34 Who is to condemn? &lt;strong&gt;Christ Jesus is the one who died—more than that, who was raised—who is at the right hand of God, &lt;em&gt;who indeed is interceding for us&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr width=&#34;25%&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: The Thread of Logic</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/influences-the-thread-of-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/influences-the-thread-of-logic/</guid>
      <description>I believe, trust, understand, love, and think by this principle: my entire grasp, knowledge, relationship, salvation, and love to God, for God, by God, from God, and through God is according to these three Scriptures:
Hebrews 6:1-3 Therefore let us leave the elementary doctrine of Christ and go on to maturity, not laying again a foundation of repentance from dead works and of faith toward God, and of instruction about washings, the laying on of hands, the resurrection of the dead, and eternal judgment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences: Where Theology and Expectation Meet</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/influences-where-theology-and-expectation-meet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/influences-where-theology-and-expectation-meet/</guid>
      <description>Romans 15:17-21 In Christ Jesus, then, I have reason to be proud of my work for God. For I will not venture to speak of anything except what Christ has accomplished through me to bring the Gentiles to obedience—by word and deed, by the power of signs and wonders, by the power of the Spirit of God—so that from Jerusalem and all the way around to Illyricum I have fulfilled the ministry of the gospel of Christ; and thus I make it my ambition to preach the gospel, not where Christ has already been named, lest I build on someone else&amp;#8217;s foundation, but as it is written, “Those who have never been told of him will see, and those who have never heard will understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Our Britches Lined With Footnotes</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/keeping-our-britches-lined-with-footnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/keeping-our-britches-lined-with-footnotes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;I will assert that serious theology cannot expect to get anywhere until we knock off the urbane silliness that characterizes so much theological discussion today. The Scriptures say the fear of the Lord is the beginning of knowledge; some have taken this to mean that unbelief and autonomous rationality must be the beginning of knowledge. In light of this, the ache that some conservative scholars have to be taken seriously in the unbelieving academy is a pitiful thing indeed, and so I would like to take this opportunity to give the whole thing the universal raspberry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowing τελοσ or Bust!</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/knowing-%CF%84%CE%B5%CE%BB%CE%BF%CF%83-or-bust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/knowing-%CF%84%CE%B5%CE%BB%CE%BF%CF%83-or-bust/</guid>
      <description>Studying Philosophy, I am wrestling with the meaning and understanding of telos as in teleological arguments or teleology.
For several weeks, I keep running into the Gk. root _telos- _and for weeks, I had to keep looking it up on my iPhone to remind me what it means and more importantly, &amp;#8220;what the sentence is actually saying&amp;#8220;.
And the cement becomes bone-dry when I read this little quote:
&amp;#8220;Moses declared that the law was not too hard for Israel to keep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not By Logic Alone</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/not-by-logic-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/not-by-logic-alone/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The goal of bringing ourselves or others to a true and sin-conquering knowledge of God will never be reached by instrument of logic alone. Jesus sent Paul on an impossible mission. He said to Paul, &amp;#8216;I am sending you to open their eyes, so that they may turn from darkness to light and from the power of Satan to God, that they may receive forgiveness of sins&amp;#8217; (Acts 26:17-18). This is what happens when strongholds are destroyed, and arguments against the truth of God are overcome and thoughts are taken captive for Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Main Purpose of the Mind</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/the-main-purpose-of-the-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/the-main-purpose-of-the-mind/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The apex of glorifying God is enjoying him with the heart. But this is an empty emotionalism where that joy is not awakened and sustained by true views of God for who he really is. That is mainly what the mind is for.&amp;#8221;
John Piper. Think: The Life of the Mind and the Love of God. Crossway, 2010. 37.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Opposite of Barren Intellectualism is not Anti-Intellectualism</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/the-opposite-of-barren-intellectualism-is-not-anti-intellectualism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/the-opposite-of-barren-intellectualism-is-not-anti-intellectualism/</guid>
      <description>Ephesians 3:1-6 For this reason I, Paul, a prisoner for Christ Jesus on behalf of you Gentiles—assuming that you have heard of the stewardship of God&amp;#8217;s grace that was given to me for you, how the mystery was made known to me by revelation, as I have written briefly. When you read this, you can perceive my insight into the mystery of Christ, which was not made known to the sons of men in other generations as it has now been revealed to his holy apostles and prophets by the Spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking versus Postmodern Jell-O Juggling</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/thinking-versus-postmodern-jell-o-juggling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/thinking-versus-postmodern-jell-o-juggling/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Yes, I have concerns. For example, I hope this book will help rescue the victims of evangelical pragmatism, Pentecostal shortcuts, pietistic anti-intellectualism, pluralistic conviction aversion, academic gamesmanship, therapeutic Bible evasion, journalistic bite-sizing, musical mesmerizing, YouTube craving, and postmodern Jell-O juggling. In other words, I believe thinking is good for the church in every way.&amp;#8221;
John Piper. Think: The Life of the Mind and the Love of God. Crossway, 2010. 17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts and Affections Cause Each Other</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/thoughts-and-affections-cause-each-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/thoughts-and-affections-cause-each-other/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Indeed, thoughts and affections are _sibi mutuo causae_—the mutual causes of each other: &amp;#8216;Whilst I mused, the fire burned&amp;#8216; (Psalm 39:3); so that thoughts are the bellows that kindle and inflame affections; and then if they are inflamed, they cause thoughts to boil; therefore men newly converted to God, having new and strong affections, can with more pleasure think of God than any.&amp;#8221;&amp;#8221;
Thomas Goodwin, as quoted in, Think: The Life of the Mind and the Love of God by John Piper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Have No Interest in Truth Effectively Ends the Conversation</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/no-interest-in-truth-versus-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/no-interest-in-truth-versus-conversation/</guid>
      <description>Matthew 21:23-27 And when he entered the temple, the chief priests and the elders of the people came up to him as he was teaching, and said, “By what authority are you doing these things, and who gave you this authority?” Jesus answered them, “I also will ask you one question, and if you tell me the answer, then I also will tell you by what authority I do these things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth to Serve</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/truth-to-serve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/truth-to-serve/</guid>
      <description>Relativism [&amp;#8230;] kidnaps the happy handmaiden of truth and makes her serve the pride and pleasure of pragmatists. Relativists don&amp;#8217;t pursue truth. They make the denial of truth serve them.
 John Piper. Think: The Life of the Mind and the Love of God. Crossway, 2010. 105.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>