<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Preaching on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/preaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Preaching on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 16:41:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/categories/preaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raising Preachers of the Gospel</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/raising-preachers-of-the-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 16:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/raising-preachers-of-the-gospel/</guid>
      <description>When I met these two girls about four years ago, I knew two things:
 They are thieves. They love to take your heart and never give it back. They love the Bible.  If you know me, I have many kids. But none of my kids had that spark, that interest&amp;#8230; that proclivity that these two girls had in the word of God.
From the moment, I met them I knew that I would give them every ounce of theological and doctrinal training, every note, every book, every podcast, every video that I had not just simply to raise preachers and pastors—although that is a small part of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pastor’s Promise</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/a-pastors-promise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/a-pastors-promise/</guid>
      <description>Having been made an overseer by the Lord Jesus Christ,
affirmed as such by His Church,
and enabled solely by His grace,
I commit to live in a manner worthy of His calling,
loving Him with all my heart, soul and mind,
always on guard for myself that I maintain a testimony that is above reproach;
I commit to preach His Word,
standing ready in season and out of season,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here’s My Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/heres-my-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/heres-my-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>In His righteous judgment, God has determined that the just penalty for sin is death and without the shedding of blood, there is no remission of sins. Now, sin has been committed by man and therefore only man can atone for that sin.
But here’s my dilemma: I can’t atone for my sin. I can’t.
I cannot satisfy God’s righteous requirement.
My disobedience condemns me before a Righteous God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Desires of the New Heart Given to Me By God</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/the-desires-of-the-new-heart-given-to-me-by-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/the-desires-of-the-new-heart-given-to-me-by-god/</guid>
      <description>**2 Timothy 3:14-4:5 But as for you, continue in what you have learned and have firmly believed, knowing from whom you learned it and how from childhood you have been acquainted with the sacred writings, which are able to make you wise for salvation through faith in Christ Jesus. All Scripture is breathed out by God and profitable for teaching, for reproof, for correction, and for training in righteousness, that the man of God may be complete, equipped for every good work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ridiculous, Foolish Power of Christ Crucified</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/ridiculous-foolish-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/ridiculous-foolish-power/</guid>
      <description>1 Corinthians 1:20-24 Where is the one who is wise? Where is the scribe? Where is the debater of this age? Has not God made foolish the wisdom of the world? For since, in the wisdom of God, the world did not know God through wisdom, it pleased God through the folly of what we preach to save those who believe. For Jews demand signs and Greeks seek wisdom, but we preach Christ crucified, a stumbling block to Jews and folly to Gentiles, but to those who are called, both Jews and Greeks, Christ the power of God and the wisdom of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Supremacy of God in Preaching by John Piper, A Thought</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/books/review-the-supremacy-of-god-in-preaching-by-john-piper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/books/review-the-supremacy-of-god-in-preaching-by-john-piper/</guid>
      <description>For I decided to know nothing among you except Jesus Christ and him crucified. And I was with you in weakness and in fear and much trembling, and my speech and my message were not in plausible words of wisdom, but in demonstration of the Spirit and of power, so that your faith might not rest in the wisdom of men but in the power of God. 1 Corinthians 2:2-5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Timeliness of it All</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-timeliness-of-it-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/the-timeliness-of-it-all/</guid>
      <description>We desperately need a new generation of expositors, men cut from the same bolt of cloth as Calvin. Pastors marked by compassion, humility, and kindness must once again preach the Word. In short, we need Calvins again to stand in pulpits and boldly proclaim the Word of God.
 &amp;#8211; Steven Lawson, What’s the Answer to the Modern Day Church?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Should I Live?</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/why-should-i-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/why-should-i-live/</guid>
      <description>I have lived my life boiled down to one simple quote: Nicolaus Zinzendorf&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;Preach the gospel, die, and be forgotten&amp;#8217; as to shine light on the meaning of 1 Corinthians 2:2 in my life. All of my studies and all of my toiling and to a much larger, unavoidable influence, the way that I love and live my life, are all wrapped in up that one little quote. It is a quote that I have mediated much on and it is a now philosophy I cannot let go.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>