<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Think: The Life of the Mind and the Love of God on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/think-the-life-of-the-mind-and-the-love-of-god/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Think: The Life of the Mind and the Love of God on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/think-the-life-of-the-mind-and-the-love-of-god/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuel of Knowledge on the Fires of Worship</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/fuel-of-knowledge-on-the-fires-of-worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/fuel-of-knowledge-on-the-fires-of-worship/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;This book is a plea to embrace serious thinking as a means of loving God and people. It is a plea to reject either-or thinking when it comes to head and heart, thinking and feeling, reason and faith, theology and doxology, mental labor and the ministry of love. It is a plea to see thinking as a necessary, God-ordained means of knowing God. Thinking is one of the most important ways that we put the fuel of knowledge on the fires of worship and service to the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not By Logic Alone</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/not-by-logic-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/not-by-logic-alone/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The goal of bringing ourselves or others to a true and sin-conquering knowledge of God will never be reached by instrument of logic alone. Jesus sent Paul on an impossible mission. He said to Paul, &amp;#8216;I am sending you to open their eyes, so that they may turn from darkness to light and from the power of Satan to God, that they may receive forgiveness of sins&amp;#8217; (Acts 26:17-18). This is what happens when strongholds are destroyed, and arguments against the truth of God are overcome and thoughts are taken captive for Christ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Main Purpose of the Mind</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/the-main-purpose-of-the-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/the-main-purpose-of-the-mind/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The apex of glorifying God is enjoying him with the heart. But this is an empty emotionalism where that joy is not awakened and sustained by true views of God for who he really is. That is mainly what the mind is for.&amp;#8221;
John Piper. Think: The Life of the Mind and the Love of God. Crossway, 2010. 37.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Opposite of Barren Intellectualism is not Anti-Intellectualism</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/the-opposite-of-barren-intellectualism-is-not-anti-intellectualism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/the-opposite-of-barren-intellectualism-is-not-anti-intellectualism/</guid>
      <description>Ephesians 3:1-6 For this reason I, Paul, a prisoner for Christ Jesus on behalf of you Gentiles—assuming that you have heard of the stewardship of God&amp;#8217;s grace that was given to me for you, how the mystery was made known to me by revelation, as I have written briefly. When you read this, you can perceive my insight into the mystery of Christ, which was not made known to the sons of men in other generations as it has now been revealed to his holy apostles and prophets by the Spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ridiculous, Foolish Power of Christ Crucified</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/ridiculous-foolish-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/ridiculous-foolish-power/</guid>
      <description>1 Corinthians 1:20-24 Where is the one who is wise? Where is the scribe? Where is the debater of this age? Has not God made foolish the wisdom of the world? For since, in the wisdom of God, the world did not know God through wisdom, it pleased God through the folly of what we preach to save those who believe. For Jews demand signs and Greeks seek wisdom, but we preach Christ crucified, a stumbling block to Jews and folly to Gentiles, but to those who are called, both Jews and Greeks, Christ the power of God and the wisdom of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking versus Postmodern Jell-O Juggling</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/thinking-versus-postmodern-jell-o-juggling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/thinking-versus-postmodern-jell-o-juggling/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Yes, I have concerns. For example, I hope this book will help rescue the victims of evangelical pragmatism, Pentecostal shortcuts, pietistic anti-intellectualism, pluralistic conviction aversion, academic gamesmanship, therapeutic Bible evasion, journalistic bite-sizing, musical mesmerizing, YouTube craving, and postmodern Jell-O juggling. In other words, I believe thinking is good for the church in every way.&amp;#8221;
John Piper. Think: The Life of the Mind and the Love of God. Crossway, 2010. 17.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts and Affections Cause Each Other</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/thoughts-and-affections-cause-each-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/thoughts-and-affections-cause-each-other/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Indeed, thoughts and affections are _sibi mutuo causae_—the mutual causes of each other: &amp;#8216;Whilst I mused, the fire burned&amp;#8216; (Psalm 39:3); so that thoughts are the bellows that kindle and inflame affections; and then if they are inflamed, they cause thoughts to boil; therefore men newly converted to God, having new and strong affections, can with more pleasure think of God than any.&amp;#8221;&amp;#8221;
Thomas Goodwin, as quoted in, Think: The Life of the Mind and the Love of God by John Piper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Have No Interest in Truth Effectively Ends the Conversation</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/no-interest-in-truth-versus-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/no-interest-in-truth-versus-conversation/</guid>
      <description>Matthew 21:23-27 And when he entered the temple, the chief priests and the elders of the people came up to him as he was teaching, and said, “By what authority are you doing these things, and who gave you this authority?” Jesus answered them, “I also will ask you one question, and if you tell me the answer, then I also will tell you by what authority I do these things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth to Serve</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/truth-to-serve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/truth-to-serve/</guid>
      <description>Relativism [&amp;#8230;] kidnaps the happy handmaiden of truth and makes her serve the pride and pleasure of pragmatists. Relativists don&amp;#8217;t pursue truth. They make the denial of truth serve them.
 John Piper. Think: The Life of the Mind and the Love of God. Crossway, 2010. 105.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>