<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gospel on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/gospel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gospel on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 23:00:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/gospel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>His Banner Over Me Is Love</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/his-banner-over-me-is-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 23:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/family-devotions/his-banner-over-me-is-love/</guid>
      <description>Series: Once a month, I get to teach the Elementary kids during our main Worship Gatherings. My incredible Children&amp;#8217;s Pastor, Kim, does the amazing work of feeding me that weekend&amp;#8217;s lesson, much like a lectionary. There will be a power verse, the lesson (or the reading) and then the accompanied Bible passage. Quite often, God will linked everything together to His Son and to His gospel which I am to believe the Scriptures (1 Corinthians 2:12) is through the power of the Holy Spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raising Preachers of the Gospel</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/raising-preachers-of-the-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 16:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/preaching/raising-preachers-of-the-gospel/</guid>
      <description>When I met these two girls about four years ago, I knew two things:
 They are thieves. They love to take your heart and never give it back. They love the Bible.  If you know me, I have many kids. But none of my kids had that spark, that interest&amp;#8230; that proclivity that these two girls had in the word of God.
From the moment, I met them I knew that I would give them every ounce of theological and doctrinal training, every note, every book, every podcast, every video that I had not just simply to raise preachers and pastors—although that is a small part of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All of the Infinite</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/all-of-the-infinite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/theology/all-of-the-infinite/</guid>
      <description> My hope is infinite because of this: The Infinite God in His infinite glory with His infinite love sent His Infinite Son by His infinite power of His Infinite Spirit across the infinite chasm to save my infinite soul from my infinite sins to my Infinite God for all of infinity.
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>