<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psalms on Theologicus</title>
    <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/psalms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psalms on Theologicus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 12:00:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/tags/psalms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:5c My Cup Overflows</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-235c-my-cup-overflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 12:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-235c-my-cup-overflows/</guid>
      <description>My Lord, I am reminded of all of your sweet blessings. You are my inheritance. You are my portion. You are my lot. Because you are my Christ, the Son of God, in whom is my All-of-all. My God, you have called me into your family and I share my inheritance. But just as you drank from the cup, I gladly and with great joy drink from the cup. I am yours and your are my Beloved forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:5b The Gift of Your Spirit</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/3821/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 12:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/3821/</guid>
      <description>My God, Because of everything your Son has done for me, I now walk in the power of Your Spiirt. He leads me. He guides me. He teaches me. He reminds me of what You have said. He reminds me of my righteousness. He reminds me that I am your son. More so than that, He is the seal upon my heart and the promise of your strength. And because He dwells in me, I fear no death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:5a Circumstances Abound</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-235a-circumstances-abound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 12:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-235a-circumstances-abound/</guid>
      <description>My God, I have been crushed and discarded a hundred times. But, I have warred against you thousand more. Yet, you sent your Son to live and die for me. And now I live for you. I will never understand why you saved me, but I only know that because I have sin much I have been forgiven much. Now I know you let me sit at your table, when I should been condemned for treason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:4d The Comfort of Your Power</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-234d-the-comfort-of-your-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-234d-the-comfort-of-your-power/</guid>
      <description>My God, It is the might and strength of your protection on my life and heart that gives me peace. That no other thing in all of creation can ever separate me from you in the name of your Son, Christ Jesus my Lord. Nothing ever compares to you. You alone are powerful and worthy. Thank you for protecting me. Thank you for loving me. Thank you for calling me your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:4c You Are With Me</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-234c-you-are-with-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 12:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-234c-you-are-with-me/</guid>
      <description>My Lord and my God, Even when I was dead, you called my name. Even when I was lost, you found me. Even when I was blind, you touched my eyes and opened them to see. Even when I was deaf, you opened them to hear. Even when I was hard-hearted, you took my heart of stone and gave me your tender heart. Even when I couldn’t know you, you gave me Your Spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:4b Fear No Evil</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-234b-fear-no-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 12:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/quotes/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-234b-fear-no-evil/</guid>
      <description>My God, I fear no evil. For your precious Son has already conquered sin, Satan, demons, hell, and death. I have no enemies on earth. Those are not my real enemies. Rulers, princes, and principalities: they crouch for my soul. They wait to devour my heart. They do not hesitate to fire a million arrows of fire just to consume my being. But you, O Lord, are my strength, my armour, my fortress and strong tower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:4a Through the Valley of the Shadow of Death</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-0234a-through-the-valley-of-the-shadow-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-0234a-through-the-valley-of-the-shadow-of-death/</guid>
      <description>My Great God,
How many times have you rescued me from not only eternal death but certain death and doom?
How many times have I sinned that did and did not lead to my death?
The answer is countless. The truth is infinite.
But yet, you are my great God and Savior! I have fallen into the abyssmal pit too many times to count. But because of your grace upon grace, you were deeper still!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:3b He leads me in paths of righteousness for his name’s sake</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-0233b-he-leads-me-in-paths-of-righteousness-for-his-names-sake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-0233b-he-leads-me-in-paths-of-righteousness-for-his-names-sake/</guid>
      <description>My Precious God, I am often reminded of my sinful ways of the past. As the vines grew up from my heart and slowly and surely tightened around my neck as I continuously die without thought But you, my God, broke the spell of the sin over my life. But time after time, I see those weeds grow. I feel the cancer thriving in my heart. I sense the sin that crouches for me and waits to pierce my soul with his poison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:3a He Restores My Soul</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-23_3a-he-restores-my-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-23_3a-he-restores-my-soul/</guid>
      <description>My Lord, I perish without you. I cannot live without you. Apart from you., the hole in my inner being remained infinitely empty. Without you, I strived and pushed and pulled and made idols and did whatever I need to do in order to fill my soul. But all of it comes up empty. But you, O Lord, not only fills my heart to the brim but gives my soul brand new life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:2b He Leads Me Beside Still Waters</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-232b-he-leads-me-beside-still-waters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 12:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-232b-he-leads-me-beside-still-waters/</guid>
      <description>My Lord, You are the fountain of true life. I am dead without you. It is not that I can find this water on my own. For I am lost. and, my soul is dried-up and dead. I have no wisdom, strength, or spirit to find you. But you, O Lord, rescued me. You have brought me into your life and in your life alone, I am fully alive. My soul is no longer dried in sin but restored, covered, and filled with your never-ending grace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:2a He makes me lie down in green pastures</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-232a-he-makes-me-lie-down-in-green-pastures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 12:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-232a-he-makes-me-lie-down-in-green-pastures/</guid>
      <description>My Lord, You are the Prince of Peace. Where you are, there I find satisfaction of my wearied soul and find perfect peace where I can truly rest. Apart from you, I die and I perish. Away from you, I am only tormented by confusion and despair. Without you, there is nothing but destructions by my own hands and by everything around me. But you, O Lord, call me to enter through you and abide in you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:1b I Shall Not Want</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-231b-i-shall-not-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 12:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-231b-i-shall-not-want/</guid>
      <description>My Lord Above, I thank you for your perfect provision. You are my Good Father in heaven and because I am your child, you have always provided for me. When I was younger, I wanted many things but you did not provide them. But looking back, those things I wanted would have harmed me or cause me to turn away from you. But what you have always done is gave something even better, which turned out to be actually good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 23:1a The Lord Is My Shepherd</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/psalm-231a-the-lord-is-my-shepherd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 12:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/psalm-231a-the-lord-is-my-shepherd/</guid>
      <description>You are my Good Shepherd. You fled the ninety-nine in order to come rescue me, when I could not possibly rescue myself. You saved me from certain damnation, you’ve rescued me from the slaughter. You’ve taken all of my sin, and you let the wrath of Father fall upon your heart You bled out for me, so that I might live forever. Lord, keep me in your care, I pray that you keep good shepherds to care and feed me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 22:25-31</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2225-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 12:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2225-31/</guid>
      <description>My Worthy Lord,
Let my words and my songs be a sweetness to your ears.
For I know that you sit on the throne of our praises because you are the God who alone saves.
I know that not only are you willing and able to save, you and you alone are the only one who is mighty to save.
So I praise you with all of my breath and strength and life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 22:22-24</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2222-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2222-24/</guid>
      <description>My God in Heaven,
There is none like you!
You are God who sits high above all of my sins, my hardness, my wickedness, my trespasses and my calamity. You are exalted far above all of my gods.
But in your steadfast love, abounding grace, and tender mercies, you saved me! You sent your son, Jesus Christ, to come live and die for me. More than that, your Son rose from the grave and conquered all of the sins, hell, Satan, demons, and death once and for all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 22:19-21</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2219-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 12:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2219-21/</guid>
      <description>Almighty God,
Who are you, my Lord, whose glory fills the entire earth? Whether I am in the heavens or make my bed in hell, you are there with me. If I ascend the mountain of your glory or wander in the desert of the wilderness, you are face to face and closer than a whisper.
My God, you are never far! You are with me! Always. While I might feel desperate or despair sadness or anger or happiness, you are with me and within me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 22:12-18</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2212-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2212-18/</guid>
      <description>Dear God,
My enemies are on all sides and their attacks are relentless, you are my protector.
When lions clamp down on my guts, you are the teeth-breaker and my healer.
When I am buried, you call me out of the ground.
When I was dead in my sins, you lived, died, and rose alive so that I might live.
You have never left me.
You have always been with me even when I did not know nor loved you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 22:6-11</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-22-6-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 12:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-22-6-11/</guid>
      <description>My Lord,
Who am I that I have been rejected a million times and despised a million times more?
You say, “Speak of my love” and it falls on deaf ears. You say, “Speak of my power” and it means little to the strong. You say, “Speak of my glory” and their eyes remain blind.
However, you saved me. You made me with your hands. You are the one who started my heartbeat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 22: 1-5</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-22-1-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 12:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-22-1-5/</guid>
      <description>God!
Where are you?
I am in trouble!
Sin and wickedness have surrounded me. Everything goes dark and cold. Satan and his minions look upon my flesh with lust and hunger.
Temptations are too much. I cannot do battle. My muscles are weak, small, and frail.
I cry and scream: HELP ME, O GOD!
But you are my powerful Champion. You are the people’s Savior. You are invincible. You are forever strong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 21</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-21/</guid>
      <description>My Lord and My God,
My focus is far from you, the one who sets up Kings and puts them down.
I have been distracted by the choosing of kings rather to place my focus on the King of kings.
It is in you, O Lord, where my strength resides
my salvation is present
my heart&amp;#8217;s desire
my soul&amp;#8217;s fulfillment.
Be my provision. Be my grace. Be my mercy.
Be my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 1</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-1/</guid>
      <description>O Lord,  Like a child, I have fallen and all of my strength has left me.
As my precious Father, put me back up on my feet and hold my hands so I can learn to run to you.
Give me your strength and might.
Give me your word and your promises.
Oh, how you give to me. You give me your love and you see to it that I make it back to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 10</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-10/</guid>
      <description>O Lord,  My sin wakes me up from my slumber.
At my weakest, my iniquities flood my mind. My mind is not sharp. My soul is asleep. In the pitch blackness of the night, I cannot see.
Sin is like a ravenous, rabid dog who sits upon my chest, waiting to devour me. I can smell it’s breath. I can taste the poison stench. My eardrums break from the deafening bark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 11</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-11/</guid>
      <description>Dear God,  I have seen the volley of artillery rain down all around me and You, O Lord, my precious shield, have absorbed their attacks.
Yet, the enemy’s sharpshooters have taken careful aim at my heart. Their fiery bullets have pierced my chest. Their lies have penetrated my mind. Their blasphemous words have laid weight upon my soul.
It hurts me so.
But You, O God, are endlessly faithful:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 12</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-12/</guid>
      <description>My Lord,  My legacy has already passed through my lips. I have nothing but strongest bitterness and the most potent venom to come out of my mouth.
I have lied. I have manipulated. I have cheated.
With my snake tongue, I have tried to get others to do my bidding, believing the lie that I am the one that needs to control them in order for my soul to be at peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 13</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-13/</guid>
      <description>O Lord,  You have not forgotten me.
You have not hidden your lovely face from me.
Your comfort and wisdom warm my soul.
Your joy and hope fill my heart all the day long.
You are mindful of me and when I call out your name, you answer me. You have answered me by saving me. You saved me by giving Yourself to me.
One day, I might stare down Death, but when I do, I will only see a crownless king with a broken scepter who has been stripped of power where there is little left to wield.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 14</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-14/</guid>
      <description>O Lord,  I would say to you, “I have not forgotten you.” But what about those times I succumb to the wickedness of my heart, to the depravity of the world, or to the lies of Satan? What about those times?
What about those times when I am devoid of strength and I do not turn to the one who has my infinite strength?
What about those times when I rely on my rational thought process, the very good gift that you have given me, instead being depended and led by that very Giver, the Spirit of God, by which I am declared to be your beloved son?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 15</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-15/</guid>
      <description>O Lord,  How could I possibly worship you? I am not worthy to commune with you and be with you. I sin even now. My heart strays. My soul wanders.
Yet, you, O God, are not far from me. When I am in the wilderness, you are closer than a whisper. When I have fallen, you set me back up on solid ground and you rejoice over me with singing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 16</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-16/</guid>
      <description>My Lord,  I have gone everywhere. I have not found any good apart from you.
When I turn away from you or try to find not You, my sorrow and grief run deep. It crushes my hearts and buries my soul.
When I try to give life to my idols, they give nothing back because there are no other gods. And I die.
When will I realize that you alone are my All-in-all?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 17</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-17/</guid>
      <description>O Father,  You are God of the Universe. Holy, righteous, just. High above my idols. High above my sins. High above my faults. High above the twisted wickedness of my own heart. In no way could I have ever approach you.
But you, O Lord, abundant in mercy and rich in grace, made the way. You sent your Son to come get me. Now I am yours.
I am your son.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 18, Pt 1</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>My Lord,  You are my All-in-all.
Beyond my Provider, it is by your very thought that you hold me together. By your will, I am pointed in your direction. By your great Spirit, I have strength.
You give unlimited might for this very weak man.
You put an immovable foundation beneath my weary feet.
You are my home where I can peacefully lay to rest.
You are my rescuer and it is in your arms, I know I am coming home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 18, Pt. 2</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>[][1]Red Tulips in the Snow by Lenore Ludlow My Lord,  My hands are not clean. My hands are washed in my own sin. They stink of feces and dung. If you judge me according to what I have done, then surely I am damned!
What hope do I have in myself and the works that I have done? I have nothing to give you, God.
But you knew. You knew and you came to be born as a man like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 18, Pt. 3</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-3/</guid>
      <description>You are my Way,
I am a man with little mercy. My life is filled with shame. My heart is ridden with cancerous sin. My will longs for the wide path well-traveled.
I cannot think I am better than a prideful man because I am that prideful man.
But you, O my Abba, have cleared one singular particular definite path to you and that is through your precious Son, my Christ my Savior and King.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 18, Pt. 4</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-4/</guid>
      <description>Who is like you, my Lord?
Who is like my God?
The one who has saved me and never abandoned me. The one who is my shield when fiery arrows have scorched the skies. The one who has called me righteous and equips me according to his own righteousness?
The one who has given me the speed to run to him in times of trouble? The one who has set me upon the mountaintop to see his awesome glory?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 18, Pt. 5</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-18-pt-5/</guid>
      <description>I was once so far from you. I was once lost. I was once your sworn enemy. Instead of casting me out, you sought me out. Instead of leaving me lost, you found me. Instead of leaving me to die, you found me and gave me life. Instead being at war with me, you call me friend.
You are my only hope. You are my life. You are my salvation. You alone hold the words of eternal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 19</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-19/</guid>
      <description>My God,
I was deaf. I was mute. I was hungry. I was thirsty. I was blind. I was ignorant. I was violent. I cursed your name. I was a dumb brute. I was barbaric.
Yet, you transported from the spiritual to the material. You cut across space and time. You personally opened my eyes, gave words for my throat, opened my eyes, filled my heart, and gave me understanding so that I may know you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 2</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-2/</guid>
      <description>My Lord,
I am set apart, this is true. But set apart by you to you.
I reach out to the world, plead to the world, and with the Spirit, invite the world to come into Your loving embrace.
Few do. Many do not.
How can I respond?
You are my Lord above. You are my King on high. All things, both spiritual and material, are yours. All truth and all philosophies are under your sovereign hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 20</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-20/</guid>
      <description>Lord, If I cry out for you, will you answer me? If you alone made the provisions and the sacrifices, will you save me? Even if I don’t understand you, will you reach for me? I need you, Lord. I don’t even have the wisdom to reach my hands up to you. I want you, God, and my heart is still filled with sin and wickedness. I have you, my Lord and my God, because I have your Spirit within me all because of what Your Son has done for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 3</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-3/</guid>
      <description>My God,  In my finite perception, my circumstances would seem to say I am in despair. I feel that. I feel that onslaught. I feel that pressure.
Many would say, ”Ah, your God has failed. Your God is not good. Your God does not deliver. Your God does not save.”
They would be wrong on all accounts.
When I turn away from all of my oppressors and turn towards you, I see the loveliness of your face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 4</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-4/</guid>
      <description>Dear God,  Help!
You have helped me in the past and this time I still need you.
I have dismissed all the lies around me.
I still need you.
I still need your love.
I still need your mercy.
I still need your grace.
Give me your hand.
I need to feel your embrace.
I need to feel your warmth.
I know you are always with me.
Right now, I will lay in peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 5</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-5/</guid>
      <description>My King and my God,  My heart grieves. My soul groans. I am in need of your Spirit.
My own pride has kept me far from you. My own arrogance has caused you to look away. Yet, I am in need of your holiness—the very thing that keeps me far is the very thing that keeps me close.
Clean my lips.
Give me your heart.
Remove this poison from my throat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 6</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-6/</guid>
      <description>My Holy Lord Above All,  My deeds have warranted not your affections but your attentions—attention to correct my path. However , it is not simply that, it is more serious, more deadly than that.
I continuously want death. I continuously want counterfeit. I continuously want less.
You, my Father, don’t want that for me.
You want life for me. You want truth for me. You want the most for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 7</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-7/</guid>
      <description>O Lord my God,  It might feel like the world is against me. I might feel like I am a being persecuted. But the real battle is not the world versus me but rather, my own sin and my own iniquities versus the spirit inside of me.
Dear God, my very best works and all of my good deeds before you are nothing more than used menstrual rags and bags of crap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 8</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-8/</guid>
      <description>My Lord, Our Lord,  Your name is known throughout all the earth.
Your fame knows no bounds.
Your glory will not be given to another.
Your love is simply unmatched.
And who you are and what you do is not determined and defined by the world around me. You are defined by your thoughts, your mind, your heart, and upon your revelation alone. I ask not for you to reveal more than what you have already reveal for my mind and soul and heart can barely comprehend your fullness now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Sings My Soul: Psalm 9</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/doxology/now-sings-my-soul-psalm-9/</guid>
      <description>Dear Lord,
I will not and cannot list what I think you have not done for me. That is preposterous! What you have done for me, in me, and through me is too great to even list. But I thank you so much. I thank you for you are absolutely good, absolutely merciful, absolutely gracious, and absolutely love. These I know of you and know you well.
God, you are high and exalted far above all creation, including any little thing I might create with my mind and my hands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 51: Confession and Repentance</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/psalm-51-confession-and-repentance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/prayer/psalm-51-confession-and-repentance/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 51  Have mercy on me, O God, according to your steadfast love; according to your abundant mercy blot out my transgressions. Wash me thoroughly from my iniquity, and cleanse me from my sin! For I know my transgressions, and my sin is ever before me. Against you, you only, have I sinned and done what is evil in your sight, so that you may be justified in your words and blameless in your judgment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalms: I Need You To Tell Me</title>
      <link>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/i-need-you-to-tell-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://festive-hopper-1abe84.netlify.com/scriptures/i-need-you-to-tell-me/</guid>
      <description>O Lord, please say to me, &#34;I am your salvation!&#34; And save me. Psalm 35:1-28</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>